This course section will build
up on the previous course section.
Now, in that previous section,
we learned a lot about building real React Native apps,
how we can build nice layouts and styles
and combine multiple components, custom components
and built-in components to build real mobile apps
with React Native.
In this course section, we're going to learn
how we can make our mobile apps
and our mobile user interfaces more adaptive and responsive,
how we can build apps that adapt to different platforms
and different device sizes
and how we can, for example, write platform-specific code
which means that we generally have one code based
for both iOS and Android, of course,
but that in some cases we can differentiate
between those platforms and execute slightly different code
based on which platform we're running.
In addition, we're going to learn how we can adjust
to different device sizes
and for example, update our styling
or our layout based on the available width and height.
And we're going to learn how we can also React
to the screen orientation chosen by the user.
In general, the idea behind this course section is,
to teach you a broad variety of tools
that you have to adjust your interface as needed
and to teach you how you can build adaptive components
which live in one and the same code base
and still can adapt to different environments.
Now, for this course section,
I wanna build up on the app we built
in the previous course section
and therefore you find the code of that finished app
which we built in the previous section attached
to this lecture so that we can all start
with the same code base.
Now, here is the app running on iOS and Android.
And I would say the look and the layout is quite good.
There isn't anything obvious that I would want to change.
But, of course, not all our users are going to use one
of the latest iPhones or Android devices,
instead they might be using older or smaller devices.
And our app typically should be able to adjust to that.
And we wanna adjust our look and feel.
For example, here I also started an Android emulator
based on the Nexus 5 image.
And I'll close the more recent pixel three device emulator.
Now this is a fine Android device
but as you can clearly tell, it is a bit smaller.
If I resize this, it just gets bigger here on the screen,
but if we talk about available pixels, it is smaller.
It has less space available.
And if that would be a real device,
the screen would be smaller.
We can tell that everything is smaller
because everything is bigger here on the UI.
And the starting screen still looks all right,
but if we dive into the game, we notice some differences.
For example, the title is right at the top here.
It's really at the edge of this screen
because this device is smaller.
Now, if we play this game here until it's over,
then we see that also on this game over screen.
Yeah, it fits on one screen
but the title is really already a little bit below
the status bar and everything probably
is a little bit too big for this small of a device.
So therefore we might wanna adjust some
of our style settings, some of our layout styles,
such that the app looks a bit better on smaller devices.
And that's what we're going to start with in this section.