So how can we make everything a bit smaller?
Let's maybe start with this game screen.
This game screen is okay
but some things are a little bit too big.
For example, besides the position of that title, which,
in my opinion, is a little bit too far at the top,
we might wanna decrease the width of this a little bit.
And if we have a look at our game screen, JS file,
there, we have various styles.
But of course, for this title
we don't have any specific styles
because data is a custom component stored
in the components UI folder.
And if we go there, we see that in the end
we have no real settings regarding the width
that should be taken up by this title.
Instead, we basically take all the width we can get
and the only spacing around it, this title, therefore
is margin or padding applied to this title
or to the container holding this title.
And that might be fine,
but what we could do here, is we could give this a max width
of let's say, 80%.
And that then should be a string,
so we should wrap it between quotes.
If we do this, then this title gets a bit smaller.
It's also not centered anymore because the parent container
which uses Flexbox, because all views use Flexbox
in React Native doesn't center, its child items.
So we would have to go to the game screen,
and then in there go to this view, this screen view
and make sure that all the children in there are centered
by adding align items center here like this.
And now that is all centered again.
Now it is up to you whether you like this or not.
But what I wanna show you and emphasize is
that you can use relative units like this,
and we have used them before, to control widths and heights
and that you can not just set the width and height itself
but that you can also set max width or min width
besides the regular width to create more responsive sizes.
Because when you set the width, then it's always that width.
It's now always 80%.
With max width, it's up to 80%,
but it could be less if less space is needed.
We could, for example, also set a width of,
let's say, 300 pixels, which would be the default,
but we could then also at max width 80% to make sure
that 300 pixels is taken, unless that would be more than 80%
of the parent container, in which case the 80%
become active.
So with this on bigger screens
we can take a little bit more space, as you can tell by
the available space to the left and the right of
the text.
There is less space available here on the smaller screen.
On the bigger screen, this gap is wider.
But we only take the 300 pixels, which we seem to take here,
if there is enough space.
Here on the smaller screen, 300 pixels
would be more than 80% of the available width,
and therefor the 80% are taken instead since
that is our max width,
and therefor the upper boundary of the width
of this container.
And what's really important to note is
that percentage settings like this always refer to
the parent container that holds an element.
So, if I say at the title to a max width of 80%, those 80%
refer to the parent container that holds the title.
So, in this case to this view, because of this title,
this view is the parent container.
So, it's the width of this view of which 80% are taken by
the title because of this setting.
So, percentage units and min and max width combined
with the regular width can be very helpful.
And of course, it's not just about the width.
You also have min at max height, in case you have
similar scenarios where you want to set a
minimum or maximum height.
So, these extra style properties are properties
you should be aware of.