So min and max width
and min and max height are useful.
But sometimes you have problems that can't be solved
with these properties alone.
And for this, let's get back here.
This overall UI on a small screen is okay,
but everything is a little bit too big.
We might wanna choose a smaller font size.
We might wanna choose less margin
between this number container and this input box.
We might want to make everything a little bit smaller
because we know they we're on a smaller device.
Now, how can we do that?
There might be different ways of achieving this,
but a great way of solving this
is to use the built-in dimensions API.
Now for that, I'll go to this number container
as an example, and there I wanna reduce the padding
and the margin if we're on a smaller screen,
and I wanna reduce that font size
if we're on a smaller screen.
And for this we can use this dimensions API.
And we use this dimensions API
by importing it from react-native,
because it is an API built into react-native.
But it's not a component we would use in our JSX code,
instead it's a JavaScript object
which we can use anywhere in our JavaScript code,
including our styles to get information out of it.
Now which kind of information
can we get out of the dimensions API?
Well, for example, we can get the device width or height.
So here we could get the device width by using dimensions,
and then there is a get method which you can call.
And the get method takes an argument, which is a string,
which holds either a value of screen or window.
On iOS there is no difference.
On Android, screen is the entire available width and height,
including the status bar.
Window is excluding the status bar.
So the actual part of the screen
where the UI should be painted and usable.
So I will use window here to get that available device size.
And then on this object, which we get from this get method,
we can access various properties.
We can access font scale
to find out which kind of scaling a user wants in the app.
And you could then take this into account
and multiply your font sizes by that factor.
But here I'm interested in height and width.
And we can, for example, get the width here,
and then use that in our styles.
But how can we use it?
Well for one, you could use it in mathematical calculations
and say that the padding should be something like
device width divided by 10.
But what's probably more useful here
is that you can use it in if conditions
or ternary expressions.
We could say if the device width here is let's say
smaller than 450 pixels,
then we wanna use a padding of let's say 12,
and we wanna use 24 if it's bigger than that.
So on smaller screens we take a padding of 12 pixels
on bigger screens we take 24.
If we save that you see the padding is reduced now,
it's now less here.
But it looks like here
I actually chose the wrong break point,
because now on both devices, including the iPhone,
we have very little padding.
But if we find a better break point,
like 380 in my case here,
then I have less padding on the left device
and more padding on the right.
We can also use this for the margin of course.
So here then use the same formula or a different condition
with different values for the margin,
so that also the margin around this number container
is affected by that.
Now this gap here is not just the margin we set here,
therefore it's still pretty big,
but will work on this gap soon as well.
So that could be a useful tool for controlling some sizes.
And you could, for example now,
also use it here for the font size
and stick to 36 on bigger devices,
but reduce this to 28 on slightly smaller devices,
so that the font is a little bit smaller
compared to the device size than it is on bigger devices.
Now, this is absolutely something you can play around with
and you can adjust to your requirements and what you want,
but you should be aware of this dimensions API,
which can help with finding out
which available space you have
to then adjust certain settings based on it.
And it's up to you, whether you adjust
based on some if statement as we do it here,
or if you have some dynamic calculation
where the width or height is used as part of a formula.
Now what I'll do here,
is I also wanna reduce this gap here a little bit
as I mentioned.
And therefore what we can do is go back to the GameScreen,
and there it's the gap between the card
and the number container.
And here it's that margin to the top on the card
which I wanna change.
And therefore in this card component
we can also include the dimensions API,
and then get our device with just as we did before,
with dimensions get window, and then the width.
And then we can use this here for the margin top
and check if this is smaller than 380,
in which case the margin top maybe should just be 18 pixels
and otherwise it's 36 pixels.
So now on smaller devices there's less margin to the top.
And with that, we indeed did reduce this gap a little bit
on the smaller device,
and we still have the bigger gap on the bigger device.
Now, again, play around with it, find your favorite settings
and maybe adjust other components as well if you want to.
I just wanted to introduce you to that dimensions API
because it can be a useful tool
for situations like this here.