Now, as a next step,
I wanna solve this game
and come back to this "game over" screen,
because here, things are also a bit too big.
And it's mostly this image, which is too big.
The rest could be adjusted as well,
but the image is definitely too big.
Now with our newly-gained knowledge
about the dimensions API,
we can improve this as well.
In the "game over" screen component,
we got this image,
and this image has the Styles image style object,
so, this one here.
And there we set the width and height to 100%,
which, as you learned, refers to the container,
and the container around the image is this view
with that imageContainer style applied to it.
If we have a look at this imageContainer style,
we see that the width and height is hard coded
to 300 pixels,
and hard coding values like this is very often
not a good idea
because you don't know on which device size
your app will run in the end.
So, again, we can solve this with the dimensions API.
And the dimensions API might be better
than using an alternative like percentage values,
which are also relative,
because we wanna ensure that width and height
do have the same value
so that we create a square with rounded corners,
to ultimately create that circle.
If I would say that width and height should maybe be 50%,
then you could think that you also get a relative size
relative to the available width and height,
but the problem is that these values are now not the same.
Yes, they are both 50%,
but 50% of different values.
The width of the container
will not be the same as the height,
so 50% of the available width,
will be a different number than 50% of the available height.
And, therefore, percentage values are not helpful here.
Instead, this is a great scenario for the dimensions API,
because we wanna have a hard coded value,
but the hard coded value should be different
for different device sizes.
So, therefore, here again,
we can import the dimensions API from React Native,
and then, as many times before,
we can get the device width, and, by the way,
you could, of course, also get the device height
if that would be more important
than the available width for you.
The dimensions API gives you both width and height,
and it's up to you what you wanna use.
But, here, I'll get the available width,
and then here, I want to actually, again,
check if we're smaller than 380 pixels,
in which case I only wanna use 150 pixels
as width for this image,
and 300 pixels only if we are on a bigger screen.
And now we use the same formula that uses the device width,
for the height,
because I wanna use a height of 150,
if we're on a small device that has a width
less than 380 pixels available,
and 300 pixels as a height for the image,
in other cases.
The border radius should also be adjusted
because the border radius should be half
the image width and height,
and therefore, here, we have the same check,
but then we use 75 for the small screen case
and 150 for the big screen case.
And, now, with that, this image is much smaller
and this screen looks much better
on smaller devices.
On bigger devices, we have a bigger image,
which also looks good there.
So, again, that's the dimensions API in action,
and, as you see, it can be a very useful API.
And also keep in mind, it's not limited to just the width,
even though I just used the width here,
you could also use it for working with the height.