So that was the Dimensions API.
Very useful, as you can tell.
Now, there's one thing we can't do with it
and with our app at the moment, though,
and that is rotate our screen.
I mean, we can rotate it.
Here I'm using a shortcut
but you can also do this here
with the menu on iOS
and rotate your device.
And on Android, you can use these buttons to rotate it.
But as you can tell, the screen doesn't adjust to that.
It doesn't flip.
The reason for that is that this app here
by default has the orientation locked to portrait.
You can set this in app.json,
which is a conflict file picked up by Expo
and this locks the orientation of the app
to a certain aspect, in this case to portrait.
Now, this is maybe what you want.
And to be honest for this kind of app, for this game,
it would probably make sense
to lock it to that orientation.
But of course you could also be building apps
where this is not locked in place,
and you can also unlock it with Expo
by setting this to default, instead of portrait.
As a side note, you can also set it to landscape
to lock it to that mode,
but here I'll go to default.
Now it's not locked anymore.
And if we now flip this, it still doesn't adjust
because typically you need to restart your app
for this to have an effect.
Here I pressed R in the terminal to force a reload
and thereafter it's now flipping on iOS.
On Android, it might still not be adjusting.
For me it is, but it might not be adjusting.
In that case open this menu here
and make sure that auto-rotate is on.
And once this is on, you should be able
to flip this screen on Android as well.
Now, what you can see is that
if you do change the orientation
the app might get broken.
Here on Android, we can barely use it still
but it doesn't look good.
And here on iOS, it looks better
but still not perfect.
There's too much space to the top now.
And if we open that keyboard on iOS
and by default it's not open
because you can type with the keyboard,
with your regular keyboard, into the simulator.
But if you do force that keyboard by going to IO, Keyboard
and then you use that, you toggle that software keyboard
then you see that that keyboard actually
overlaps the input and you can't actually
close it by tapping anywhere else.
So now the app is not usable anymore here.
I can only close it here in the simulator
by using this toggle shortcut again.
But of course the real users of your app won't have that.
So therefore this is not working this well
in different orientations, as you can tell.
And that is what we will work on next
to improve this app for different orientations.