Now, what can we do
about different orientations
and this app looking better?
Well, for one, we can again, use the dimensions API.
And we could, for example, take a look
at the available height to base this margin to the top here,
on that available height,
so that we don't have as much of a margin to the top
if we have less height available on our device here.
Now for this, we can go to the start game screen
where we have this margin to the top here
on this view with the root container style,
there, we have this hard-coded value.
And as you learn with the image on the game over screen,
hard-coded values aren't that great.
And therefore, in start game screen,
we can of course, import the dimensions API
from React Native.
And then use that to change that margin to the top.
So now we could get the device height here,
instead of the device width by using dimensions get window
and now the height.
And then here we could, again, check
if the (indistinct) height
is maybe, let's say, smaller than 400.
And in that case, we want to set a margin to the top of 30
and otherwise 100.
And you will have to play around with that value
to find out what looks good and what works well.
But if we save this, now we have less margin to the top
if we are in landscape mode.
on both iOS and Android.
And we could go for 380, since that was our width before.
If we rotate the device, that is our height break point
that sets these two devices apart
to still have the bigger margin here on iOS
and the smaller margin on Android.
Now, it is totally up to you how much margin you wanna have,
but this would be one way of doing it.
But even with that solution, it's still not perfect.
What if a user changes the orientation
whilst he or she is using this app?
If we switch back to portrait,
now we have that smaller margin still.
And the same, of course, on iOS,
it just left my screen for a second.
And the same would be true for iOS
if you would switch back, but there, of course,
thanks to this break point,
the margin was bigger anyways.
But you can see it on Android.
If we have that smaller margin
because we start in landscape mode,
then we keep it even if we rotate back.
Because that is important.
This code here, where we get the device height and so on,
is only executed once
when this component code, this entire file code
is parsed and executed for the first time.
So if we adjust the screen orientation
after starting this game,
this code down here will not get executed again.
Yes, the component file, this file will execute again
from time to time.
For example, when our estate changes.
But the code outside of this component function
will not be executed again.
So therefore, if it's possible to switch the orientation
whilst using this game or this app in general,
then you might not wanna use the dimensions API like this.
You could, but you then might be locking in values
that you don't really want thereafter.
What you should do instead, is you should write this
in a more responsive way,
which adjusts to changing device orientations.
And thankfully, this is all the very simple and easy to do
with React Native.
Instead of locking in the device height here
and instead of setting the margin top here,
what you should do, is move that code
into your component function.
So any code that should react to device orientation
or size changes, should go into the component function
because this function, unlike the overall file code,
will get executed multiple times.
Now, React Native gives you an alternative way
of accessing the dimensions API, which allows you
to then react to device size or dimension changes
inside of component functions.
React Native gives you a hook,
the use Window dimensions hook, which you can use.
Now, like all React hooks, you have to use it
inside of a component function or inside another hook.
And you then simply call this,
to get back an object,
on which you can use object de-structuring
to get the width and height Of the device.
So now here, we get width and height,
but internally, this hook will watch the device dimensions.
And whenever they change, for example,
because the device ice gets rotated,
this component function will get executed again,
and we will get an updated width and height.
And that means that now we can derive
our margin top dynamically inside of this component function
based on this dynamic height or width,
and then use this in our JSX code.
So maybe here, right before returning JSX,
we could get our margin top
by simply using height.
And then the same logic as before,
where we have this check here,
to then set a margin top of 30 or 100.
But we now do this here,
in our component function, right before we return JSX code.
And now we just need to make sure that this value
gets applied.
So here I'll name it, margin top distance,
but this name is up to you.
So that means that we now wanna merge this dynamic style
into our style sheet object that we're setting here
on the view.
And thankfully, as you learned before,
merging styles is simple.
You could, for example, turn this into an array
and then add another style object like this,
where you set margin top equal to the margin top distance
that is derived here.
And since this component function will now re-execute
whenever the dimensions change,
this will adjust whenever the device orientation changes.
So now with that, if we save that
and we force a reload on all devices,
Here, we start with a lot of margin to the top.
But if I rotate this, you see?
It gets lessened margin to the top,
it's less margin to the top now.
But if I rotate back, it's more margin again.
Because of this dynamic usage of the dimensions API.
Now you don't always have to use it like this,
but it makes sense to use this hook
instead of the other way of using the dimensions API,
if you need dynamic dimensions.
If you are fine with locking in certain values initially,
then you don't need that.
But if you do want to adjust dynamically to changing sizes,
you should use this hook
instead Of the other way of using it, which we saw before.
Now, I will not adjust the other components here,
simply to save some time for now.
But feel free to experiment with that hook here,
to see which other parts of this app could be adjusted
to different device orientations.
Here, I'll keep it like this,
but again, definitely feel free to experiment
and find different areas where you could optimize that.