Now for the rest of this section,
we will work ourselves through the different screens
and make sure that they look good
on different sizes and orientations.
But for the moment,
I wanna stay on this starting screen here.
And here, we have a problem with the keyboard.
Now on Android,
we might get that full-size overlay keyboard,
which we can close ourselves, which looks and works okay.
But on iOS, we have a problem.
There, if I toggle this built-in keyboard,
which our actual app users would be getting,
we see that we can't close it, there is no button here,
and tapping on the background doesn't do anything.
And I also can't get to the input anymore,
so I basically broke the app now.
And that, of course, is totally unacceptable.
The solution for this problem
is thankfully built into React Native, though.
We can use a specific component that helps us with that.
The KeyboardAvoidingView,
which in the StartGameScreen,
can be imported from React Native.
This is a component which you can use in your JSX code
to wrap other content with it,
other content that involves or contains an input field,
and whenever the keyboard that opens up that content
that holds your input element and other elements
can be moved up so that you can still access it,
even though the keyboard is open.
For this, all you have to do
is wrap this view here in StartGameScreen,
with this KeyboardAvoidingView.
You wrap this around your view here.
The View with rootContainer
now is wrapped by the KeyboardAvoidingView.
Now, since this will now be our rootView,
the top-most View in this component,
this would break our style.
If we save this, everything would be broken.
The reason for that is
that we no longer get as much space as we can,
but we need to get as much space as we can
on this root element, for the rest of the elements
to get their appropriate slices and to look good.
Now, we can add the style prop here,
to add a style that makes sure
that we take all the available space,
and for this I already added a new style object
in the StyleSheet, which I named screen,
which sets flex to one.
That's all I do here.
And this screen style object,
can now be added to this KeyboardAvoidingView
with styles screen like this.
With that, it looks better again.
Now, if you tap in there, nothing changes though;
it still is not accessible,
because you cannot also configure the KeyboardAvoidingView.
You can add a behavior, which either wants height,
padding, or position as a value.
Now, I do recommend that you play around
with those values to see the differences.
Very often, in my experience, position works best.
Now, if we save that, however,
we notice that everything is broken again,
because what position will do, is it will try to move this,
as you can see if you tap in there, that is working now,
out of the way so that we can still see it whilst typing.
But for this to move effectively,
this needs to be in a scrollable container,
which at the moment isn't.
Therefore, to make position work great in this case here,
we should wrap the KeyboardAvoidingView, with a scroll view.
Because we learned before that we can use a scroll view
to add scrolling.
We don't want flat list here,
because we don't have a dynamic list
with possibly an infinite amount of items,
instead we have a clearly defined user interface,
which should be scrollable in case we run out of space.
Therefore, we simply wrap ScrollView,
around the KeyboardAvoidingView, like this,
and on the scroll view, we should also add the style again
and set this to styles screen
to make sure that the scroll view
occupies all the space it can get,
because screen sets flex to one,
so that we still get all the space we can get here,
and then here, and then all our other styles
can style themselves and lay themselves out
based on that available space.
Now with that scroll view
wrapped around KeyboardAvoidingView if you save this,
this looks good again,
and now you see this moves up as I start typing.
And I can scroll this
to reach the different parts of this UI.
Here on Android, we don't really see this, but that's okay,
because we just needed it here on iOS.
Now with that, we can also tap somewhere else
to close this keyboard.
That's a nice side effect of KeyboardAvoidingView.
If you now tap this card here, the keyboard closes.
Now, if I tap here, it does not really close,
at least not always, but we do have this main area covered,
and therefore we now of course,
allow our users to always reach all these buttons,
and they can also close the keyboard.
So that's the KeyboardAvoidingView in action,
which is another super important component
exposed by React Native,
has nothing to do with expo as you see,
but instead it's built into React Native,
and it can help a lot with building accessible
and usable user input areas.