[Maximilian Shwarzmuller] Now let's continue
with improving this app.
If we move on to the next screen here on Android,
we notice a new problem.
In landscape mode, there isn't enough space available.
Even here on iOS it's not really that great.
It would be usable there but it doesn't look good
and on Android on this device here to be precise,
it's not really usable in landscape mode.
Sure we can always switch back
and that should theoretically work.
It does work here on iOS and it should be a problem
with the simulator here on Android because theoretically
we should be able to switch here as well
but either way, the problem is that it should also work well
in landscape mode and that is not happening at the moment.
So how could we improve this?
There are certainly many ways of improving this
but I wanna dive in one specific way.
I wanna totally change this UI or at least parts of this UI
when we are in landscape mode
or when we have more width but less height available.
And we can achieve this pretty easily
with the Dimensions API
but now we're using it for a brand new concept
to dynamically adjust the layout structure
and the component structure.
For this here, in the GameScreen, that is our UI
as we display it when everything is normal,
so in portrait mode.
Now what I want to do, is I wanna change this.
I wanna render a different UI in landscape mode.
For that we can use the Dimensions API
and I wanna use it such that we can listen to changes
in the dimensions inside our component function.
So therefore, I wanna use this hook,
the useWindowDimensions hook.
And then as you learned, we can use that
in our component function in the GameScreen,
we can call useWindowDimensions
and then we can get our width and height.
And you don't need to always get both, you can of course
just get the one value you might be interested in.
Here I'm just getting both to show you
that both properties exist on this object returned
by useWindowDimensions.
Now I just wanna find out
if we have plenty of width available
in which case I wanna display a layout that is optimized
for more width.
So therefore, maybe down here, right before we return JSX,
I in the end want to create a variable,
content could be the name
and that content should be the JSX code
that should be rendered by default.
So that could be this NumberContainer with the card below it
like this.
Therefore, I'll cut this from here
and then add this between those fragment tags here
like that.
I used these fragment tags
since I have two root components next to each other,
card and number container are root sibling components
and this would not be allowed without such a fragment tag.
Now that is my default layout
and therefore I'll inject this content variable here
below the title, above the view.
With that alone, nothing changes of course,
we got the same look and feel as before.
But now I do want to change the layout,
if we have more width available.
And for this we could add a if statement here
and check if width is maybe greater than
let's say 500 or 600, you can play around with that.
If we have that much width available,
then we are likely in landscape mode but even if we're not,
then I wanna display my UI differently.
Then my content, which will be output down there,
is not this NumberContainer with the card next to it
instead I then wanna have my NumberContainer
but to the left and right of that, I wanna have my buttons
and above the NumberContainer,
I wanna have this higher or lower text.
So actually here, I will also add the fragment tags
but now above the NumberContainer,
I will have the instruction text here.
So copy this down there
and then left and right of the NumberContainer,
I wanna have my buttons,
therefore I will wrap this in a view overall.
And in that view, I then add these two buttons here.
So I copy the views that wrap the buttons like this
but now one button is in front of the NumberContainer,
one button comes thereafter.
If we save that, now the layout changed, as you can tell.
It's not looking the way I want
because I haven't added all the styles yet
but you see the card is gone and instead one button is here
and the other button comes after the NumberContainer
as you can see here on my iOS Simulator.
Now of course, the styling is not the styling I want,
therefore I'll add a new style here
to this wide screen content
and set this to buttonsContainerWide maybe.
The name is up to you.
Here I'll choose buttonsContainerWide
and add this down here.
And then here for buttonsContainerWide,
I want to set flexDirection to row.
The default is column so here I'll override it to row
and set alignItems to center
so that everything is centered vertically.
If we save this, I now have this user interface
which I personally find much better.
However, you can see here on iOS
that still the log is pretty cut off and hard to use.
So therefore, we might not even want
that higher or lower text here and simply get rid of that
because you don't need to have the same elements,
you can render two totally different user interfaces
or layouts with different content based on the width
as we're doing it here.
So now this is gone and now the log is a bit more accessible
and easier to see.
We might also want to reduce the spacing
around this container and the spacing above the log
and therefore on this listContainer that holds the log,
we could, for example, adjust the padding
so that there is less padding around the log
or at least reduce the padding to top and bottom.
Alternatively, in the number container, we could of course
tweak the margin so that there is less space
around the NumberContainer that will be reserved.
Feel free to do that.
Here, we now at least got a basic style
that we can use to play this game.
It might still be optimal in portrait mode
but now it is at least playable in a landscape mode as well.
Thanks to adjusting this dynamically.
And with this, we're left with this game over screen,
which doesn't really work in landscape mode
as you can tell here.
Now definitely feel free to find a way
of fixing this on your own.
In the next lecture, we will fix this together.