So let's now work on this game over screen.
At the moment, it doesn't look that good here.
And I think an easy way of improving the way it looks
is to shrink the image a bit more and make it scrollable
so that we can always reach this new game button
even if it would be outside of the screen.
And at the moment that is not possible.
Now, actually in the game over screen
we are already setting the image width and height
but at the moment we're only changing it based on the width
and we probably also wanna take the height into account.
We also wanna make sure that
if the device orientation changes,
we adjust the image size.
Now to do this
we can use this other form of the dimensions API.
We can use the useWindowDimensions hook instead.
So now instead of setting
the width, height, and border radius down there
we now wanna do this dynamically
in the component function
to react to changes in these values.
We do, of course, also wanna get rid of that code.
And here I'm just commenting it out
so that we can still see it.
So now inside of the game over screen,
we can of course use this hook to get
the width and the height of this screen,
of this size like this.
And now we can use this width and height
to adjust the image size.
For this we can set a imageSize of 300 as a default
and then we can add a if statement
to calculate various alternatives.
For example, if the width is smaller than 380,
which was the check we had before,
then we might want to use a image size of 150
and I'll use the image size
for both the width and height later,
and also for calculating the radius.
But we also know that if the height is maybe
smaller than 380 or smaller than 400, let's say,
then we also wanna make this smaller.
Then we might want to set the image size to just 80.
And then we got a certain image style here
which in the end sets a width
which is equal to the image size
and a height which is equal to the image size
and which sets a border radius
which is image size divided by two.
And now it's this image style that should be merged
with the other image styles dynamically
on that container though,
because it was that container
on which we set width, height, and border radius before.
Now we don't wanna override it,
because we're still setting some other styles in there
but we wanna merge in our new styles.
So therefore, again, we can wrap this
into an array
and then simply add our image style object to that array
so that these styles will also be taken into account.
With this, the image is smaller.
But if we rotate, it gets bigger again.
So this works the way it should here.
Now, in addition, as mentioned,
we might want to make this all scrollable,
even though it's not needed here,
but it could be needed on some devices.
And therefore we can also include the scroll view here,
and import that and add this as a wrapper
around this entire screen in the end.
So we wrap the root view with this scroll view.
And now we just wanna make sure that we set flex: 1
on this scroll view here again.
So we add style and set this equal to styles.screen
maybe again, which we have yet to add.
And then we add a new style object here,
the screen object, as we did it before,
where we set flex: 1 like this.
With that, this now also is scrollable
even though it's not needed here
but we could scroll if we would need it.
And with that, we also fixed that game over screen.
And now we should be able to use all these screens here
and play this game on different screen sizes
even though it might still be best on portrait,
but it now also works on different screen sizes.