[Maximilian Schwarzmüller] Now that was a lot
about screen sizes and orientations and adjusting to changes
in those sizes and orientations, and as mentioned before,
definitely play around with those different tools
to learn more about how they work and to optimize
the UI for your personal preferences.
What I wanna do here, is, I now wanna move away
from adjusting to sizes and instead adjust
to platforms because that is also quite interesting.
Now for this I'm back here on Android and iOS portrait mode,
but now let's say there are certain elements
that should look different on the two platforms.
To be honest here, I like the style,
I like the similar style for both platforms
and it is one of the advantages React Native offers
that we can write one code base
and target multiple platforms.
But sometimes you want slightly different styles
for different platforms and React Native
also gives you tools for this case.
Now, for that, let's say that in here, we wanted to change
this title based on the platform we're running on.
On Android, we might wanna keep it like this,
but maybe on iOS, we wanna get rid of the border.
How can we do that?
Well, we go to the title, and now we wanna adjust
the styles based on the underlying platform.
For this, React Native gives us another API we can use,
the platform API.
The platform API allows us to detect
on which platform we're running.
Now, we don't need to set up a dynamic listener here
because the platform is not going to change
whilst the app is running, unlike the dimensions,
instead, it is always the same for the entire lifetime
of this app, so we can use this platform API anywhere
and we don't need to React to any changes.
And if we would want to get rid of the border,
we could say here for "Border width",
instead of always setting this to two,
we use the platform API, and then on that platform API,
we can access OS, this OS property, which is actually
a string that's equal to Android, iOS, or,
since you theoretically could also build desktop apps
or web apps with React Native, Macos, Windows, and web.
But we will focus on Android and iOS in this course.
And if I only want to set a border width on Android,
then I check if this is equal to Android, and then I set
a border width of two, otherwise, of zero.
With that, you see the border is gone on iOS,
but it's still there on Android, and that's how easy it is
to use that platform API.
But when it comes to working with the platform API,
there also are other ways of using it.
You can use it in a turnery expression like this
and there's nothing wrong with it, this is short and easy
to read, but there also is an alternative way of using it.
You can use the platform API object here
and use the built-in select method.
Now select wants an object as our parameter value,
and in this object, you should specify an iOS property
and an Android property.
And then you can set different values that will eventually
be returned by select for these different platforms.
So here I could then set zero for iOS and two for Android.
So that's simply a different way of writing
such a conditional statement.
In a place where you want a value that should be different
for iOS or Android, you can use platform select
to define the iOS and the Android values,
and then select will return the appropriate value
in its place based on the platform
on which this code is executed.
So with that we achieve the same result as before
but this is maybe a bit more readable,
or it's simply an alternative that you should also know.
Now, another alternative, which I also wanna show you
which can be very useful when writing platform specific code
is to write platform specific files.
Now, up to this point, we always added Component files
like this, which had a Component name and ended with .JS,
and that's the default.
But you can actually also write platform specific
Component files or code files in general.
For example, if I wanna write
an Android specific title Component version,
I can copy this and name this file, title.android.JS.
And then I could name the other Component title.iOS.JS.
Now you don't need to adjust your imports.
In the places where title gets used, you should make sure
that you don't have .iOS or .android at the end,
and since my IDE added the .iOS extension automatically
here, I removed it, and you wanna make sure you remove that
on all the screens where the title is used
because you still import as if the file
would just be named title.JS, and under the hood,
React Native will pick the proper file based on the platform
on which you're running.
And so now we could go to title. Android and get rid
of the platform API usage here and just set border,
border width, to two here, because we know that this file
with these style settings will only be executed for Android.
And on the other hand on title iOS JS, we can also get rid
of that code and always set border width to zero,
or simply get rid of all the border settings altogether
since we want no border.
Now it might be overkill here for the title,
where this simple switch was actually enough to achieve
the desired result, but it is a feature you must know.
And therefore, here, I'm showing this to you by building
the same Component twice in different files
with different file endings, with slightly different styles.
And with that, if we reload everything,
we still get the different styles as before,
but now we achieve this
with help of platform specific files.
And you're not limited to Component files, you could also
be importing from other files,
like maybe different colors files,
where one file defines the colors for Android
and one file defines the colors for iOS.
Then you would just add the different extensions here
and you would make sure that you always import
from just colors, so you don't include the extension here
in the import statements, and then React Native would pick
the different files for the different platforms,
and you could easily set up different color palettes
with a trick like this.
And actually, why don't we give this a quick try?
If I add colors. Android JS here, and then colors.iOS JS,
we have to make sure that in all the places
where we import colors, we don't have .iOS at the end,
so we wanna make sure that we search for all the imports
and we never have colors.iOS or colors. Android here,
but always just colors, that's really important.
So we wanna search all those imports and get rid
of these extensions here, which is what I'm doing here,
so that ultimately, we can then set up
different color palettes for the different platforms.
So now with all those imports adjusted, we could say
that for Android, maybe this primary color here
should be green and this accent color should be,
should maybe be this color here.
Now that's probably ugly, but we can see that it's only used
on Android and not on iOS.
Now I will actually revert this because here I was happy
with my colors on both platforms, and therefore here,
of course, we don't need those different platform files,
but it is worth noting that this feature exists,
that it's not exclusive to Components and that you can use
this feature to define different Components,
different styles, different colors and different code,
in general, for the different platforms.