Now to come to an end in this course section
there is one last component I wanna talk about.
And that's the status bar.
We actually did see this early in the course already
and I wanna reintroduce it here.
The status bar component is a component exposed by Expo
which allows us to control how the status bar looks like.
And typically you want to include
that in your app JS file
though you can include it in specific component files
specifically components that take up the entire screen
to style the status bar differently
inside of different components.
Now, for this, we need to import from expo-status-bar
and this is a package
that should already be installed by default.
And what we import from there is the StatusBar
between curly braces like this.
Now we can use this here in my app component in this case.
Next to my root component here
which in this case is the linear gradient.
There I will render my StatusBar.
And now since I have two sibling root components
I will wrap this with this fragment component here.
Otherwise this wouldn't be allowed.
And on StatusBar,
you can now set the style to light, like this
and you get a white status bar.
Now all on iOS where it was gone before.
Alternatively, you could set this to dark
to get a dark status bar.
Now here, I'd say light looks a little bit better.
So I'll go for a style light, but as always
you can choose the style you prefer, but it is worth noting
that this status bar component is a key component
that allows you to control whenever a status bar is shown
as you saw it was missing before and how it looks like.
And therefore, typically you wanna add it
because you want a status bar
and you want the dead status bar to look good.
So here you go.
The status bar component has got you covered.