In the previous course section,
we got started with key React Native
fundamentals and basics.
In this course section we are going to explore
how we can debug React Native apps
because things go wrong, errors happen,
and you must be able to fix errors on your own
and you must be able to understand your app
and dig into your app and the UI you built
whilst you're building it.
Therefore, in this course section
we are going to take a look at an example error message
and see what we can make of such error messages,
which hints we can get out of error messages,
and how we should treat and handle error messages.
Before we then also take a look at some DevTools
and some additions we get by using React Native and Expo
that also help us when it comes to debugging
React Native apps.
Now, for this course section,
I'm going to use this app we built
in the previous course section.
In case you skipped that section, you'll find it attached
so that you can follow along just fine.
And with that, let's dive into debugging.