[Maximilian Schwarzmuller] Now, let's start this section
by exploring error messages.
And at the moment this app has no error,
but we can force one.
Tor this I'll go to the GoalInput.js file
and in there, I will simply force an error
by actually setting this image source
not to the correct source.
I will comment this out.
Instead, I will set the source to just a string,
some path to image.
Now this path doesn't exist, but this doesn't matter
because that's also not a good way of defining such a path.
If I save this, we now get an error here,
when we have a look at our emulators at the bottom,
and we also get one here in the terminal.
And the error message we're getting here
is that we provided an invalid prop,
to be precise that the source prop is the problem,
to the image, and that it expected one of type number.
Now I will be honest.
This last part is a bit confusing and you will often have
confusing elements in error messages, they are not perfect.
But what is important is that
you read the message because often it gives you
a first hint at what's wrong and what could be the problem.
Here the hint is relatively clear that it is related
to the source prop of the image component.
But even if it's a bit more abstract,
you might at least get a first idea
of where to look for the problem
and where you could maybe fix it.
Now, in addition, what's also very useful
when getting error messages, is this stack trace down here.
This tells you where the error occurred.
The first line isn't too useful
because here it points at an image component
in some weird path,
because that in the end is the bundled code
to which it's pointing here
and that's not helping us too much.
But if you have a look at the parts down here,
it becomes more useful.
Here we learn that it's in the GoalInput component,
which is created by the App component.
This can be useful if you have the same component
being used in multiple components,
then you know which instance being used
by which other component is causing this.
And therefore now it's pretty clear
that we should dive into the GoalInput component
and that in there we might wanna look for
the users of the image component,
and then take a closer look at the source prop.
And if we're not sure of what should be provided here
then of course it's always a good idea
to look into the official documentation.
If you search for react native image,
you should get a direct link
to the official documentation for this image component.
But you can also just go to the React Native main page
and then to Components, and then find the image there.
And here you then learn more
about the usage of this component,
and which kind of value can be passed to the source prop.
Now, here we forced this error, of course.
So it is rather simple to fix,
but I wanted to show you
what you can make of such error messages.
And before I save this fixed code
let's also have a closer look at the emulator again.
There, we also got a error message at the bottom here.
And you will sometimes get warnings
or error messages down here
and you can click on them to see more details.
Indeed, you see that here it's actually not an error
but a warning, which means,
yeah, the app still runs but not as intended,
in this case no image would be displayed
and you get a similar output as before.
You get basically the same error
or warning message up here.
And then you got a stack trace down here,
though I will say that this output here
is not that useful compared to what we had
here in the terminal.
Here in the terminal it was pretty clear pretty quickly
which component, the image component,
in which component built by us causes the problem.
Here it's not immediately clear.
Nonetheless, taking a look
at this output can also be helpful.
At least here we also learned
that it is related to an image.
Now with that I will of course save the fixed code.
And with that, the apps update and the error goes away.