Now we had a look at an error message.
Sometimes you don't have an error necessarily
but you want to get deeper insights into your application.
Now one thing you can do to get insights
is you can log things.
You can add simple console log statements to your job,
a script code, as you might be doing it in the browser
and then log something like, goal input component rendered.
And when you do that, when you add log messages like this,
as a result, you will see them here in your terminal
where you started this MPM start process.
So here, if by expand this,
we see that this is being output here.
And we see it twice because I'm running the app twice
on two different emulators.
So that can of course also sometimes be useful
to understand the flow of your application.
By adding this into different places,
into some functions, into some component functions,
maybe in some other places
you understand which code gets executed
at which point of time.
And of course, you can also console log
things like the entered goal text here
to print the value or to print some value
of some variable or state.
So that if I save this and I now go here and I start typing.
We actually see that this text is being output here.
So that again, we understand when this code executes,
when it logs something to the console
and which concrete value we might be storing
in some variable at a given point of time.
So console log can be very useful
and you get the log messages delivered
to your terminal here.