Now sometimes,
you want more detailed insights.
You don't just want to console lock something.
When using React Native,
especially also with Expo,
you get some additional tools.
Now for this let's press question mark here,
in our terminal
where we started npm-start
to see a full list of available shortcuts we can use
whilst this npm-start process is running.
So you just need to activate this terminal, this console
by clicking into it,
and then you can use the shortcuts you see here
to trigger certain things.
For example, we did press A, to open the app on Android
or I, to open it on iOS before.
You can for example, also press R, to force a reload,
I also did that before.
Now, what's quite interesting
is that you can also
press M, to toggle a menu,
to be precise a developer menu.
If you press M here,
this menu opens up on one of the two emulators
which you can also open by pressing Command-D on iOS
or Command or Control-M on Android.
Alternatively, press M here,
in the terminal to open it as you saw.
And then in this developer menu,
you can also force a reload.
You can go back to the homepage of your app here
but you can also do a couple of other things.
For example, you can debug JavaScript remotely.
If you click on this,
a new tab in Chrome should open up,
and in that tab,
you can open up the Chrome Developer Tools
and in those developer tools, you can, for example,
see network requests made by your app.
At the moment our app isn't making any network requests
but you could see network requests made by your app here
if it's reaching out to some backend or anything like this.
Here, we just see some development and debugging assets,
which are downloaded.
(alert chiming)
And you also see a console
where you can see the log messages
your app might be generating.
For example, if I go back to my code here,
and I re-add console.log "GoalInput"
here in the goal input component and I save this.
In that console, you should also see output generated
by the running app.
If you don't see it here,
you might need to force a reload
or even restart the iOS app.
I did have problems with that before,
it can be a bit clunky
but ultimately you should see some output here as well.
Now, this is just an additional way of looking into your app
and especially having a look at the network requests
could be something that is interesting.
Now you can at any time, of course,
stop remote debugging
to go back to the old state, like this.
It's just an addition,
not something you have to use all the time,
and probably not something
you want to use all the time.