Now Remote Debugging can be nice
for certain situations.
What I personally find more useful is to use
the React developer tools
and not some specific React native developer tools
but the regular React devtools.
Now you might know the React devtools as an extension
you can install in your browser
and that extension will not work for React native.
But what you can do here in a separate terminal
is you can install them globally on your system,
or also as a project only dependency
but here I'll install them globally
with npm install -g react -devtools
and here on MacOS, I need to add a sudo
in front of this to make it work.
You might not need to do that on windows.
You definitely don't
because sudo doesn't exist there and isn't required there.
And if you hit enter and you install this package
what this will give you is a standalone version
of the React devtools.
With the devtools installed
you can start and by running react -devtools
like this as a standalone command in the terminal.
And please note
that I still have my npm start process up and running.
And this opens up a new window.
This opens up this devtools window here.
Now with that up and running, you can go back
to your simulator, to your app and open that builtin menu,
that development menu and enable Debug Remote JS again.
And now the React devtool should connect.
Now you see that by the way, my color gets lost if I do that
seems to be a bug.
I don't know exactly where this is coming from here
but the background color set in the app
Json file is getting lost
as I enable Remote JavaScript Debugging
but it is what it is.
Nonetheless now we got these React devtools up and running
and in those tools, that's the nice thing.
You can see your component tree.
You can see the app component
you see all these devtools components like view and button
and then the components that are part of the builtin button
which can also be interesting to look into
you see your goal input.
And what's really nice is if you click on a component
you see the props it gets and the values of those props
and you see any state you have in there.
And as I, for example, start typing here.
You see that this state updates here as well
and you can even change this state here
to simulate different things and to test different things.
And you see this updated state gets reflected back
into the application.
And these React devtools are really nice to have
because being able to look into your component tree
whilst your app is running
and analyzing your state and your props
and even changing those values can be super useful
especially as you're building more complex apps.
Now, of course, if you don't need it
you might want to not run this
and you might want to actually disable
this Remote Debugging in that case,
since it can cause some performance issues
but it is a nice to have feature here.
Now with that, I will reload though and get rid of this.