Even though we had a first look at some important basics
like these core Components
and how you can style and debug your React Native apps,
we're only scratching the surface thus far.
It's time to dive deeper
and that's exactly what we'll do in this core section,
we're going to dig deeper into all these fundamentals,
into all these basics that you must know.
And for this, we're going to build a complete Demo App,
a brand new app,
a little game where you will be able to enter a number
between one and 99
and then it's the phone's task to guess your number
and you give the phone hints,
and then we'll see how many turns it takes the phone
to guess your number.
So it's a nice little game, a Number app, which we'll build.
And as you can already tell by looking at this app
there are some new concepts in there
like using gradients or background images.
We have multiple screens between which we'll navigate
and therefore we're going to dive
into many new Core Components.
We'll work on these Complex Layouts
and learn many things about creating layouts like this.
And we'll dive deeper into Styling
and learn about some brand new Styling techniques as well.
And last but definitely not least,
this is a React app after all, a React Native app,
but therefore also a React app
and hence we will also build reusable components.
We will build custom components
and we will ensure that we don't just create this app
in some way but in a good way by writing good code,
good react code to be precise.
So plenty of things to cover, by the end of this module
you will have a super deep understanding
of react native and of its fundamentals
and therefore let's dive right in.