[Maximilian Schwarzmuller] Now to get started.
I created a brand new expo project
and you find my project attached.
So that you can use the same starting point as I did.
It's a very simple app with only one component.
The app component
with some dummy content and some basic styles.
This will be our starting point for this course section.
Now in this course section,
we're going to build this game
which I already showed you.
This game of course has multiple screens.
It has this starting screen, where we
as the owner of the phone, pick a number between one and 99.
And on this screen, we want to do a couple of things.
We want to ensure that no number smaller
than one or bigger than 99 can be picked,
for example.
We also then want to allow the user to reset this input
and pick a new number, or finally start a game
at which point we'll navigate to the game screen.
The second main screen we have in this game.
On this screen
the phone will guess the number
and we have to tell the phone after every guess,
if it should guess lower or higher
to get closer to our number.
Now on this screen, we for example
show a little alert, a little a warning.
If we give the phone a wrong hint.
If our chosen number is smaller and we tell the phone
that it's bigger, something like this.
Now, besides that every guess by the phone is logged
and we see our log here, and this log also is scrollable.
In case we exceed the max available height.
Last but not least, once the phone guess our number.
We get this Game Over screen
with a short summary and this nice image.
And then from that screen
we can start a new game if we want to.
And therefore, in this starting app here
we will have to add all these screens
but also plenty of other reusable components.
Like the buttons we have, because we will build those
from scratch ourselves and many other things.
And therefore, that's what we'll do
for the rest of this section.
Now, if you're feeling super fancy
definitely try building a first prototype of this game
on your own with the basic React
and React Native knowledge you have up to this point.
You will not be able to recreate the exact same look
because there are new components
and new tricks that we will need to build this result.
But maybe you can build a basic prototype
with React and React Native.
And if you want to definitely try building this
on your own first, but of course
otherwise it's perfectly fine to just follow along
so that we can build this game together step by step.
And at the same time
we will learn many new important things
about React and React Native.