So let's dive right into building this app.
And for this, I am in this new project
and as you saw before,
we will have a couple of screens in this app.
Therefore, what I'll do as a first step
is I'll add a folder named screens in this project.
You don't have to create that folder,
you don't have to name it screens,
but I like to add my components that will act as screens,
so that will be full size
taking up the entire size off the screen.
I like to store them in such a screens folder
to make it clear that this will be full screen components.
And I will also add a components folder
which will hold all the other components
that are then combined together to make up these screens.
So in the past, in the first app we built,
we only had one screen in the end
and then we had that model
which you could count as a second screen
but it generally was all on one screen
and our app component did render the entire screen
and all the components that made up that screen.
Now we will have multiple main screens
between which we'll switch and you will learn
how you can switch throughout this section,
though we will also come back to this idea of screens
and navigating between screens later in the course
when we dive into navigation.
But now we have these two folders, screens and components.
And in the screens folder, I will add three new files.
I will add a StartGameScreen.js file
which will hold the component
that will act as a, well, start screen
where we pick the number that should be guessed
and where we start the game.
I will then add a second component,
a second component file I should say,
which I will name GameScreen.
This will be the component, the screen
that will be responsible for the actual game.
So where we will see the gases by the phone
and where we then let the phone know
if the gas is too high or too low.
And then finally we have one last screen
and that's the GameOverScreen
which will be shown once the game is over.
At the moment, all three files are empty
but we're going to add content throughout this section.
Now it makes sense to start with the StartGameScreen
because that is the first screen we will see,
that is the screen that will allow us to pick a number
and then start the game.
Therefore I'll start by adding a new functional component
in there like this and it will export it
so that we can use it in other files.
And that's the first important takeaway by the way.
A screen, as I define it here,
is just a regular react component,
a react component that will render
react native core components
and custom components which then in turn
are made up of react native core components.
That is what a screen is, it's nothing special,
it's just a component.
And therefore now the question is
what do we want to display on this StartGameScreen?
And it is of course up to you
what you would want to display,
but in this game which I have in mind,
we essentially have this input field
where users can enter a number
and then we also have a button
which allows users to confirm that number
and the button which allows users to reset the input
and then a couple of titles around that input field
to provide some instructions.
Now, therefore we can start simple
by adding this input field.
And for this, we import another component from react native
and this the text input component
which we also saw already in the first course section.
This is a component that renders a input field
which can be used to enter data,
some text or in this case a number.
Now, I don't just want to display a text input field,
I also wanna have two buttons below that text input field.
One button for resetting and one button for confirming.
And therefore we could also import button, we could do that,
but I instead wanna build my own custom button
so that you also see how this could be done
since this will be something you will do quite a lot
when working with react native.
Because when you build your own buttons,
you have full control over their look and feel.
Therefore I will not add a button but I will import a view
because I want to use a view as a container
around my text input and those buttons.
So therefore here I then add my text input in that view
and then below that text input, I plan on having my buttons.
By the way, rendering text like this
would not work as you learned.
You can't output text directly in a view,
you would need to wrap this with a text component,
but here I just placed this text for me
as a placeholder to remind myself
that here I wanna display some buttons.
So at the moment, this would not work
and I'm not even running this NPM start process
because I know that it won't work.
I just wanna outline this base component structure
that I wanna have.