Now, speaking of those buttons,
I think this is a great next step,
building those custom buttons,
because this is something
we haven't really done up to this point,
or at least not in great detail,
and it is something that's definitely interesting to do.
So let's add custom buttons.
And for this, I will add a custom button component
which I'll name PrimaryButton.
The name of course is up to you though.
It's just the main button I will use in this course section
and therefore I name it PrimaryButton,
like this.
And of course,
we also exported this PrimaryButton component
so that it can be used in our files.
And this, of course,
is just standard React here.
We build a component,
we make it available outside of this file
so that it can be used in our files.
Now, when it comes to building this button here,
it is important to understand,
that again,
we're just going to combine core components
exposed by React Native.
And I think what could be quite interesting related to that
is if you search for GitHub React Native.
Here, you will find the official React Native source code,
which is free to access for everyone.
You can dive into it and have a look at it.
Now in this GitHub repository
if you dive into Libraries
and then into Components,
you will find the Button.js file
which holds the source code for this button
which we can import from React Native.
And it can be interesting to dive into code like this
to see how that button was built by the React Native team.
But what you will notice
if you dive into the source code
is that in the end it's also just a combination
of other core components,
to be precise of View and Text in its core.
And then we got a style sheet
and a bunch of logic.
And therefore here,
where I build my own button,
I will also use these core components.
For this, we simply import View and Text from react-native.
and now we can build a button with those components.
Of course, you don't need to use View and Text.
Maybe you have a simple button
that is just some clickable Text,
but I also bring in the View
so that I can build a nicely styled container
around this button
because not all style properties can be applied
to Text and vice versa.
Therefore, here for me,
a button is in the end a View with a Text let's say
and the Text should of course be provided from outside.
So in the component where I use the PrimaryButton,
I want to be able to provide the Text for the button
between the PrimaryButton opening and closing tags.
So we wanna accept props
and then the content between the opening and closing tags
in React is made available
through the special children prop.
And this is standard React,
has nothing to do with React Native.
Now what you can do,
it's not mandatory,
but what you can do
is you can use object destructuring here
in that parameter place,
in that argument list.
And simply destructure the children prop like this.
This saves you the hassle
of having to access props.children down here
and you directly pull out that children property
from that incoming props object
with that object destructuring syntax.
It's optional,
but I will do it here.
Now with this,
we have a simple custom component
that renders a View and a Text
with some text between those Text tags.
At the moment, this button has no styling
but we can already use this component.
So back in the StartGameScreen,
we could now display two buttons below that TextInput.
So therefore, here we can now access PrimaryButton
and make sure to add this import
that imports primary button
from the components folder
and that PrimaryButton.js file.
And then on the first button,
we could say Reset
by passing the text Reset between opening and closing tags.
And then we add another primary button
where we maybe say Confirm,
to confirm our choice
which we will be able to make here
in the future.
And with this, we won't have any styling at all
but we should have a functional first View here,
a first component.
Now I wanna use this Screen component
and for this, we have to go to App.js
because as explained earlier in the course,
the App.js file is the first file
that will be loaded by React Native,
and the component exported in that file
is the main component that will be rendered
by React Native.
So if I wanna display the StartGameScreen,
I have to use this StartGameScreen component
in my App component,
I have to use it there.
So therefore, what I'll do
is I'll import StartGameScreen,
from ./screens/StartGameScreen.
So from that file,
and with that imported
we can simply render this as a standard component.
And I will get rid of the styles down there.
I'll keep the style sheet
because we might need it eventually,
but I will get rid of all the styles
and we can get rid of that extra import here
and get rid of the StatusBar import.
Now with all of of that,
this should be an app that works.
So what we could do now,
is run npm start
to start this expo build process
that watches our code
and then previews the app
on our emulators
and start our emulators.
And as soon as you started your emulators,
you can press A in this terminal to start the app on Android
and I to start it on iOS,
if you also have an iOS simulator.
So this will now ensure that
the expo app starts on those simulators and emulators
and that our application will then be started
on those devices.
So here we go.
Now the app is up and running on both virtual devices.
Of course, at the moment,
it's not pretty,
it's pretty ugly, indeed.
But we have something up and running.
As a next step,
we can start styling these buttons
and styling the overall app creating a layout.
We can work on these things
to make sure that we slowly get closer
to the final state that we wanna achieve.