So what would be a good next step?
Well, I would say a good next step
would be to ensure that the buttons here
and the text input, which we can't really see,
but which is there,
that these elements are a bit more centered
and not sitting directly on those edges
where we can't really use them.
That would be very useful.
And to achieve this,
we can go back to the StartGameScreen
because that is where we have this View
with the input element and the buttons.
And of course, we can now position this View
and we can change how it's positioned and laid out.
And for this, you learnt that we do that
with help of the StyleSheet object
that is exposed by React Native
because this allows us to create a style sheet object,
which allows us to set up styles
that can then be attached
to our different Components and elements.
So here, I'll add a styles constant with StyleSheet.create,
like this.
Now, in here, the question is,
which kind of styles do we want?
And I wanna start with a basic style for the main View
that wraps these elements,
which ensures that this View is a bit more away
from the edges of the device.
So we'll name this style object inputContainer.
The name is up to you though,
and it will add flex one.
Flex one, as you learnt before,
ensures that the element on which we add this styling object
takes up as much space as it can.
So that could be the entire space on the screen
or if there is another sibling element somewhere,
they would split the available space
depending on the flex options set on that sibling container.
Here, it will be the only container
and therefore it should take up the entire available space.
Now, in addition, I will also add some padding here
so that we have some distance to the edges.
And I will add 16 pixels of padding,
though you can, of course, play around with that
to find the right amount for your requirements.
I will also add some extra margin to the top,
so some extra distance to the top, outside of the box.
Though it won't matter too much right now
because we have no background or border anyways.
So we don't really see where the View box ends and starts.
But still, I'll use marginTop here.
Instead of marginTop of 100 pixels,
to push this View to which I'll add my styling,
away from the top edge of the device.
And speaking of that,
we can now add the style prop to this View
that holds the text input
and add styles.inputContainer to it
so that these styles are applied to this View.
And if you do that and save everything,
it should automatically refresh your applications here
on your devices.
And now the content is a bit further away
from the device edges,
which is nice.
Of course, that's not all we wanna do
when it comes to layouting.
It's just a first step.
As a next step, it would be nice to have some background
behind this entire input area.
So behind the input element and the buttons,
which separates the input area from the rest of the screen.
At the moment, everything is white here.
Later, we will add a background image.
But either way, I wanna visually separate the input area
from the background of this screen.
And therefore, what I'll do as a next step,
is I'll add a backgroundColor
to this inputContainer,
which is the element that holds my input element
and the primary button.
And I'll add a background color,
which I prepared in advance,
which has a hex code of 27063c,
which is this plum color here.
If I save this, we got this background color here.
And because of flex one,
it's basically taking up the entire screen.
We just have some white space up here
because we have marginTop 100.
So the entire container does take up all the space it can
but it is pushed away from the top by 100 pixels.
And that's this white area.
But the rest now has this color.
Now, this is actually not the look I want though.
Instead I just want to have a tiny box
around the input and the buttons.
I don't wanna add a background to the entire screen.
Now this could be achieved by actually removing flex one.
If we do that, it only takes up the space it needs
to squeeze the elements,
the content off this box into itself.
So now it only takes up as much space as needed
by the text input and the buttons
and the padding added here.
And for the moment, that's closer to what I want,
even though we will fine tune this again later.
But for the moment, we have this input area here.
As a second step, I will now also add a marginHorizontal,
so left and right of 24 pixels,
so that we also have some space into the left and right.
And I wanna add rounded corners to this input area.
So therefore, I'll also add borderRadius
and give this a border radius of let's say, eight pixels.
So if we save this, we now have these nice rounded corners.
In addition, I think it would be nice
to have a little bit of a shadow behind this box.
And that's also something we haven't done before.
And adding shadows is different
from what you know from web development.
Because in web development, if you would add a shadow,
you could do this by adding the boxShadow CSS property.
But this does not exist in React Native.
Instead, if you wanna add a shadow,
there are two main ways
which differ between Android and iOS.
On Android, you can add a elevation property
here to your styling, which does not exist in CSS,
but which instead is React Native specific.
And elevation takes a value like zero, one, two, three
and so on.
So we have different levels of elevation.
And the higher the level, the more shadow will be added.
If I add four, for example, what you will see
is that on the Android device,
we now have a tiny shadow behind this box.
It might be clearer if you pick a higher number like eight.
If you set eight, now we can see it a bit more clearly
that there is a shadow.
Now I will go back to four, though.
So we have a little bit of a background shadow
on Android now,
but we have absolutely no shadow on iOS.
And the reason for that,
is that elevation indeed is a Android-only property.
It has no effect on iOS
because you can't add shadows with elevation.
It's a Android-specific concept.
And here, it's really important
to keep in mind that all these Views,
all these core Components which we're using,
are compiled to native Components
for the different platforms.
And we have different native Components for Android and iOS.
And these native Components
support different style properties
in their native languages.
And the style properties we said here,
are in the end also translated
to native style instructions by a React Native
and many style properties can be translated
into fitting instructions for both operating systems,
iOS and Android.
But the elevation property is an exception.
It can be translated into an appropriate instruction
on Android, but there is no equivalent
to this elevation concept in iOS.
And that's why we have no shadow there.
If we wanna add a shadow for iOS, we can do that.
But we do it with a different set of properties
with the shadow properties, shadowColour, shadowOffset,
shadowOpacity and shadowRadius.
These four properties together
allow us to add a shadow on iOS
in addition to adding a shadow on Android with elevation.
Now, shadowColor allows you to pick the color of the shadow.
You could create a reddish shadow,
but here I'll use black as a shadowColor.
But of course, you can pick any color you want.
ShadowOffset then wants an object
where you control how much the shadow should be offset
from the original object to which it belongs
to the left and to the right.
Therefore, you have a width and a height property here
which you can set and you set a number here,
which will be treated as pixels
by which the shadow will be offset.
For example, if I choose zero for the width
and two for the height,
the shadow will not be offset to the left or right
but it will be pushed down a little bit by two pixels.
And you can play around with these values
to find the shadow positioning you want.
Now, what you also need to set is the shadowRadius.
This basically controls how much the shadow expands,
so to say.
And here I'll choose six because again here,
you provide a value which is a number
and you can play around with that value
to see the impact of different numbers on the shadow
that is created.
Last but not least, you can add a shadowOpacity
to control how transparent a shadow is.
For example, here, I'll set this to 0.25.
But you can play around with this value as well
to see how that influences the effect of a shadow
and how strong a shadow is.
Now, with those settings here, if we save everything,
we now have a nice little shadow
behind the box on iOS as well.
And we have the elevation-related shadow on Android.
Now, if I would, for example,
crank up the shadowOpacity to one,
you would see that the shadow is much stronger on iOS now.
So that's what I meant.
You can play around with that
to get a feeling for how this shadow works.
Here, I just wanna have a little bit of a shadow
and therefore, I'll set it up like this.
And that's another major step.
The app still doesn't work.
The buttons don't work,
the text input does nothing.
But we learnt something new about styling.
We learnt how to add shadows
and we gained more practice on how to set up styling
on our own Components
combined with those core React Native Components.
And since this is something you will do all the time
when building React Native apps,
this is, of course, crucial to understand.
And now you also know how you can add shadows.