So let's now dig a bit deeper
into this text input field
and learn how we can configure it.
We already set a max length, but I also, for example,
wanna control which kind of characters can be entered there,
or to be precise, I wanna control which keyboard I get
when I get a keyboard on my mobile device.
Because at the moment, as I show you,
we get the regular keyboard
with all those regular characters,
and that's not what I want.
Now, text input allows you to control which keyboard
is opened by the device.
And it can be controlled with the keyboard type prop.
Now, this keyboard type prop takes a bunch of values.
And it's worth a look at the official docs
to understand which values are supported on which platform.
If you take a look at the keyboard type prop description
in the official docs for the text input,
you'll learn that there are a couple of values
that work across platforms.
And then there are values which are only available
on one of the platforms.
So for example, URL is supported on iOS devices,
but not on Android.
Now here, I wanna use the number-pad though,
which works across platforms,
because this will open up a keyboard
that only shows numbers, which is is what I want here.
So therefore here all set keyboard type two number pad.
Now, there also are a couple of other properties we can set.
And you see that there are a lot of props that are supported
and definitely feel free to browse through them
to understand which options you have
when working with text inputs.
Here I, for example, also wanna set
the auto capitalized option to none.
It's not too important when working with numbers,
but if this would contain regular text,
this would ensure that it's not auto capitalized.
Again, that's not really important here,
but I wanna show that this kind of prop exists.
We also have a auto correct prop that allows us
to turn auto correction on or off.
Because it could, for example, be super annoying
if you have a field where users should enter their email,
and you have auto capitalization
and auto correction turned on.
We all know these input fields where your email address
gets corrected and the first character gets capitalized,
and you have to fix it thereafter.
You can avoid such bad user experiences
with props like this.
Again, for this input where we only expect numbers,
this is not really needed.
Now with that, if we save everything and I go back,
you see immediately that on Android,
we now get a different keyboard which only shows us numbers.
And it's the same here on iOS.
And that is a huge step forward,
because that is the behavior we want for this input field.
And that's of course pretty nice to have.
Therefore as a next step, let's leave this input field
and let's work on these buttons before we then start working
on the layout of this box by making sure
that these elements are laid out of bit nicer.