So let's get back to this button.
At the moment, it isn't really a button.
It's just a View with Text inside of it.
Now, to make it a button,
we need to add a component that allows us
to react to presses, to taps.
And react-native has a couple of components that do that.
For example, the touchable components.
I briefly mentioned them before,
in the past, these were the main components you would use
for adding touch support to elements.
But nowadays, the Pressable component is recommended.
Therefore, I will use Pressable here.
And we can wrap Pressable around our View and Text here.
So, we can create a Pressable component here.
Use it in JSX like this,
and wrap it around the View and Text.
And Pressable has a onPress prop,
which takes a function as a value,
which ensures that this function that we pass to onPress
will be executed whenever the button is pressed in the end.
Whenever anything inside of Pressable is tapped.
Now to show you how this works,
I'll add a little dummy function here, pressHandler.
And in there, I will just console.log, Pressed!, like this.
And I wanna connect this pressHandler
to this button by pointing at pressHandler like this.
As you learned before,
we're not executing this function here,
we're just pointing at it.
So that it will be executed for us,
when such a press occurs.
With that, if we save this,
we cannot press these texts.
And we don't get any feedback.
At least, not right now.
We will add some feedback soon.
But in the console, we can see that indeed,
we did press these buttons successfully,
And that we listened to those events,
which is another big step forward.
But of course,
having some styling and some feedback,
would be nice as well.
And there, for that's what I wanna work on next.
Now, for adding styling,
I again, will import the style sheet
because that is how we do define our styles,
typically, when working with react-native.
And we can add such a styles constant,
which is a style sheet created
with this style sheet create method.
And now, in this method here,
we can define our different styles.
Now, I want to have a couple of different button styles,
but I wanna start with the main style
for this container that I have around my text.
So my main style for this View.
So I'll name this, container.
And in here, I wanna set a backgroundColor.
And the backgroundColor I wanna set,
is the same color I have here.
So I will actually copy this color
from the StartGameScreen, and use this here, for my button.
Now, of course,
if I use the same color as I have it here
for the background, it won't be visible.
Therefore, to work around that,
I'll change that backgroundColor
in the StartGameScreen a little bit.
And simply make it darker, let's say.
By switching to this hex code, 4e0329.
Now, we have a different backgroundColor for the button.
And I also wanna make sure that I have rounded corners.
And not just some rounded corners,
but, essentially, no corners.
But instead, a nice little half circle
on the left and right of the button.
This can be achieved by giving this button
a huge borderRadius.
For example, with a value of 28.
I also wanna have some padding in there.
And I wanna have different padding to the top, and bottom,
and left, and right.
So I will set paddingVertical, let's say, to eight.
And that's the padding, the distance inside
of the container to the top and to the bottom.
And I will add paddingHorizontal.
So to the left and right, of 16.
So that we have more padding to the left, and to the right
than to the top, and to the bottom.
In addition on Android, I want to add a shadow.
Only on Android, not on iOS.
You could also add an iOS shadow.
You learned how that works a few minutes ago.
But here I want to add a shadow only on Android
by setting the elevation to two.
If we save all of this,
we don't see anything
because we need to apply this styling.
So, we can go to this View,
add the style prop and point at styles.container.
And with that, if we save this.
Now, we got these buttons here.
Of course, they're still not super pretty
but we're getting here.
But we also need to style the text now
because the text doesn't look good.
We also might want to add
a little bit of margin around the button,
so that there is some spacing between the buttons.
Hence, I will start with that,
and actually add a margin
in all directions of four pixels.
And I will define a second style object,
which I'll name, buttonText.
And therefore, actually,
I'll name this here, buttonContainer, to be consistent.
And my button text will receive a color of white,
so that the text is white.
And I wanna center the text,
which can be achieved by using textAlign center, like this.
And what's very important,
you have to define those styles on a style object
that's directly applied to this text component
because as you learned before in this course,
if you would add textAlign center,
and this color prop on the button container,
it would not affect the text inside of the container.
Because there is no inheritance
in this react-native styling approach.
It looks like CSS, but it isn't CSS.
So therefore, now, we can add this new style,
the buttonText style to this text component.
And since I changed the name of the container,
we also should update the name up here,
and point at the buttonContainer style object here.
With that, If we save this,
and we go back, this is centered and already
looks a bit nicer.
We can also see that there is a slight shadow on Android,
whereas, there is none on iOS.
Now, what we don't have at all is any feedback,
when a button is pressed.
And that would be nice to have.
Now, I did show you how you can add such feedback before.
You can add feedback on Android add a nice ripple effect
by adding the android_ripple prop.
And as the name suggests,
this only has an effect on Android.
But there, you can pass an object to android_ripple.
And then on this object, you can set the color
that should be applied when this button is pressed.
So the ripple color that will be used.
And ripple is this little wave effect,
which you get when pressing a button on Android.
So here I'll set this to a color,
and I'll use the main button color here.
But of course I'll use a slightly darker tint here.
Maybe, like this switching to the hex code, 640233.
With that, if we save that.
On Android, we should have a nice little ripple effect.
But actually, if you press the button,
you will see a slight effect outside of the button.
But not inside of it.
So that is not working as intended.
And I'm showing this on purpose because this can be
a common problem when building custom buttons on Android,
or with react-native in general.
This is a common problem to run into,
that the ripple effect.
This outside of the button, for example.
And therefore I'm showing this here,
so that you have a solution for this common problem.
Because the solution is to restructure this JSX code.
What you should do,
is move your View outside of the Pressable element.
So that Pressable is inside of View.
And then we also need to add a new styling object
and restructure our styling objects a little bit.
I will actually add a buttonOuterContainer here, like this.
And rename this to buttonInnerContainer.
Because we will work with two containers now.
One container will be that View that holds the Pressable,
and the Pressable will be the inner container
that holds the text.
And we need to distribute our styles across
these two containers to make sure
that they work together correctly.
And what you should do now is that on the outer container,
you add this borderRadius.
You don't add it on the inner container.
You add it on the outer container instead.
In addition, it's that outer container
that receives the margin, like this,
which should make sense because it will be
the outer container that will be closest to our elements
that are used side by side or close to the button
when you're using this button component in other components.
Now in addition, on this outer container,
you should add overflow hidden,
which is a property you might also know
from web development.
What this will do is it will ensure that if any effect
or any styling from inside that container
would go outside of that container, it's clipped,
it's not shown.
So for example,
if the ripple effect would go outside of this container,
it will be clipped and it will not be visible.
Now on the inner container,
we want to have the backgroundColor.
And we wanna have padding and the elevation.
Now, we can add this OuterContainer class here,
to this View, which is our outer container.
And on this Pressable element, we can also add a style prop.
And here we wanna add the buttonInnerContainer style.
When we do that and save everything,
the buttons look as they did before,
but now, you will see that the ripple effect
is inside of these buttons.
You have to watch really closely and you can,
of course, temporarily switch
to a totally different color
to make it a bit easier to spot this effect.
Now, you see the ripple effect is inside of the button.
And I'll switch back to the other color now,
because I just wanted to show you that this works.
So working with such combined containers is something
you often need to do when building custom buttons.
And now, here you see one example approach of building
a clean button combining such a outer
and such a inner container.
Now, of course at the moment though,
this is nice on Android, but it has no effect on iOS.
Because this ripple effect is only available on Android.
So if you wanna provide some visual feedback on iOS as well,
which we typically want to.
We have to set up a dedicated style for iOS.
And for this dedicated style,
I'll add another styling object
in the primary button component file.
And I'll name it, pressed,
because this should become active
when the button is pressed.
And what I wanna do in that case is I wanna set
an opacity of 0.75.
Opacity makes the element,
on which you apply this style transparent.
And here, I will make it 75% opaque, so 25% transparent.
Opacity wants a value between zero and one,
which then is translated into percentage.
So one is 100%, zero is 0%.
Now this pressed style here,
this object should be applied to Pressable
when the button is pressed.
And for this, we can changed this style prop a little bit.
Because as I as I mentioned before,
the style prop for this Pressable component
takes either a styling object
as we're currently passing it in,
or it takes a function, for example, an arrow function here,
which will be called automatically by react-native,
whenever the Pressable is pressed.
So whenever the press event occurs.
And then, this style object receives some data
about the press event,
which is an object with essentially one property.
And therefore, we can also use object destructuring here
to pull out that one property.
And that one property is a pressed property.
And this name is not up to you.
This is a property named pressed,
which is part of that object
which is automatically passed into this function
by react-native for this Pressable component.
And pressed is a Boolean which is true,
if we currently are pressing the button
or the element in general, and false otherwise.
So now, pressed can be used here
in the body of this arrow function
to determine which style objects should be applied.
And for this I'll check,
if press is truthy,
in which case I wanna apply different styles
than it's not true.
If it's not true,
after the colon here,
I wanna apply the default button in our container style.
But if it is true, then I wanna apply multiple styles.
I do wanna apply the default button styles,
but I also want to add my pressed style object here.
And this can be achieved by passing an array of styles.
And in general, in any place where you use the style prop,
even if it's not Pressable component.
You can pass style objects like this.
But you can also pass arrays of style objects.
And in that case,
all the style objects in that array
would be considered by react-native.
So here, I then want to add
my buttonInnerContainer style here.
But I also want to add the press style.
So, if pressed is true,
then this array of style objects
will be applied to the button.
If it's false, this single style object will be applied.
And with that, if we save this.
We now got this feedback here as well.
Because we got some transparency going on,
when we click this
On Android, we now also have this effect.
And for the moment that is fine for me here,
you will learn in the next section,
how you can differentiate between platforms
and how you can write or execute different code
for different platforms.
So in the next section,
you will learn how you can disable
this styling behavior for Android,
and only use it for iOS.
For the moment, we will use the same effect
for both platforms.
So we will add this opacity, when the button is tapped.