So slowly, this is taking shape
but of course it's still not beautiful
and especially the layout here is not great.
So therefore that is what I wanna work on next.
And as a first step it would be nice to
position the elements inside of this input box
in a different way.
The text input, for example,
should be centered in the middle.
And whilst we could have the buttons beneath each other
like this, I want to have them sit next to each other
in one row because they don't need to be that wide.
They don't need that much horizontal space.
Hence it's time to go back to the code.
And of course, just as a side note,
as always, feel free to pause the video
and try implementing this on your own.
You will need to work with flexbox
and you learned the fundamentals about flexbox already.
So definitely feel free to enhance the layout on your own
before following along with me
where we will then enhance it together.
Now, here is what I will do though.
In start game screen,
we have this view which holds this entire input area.
And this view has this input container style object
attached to it.
So inside this input container style definition here
I wanna control how the elements in there are laid out.
And since I wanna center this text input,
we have to add some flex properties that will take care
about centering.
And the positioning of elements in a flexbox is controlled
by using justify content
and align items.
Now justify content will position elements
along the main axis which by default is top to bottom
because the default flex direction
with React Native is column.
And align items will position items along the cross axis
which is the opposite of the main axis.
So at the moment, as I just said,
the default is flex direction column.
So justify content will position items
along this top to bottom axis and therefore here,
it doesn't matter too much what we set here.
We could set this to center
and temporarily remove align items
and it wouldn't really have any effect
because the main axis, top to bottom, is occupied
by the elements already.
And since this overall container is not higher
than the space taken up by the elements inside of it,
there is no extra vertical space to distribute.
That's why this doesn't matter too much.
Now, what does matter though, is align items
which positions item along the cross axis.
And the cross axis in this case is left to right
because the main axis is top to bottom.
And here we wanna center the elements
so that the text input element is centered.
And this can be achieved by setting this to center.
If we do this, indeed, this is centered and automatically as
a side effect, the buttons got smaller
because before the default was stretch,
which ensured that the elements would stretch out
to take the full available width.
The text input element doesn't stretch because
we set a dedicated width on it.
So we restricted the width of the element and didn't allow
it to stretch.
Now, if we change this to center,
we also don't stretch the buttons anymore,
which is why they only take the space they need
to fit the text inside of them.
Now that is okay for the moment,
because as I don't wanna position the buttons
like this, anyways, instead, as I said before,
I personally would prefer them to sit in a row
next to each other.
Now, for this to happen, we need to encapsulate
these two buttons into a separate container.
As long as they are directly in the same container
as text input, there is no way of positioning them
in a different way but we can wrap them in an extra view.
And now it's this view, which is in the same container
as the text input but the buttons are
in a separate container.
If we save this, this has no immediate effect other than
the button size is changing again
because they are now in a new flexbox container
because every view constructs a new flexbox container -
that is something you must know - and they,
they stretch again.
We would have to change the styling of that view to,
for example, center them again to get rid of the stretching,
if we wanted to.
Now, I don't wanna get rid of the stretching
but I do want to change the flex direction to row
so that the buttons are next to each other
instead of beneath each other.
And for this, I'll add a new styling property here
in my style sheet which I'll name buttons container.
Of course, this name is up to you as well but here
I'll set the flex direction to row
because now the buttons should sit in a row.
And if we do that and we add this to this view here,
we add styles.buttonsContainer as a style to this view,
then indeed, they are next to each other.
Of course the button now have different sizes again,
and an easy way of fixing that is to, again, encapsulate
every button into a new view.
But now every button receives its own view.
And the idea behind this is that now we have new
flexbox containers where every flexbox container
contains one button and this flexbox container here
will again have a flex direction of column
and the button will stretch in there.
And the two flexbox containers we have here
can now distribute the available space provided by this view
which is the overall container for these buttons.
Now, just by adding these views nothing changes though,
because by default, a view takes only as much space
as is needed by its content.
But you also know what you can do about that.
You can add flex one to enforce that a view
takes as much space as available.
For this, we can add another style object,
the button container
which only holds one button and add flex one to it.
And this style object can now be assigned
to these two views here.
So here we add style, styles button container like this
and we do the same on this second view.
And with that, these two buttons now have the same size
and they distribute the available space amongst each other.
And I was showing this to you so that we A, have
a layout that we like but also B,
so that we learn more about React Native
and how we can create layouts.
And indeed it is super common and normal that you nest
views into each other and that you combine different
flexbox properties on different view levels
to achieve the final layout you want.
And here, I would say this layout doesn't look too bad
for this input container.
Later, we will make sure that the buttons don't look equal
but for a start, this doesn't look too bad.
Now, I would say it's time to work on the background
before we then finally start adding more logic to this game.