So as a next step,
I wanna make sure that we have a nice background
behind this input element.
And for a start, I wanna add a nice little color
in the back, which we will then change to a gradient
which we will then change to a background image
plus a gradient.
But let's start with a single background color.
You learned before that there are different ways
of setting that.
You can, for example, go to App Json
to this configuration file
and add a backgroundColor property here
and set this to a hex code that will then be applied
as a background color to the screen.
And this would be a fine way of doing that.
What I will do instead though is,
I will add a background color with help of a view.
And for this I'll go to app.js
because once I add more screens
they will actually still end up in this root app component.
So these different screens which I will add later
will still share this app component as a root.
So therefore any background color we set here
around this View, around this screen, I mean,
will be applied to all screens later,
once we start adding them to app.
Therefore here I will add a View
around the StartGameScreen, like this,
of course for a View to work,
we need to import it from react-native though,
otherwise it's not available.
So now we got this View here around our StartGameScreen.
Now we can add some styling to this View.
And for a start,
I will add my screen or my rootScreen
whatever you wanna name it, style object here.
And I'll set a backgroundColor
which should be a nice yellow color.
And I'll pick that yellow color, which I chose here
for my input element in the StartGameScreen.
I'll use that same color here.
Now we can apply this root screen style to this View here
by using styles.rootScreen.
Now, if we save this, it only covers this part at the top.
And do you know why?
Because it only takes up the space
it must take up by default
and that's really important to memorize.
Views only take as much space
as they need to fit their content into themselves.
And the content of this root View is this StartGameScreen
which in turn is just this input area.
So it's this input box
plus the margin reserved by this input box.
Now, if I wanna apply this color to the entire screen
what can we do?
Well, we can use flex: 1.
If we add flex: 1 here, this container, this View,
which receives this style
will take up as much space as available.
So by adding flex: 1 here, now everything is yellow.
So that's how we can add such a background color
with a View.
It's a nice first step, but as a next step
we will switch to a gradient instead.