So how can we add a gradient in the background here?
Well, for this we'll utilize expo.
If you search for expo linear gradient,
you will find that expo,
this extra tool we're using to simplify the process
of building React Native apps,
this tool, and the team and company behind it
provides an extra package called expo linear gradient
that gives us a component, which we can use
in our code to display a linear gradient.
So, what we have to do here is open a new tab
in our terminal here
so that we can install this extra package,
and we should install it with expo install
not with npm install, you could do this as well
but by using expo install,
expo, this tool which we're using,
will ensure that a fitting version
is installed into this project.
So it will take a look
at the version of expo you are using in this project,
and it will automatically install a dependency version
that works well with that expo version.
Therefore we'll use expo install here
and install the expo-linear-gradient package like this.
If you hit enter,
this will execute npm install behind the scenes
but as mentioned, it picks a fitting version.
Now, once it's done, you can close this terminal window
and keep the npm start process running.
And now we can import LinearGradient
from expo linear gradient.
And as always, the official docs are a great place
to understand how you can use this component
in case you're not sure.
So now we imported this LinearGradient component.
And with that imported,
we can replace this view with LinearGradient.
And therefore, of course, we can get rid of that view import
because we're not using the view component
in this app component anymore.
Now LinearGradient takes a style prop,
and on that style, we still wanna set flex: 1 because
the gradient also should take all the available space
but we won't set a background color anymore
because the idea behind that gradient
is that we have a gradient between multiple colors.
And we set those multiple colors
with help of the colors prop that is supported
by this LinearGradient component.
This colors prop takes an array
which takes all the colors you want to use in your gradient.
That could be two colors.
It could be five colors.
Again, take a look at the official documentation
to learn more about all these supported properties
and how you can configure this gradient.
Now, the two colors I want to use here are, in the end,
the yellow, which we used for the input,
so I will pick this.
But as a first color, I want to use a different color.
I want to use this plum color
which I used for the background of my input container.
So I will grab this as a first color here,
separate these items with a comma,
and with that, if you save this,
you have this nice gradient here in the background.
Of course, with that added,
to make sure that there is a higher contrast
between the background and this container,
this input container,
we could go back to this container
and pick a even darker plum color here, like 3b021f.
And with that now this is darker
and stands out more from the background.
But this is how we can add a gradient.
And thanks to this extra expo package,
it's really not difficult.