Now having this gradient here is nice.
Certainly perfect
if we would be building a tequila sunrise app,
but as a last step for finishing this background,
I actually wanna overlay a background image
above this gradient, but below the upper elements on the UI.
So below this input container, for example.
Now a background image can be added with another component
that's actually already built into react native.
And that's the image background component.
Now we learned about the image component before already,
image background is quite similar
but as the names suggests, it renders a image
in the background instead of the foreground.
Now I wanna have that above the linear gradient
so that the linear gradient shimmers through the image
but below all the other UI elements.
So therefore now here I'll add image background
like this and wrap my other content with it
so that the other content is inside the background image
and therefore above the background image visually.
And now on this image background,
just as on the normal image we have to add a source.
And this source should provide the image
that should be displayed here.
Now for this, I prepared an image for you
and I will add a images folder here in the assets folder
into which you should store this image.
You find the image attached
it's this background PNG file.
And this image looks like this, just a couple of dices.
By the way, I took this image from Unsplash.
And of course I do wanna give proper attribution, therefore.
And there, if you search for dices,
I think you find this image.
So this image was not taken or created by me.
It's from Unsplash, Unsplash is a great resource
for finding free images.
And you can take this image here, or another image
from Unsplash, if you wanna use it in your app.
So now with the image stored in the assets images folder,
we should point at it.
And just as with the normal image component,
we don't just pass a path as a string here,
instead, we use this special require function
and to then construct a path to the image.
Now, here I'm in app JS.
So I don't need to go up one level first.
Instead, I am already next to the assets folder.
So with dot slash, we tell react native that we're looking
for a folder that's in the same folder as this app JS file.
And then it's the assets folder
there, the images folder
and in there, the background PNG file like this.
Now image background also takes another prop
which is very important.
And that's the resize mode.
It's very likely that the image you're using is too small
or too big for the screen size
of the device on which the app is running.
And resize mode controls how the image will be resized
if it doesn't have this same dimensions
as the underlying device.
Here, you got multiple options
which you might know from web development
because there you have similar options
when working with images,
with background images to be precise
and I will use cover, which will make sure
that the image always covers up all the available space
but not by distorting it, but instead by zooming in or out.
So that's a nice setting when it comes
to adjusting the size of the image.
Now what's also important
is that I will add the style prop to image background.
And here I also will point at a root screen
so that this also takes up all the available space.
It's not enough that the gradient does this.
This image should also take
up all the available space that is made available
by its parent component.
So by the gradient, in this case.
If you now save this
here's the image, but the gradient is gone.
Now you might just want an image.
And in that case, this perfect.
But if you also want the gradient back,
we now have to make this image transparent.
Not entirely transparent, of course, but to some extent
so that the gradient shimmers through the image.
And this can be achieved with another special prop
that we can set on image background.
And that's the image style.
Now we already added style here.
But what you have to understand is that image background,
this component provided by react native
is actually under the hood, a combination of components.
We saw that before in the React Native GitHub repository
where you can see all the React Native source code
when we had a look at the button.
If you have a look at the image background JS file here,
you will see how that works internally.
And you will see that it's a combination
of a view and the normal image component.
Now, the style which we set here,
this prop is added to this view.
We can see that here, the style is set.
The inner image can also receive some styling though.
And here on this inner image we wanna add some transparency
because the view is transparent anyways,
it doesn't have a background color by default
but of course the image, well shows the image.
So therefore,
now we can add the background image style object
and add the opacity property to give this image an opacity
of let's say 0.15.
So that would be 85% transparency.
So almost entirely transparent.
And it's now this style property
which we will add as a image style.
So QD image that's inside of this view
that is exposed by image background.
If we save this, now we have the image and the gradient
and now we have a combination of gradient and image
which I think looks quite nice.
Of course, as always, feel free to pick different styles.
But I am quite happy with that background.
And I would say after all that styling and layouting
and all these things on which we work thus far,
it's now time to dive into some actual logic.
Because up to this point, we have a nice user interface
but nothing happens when we tap those buttons
or when we enter something into the input field.
And it's time to change that.