So let's start working
on the Game Logic now.
And this includes fetching the user input,
resetting it if we click this button
and moving on to the actual game screen,
if we confirm the input.
Though, we also wanna validate the input.
For example, we wanna make sure
that if it's empty, we don't proceed
to the game screen.
That would not be the behavior we want.
Instead in that case,
I wanna show a little alert
that tells the user that a value
must be entered here.
In addition, I also wanna make sure
that you can't enter,
let's say zero or minus one as a value here.
So we'll also have to make sure
that this is not possible.
Now, how can we fetch
and handle the user input with good old state?
Because again, it is just a React component
and now we wanna fetch some user input
as we did it before in the course already.
And using state for that is
of course the standard React way of doing that.
Therefore, we should import the useState hook
from React so that we can manage state
in this functional component.
And here I then have my state for managing or
for getting this entered value.
And therefore I will name this enteredValue
or actually enteredNumber,
since it should be a number.
And we have the setEnteredNumber state updating function,
and here out of the box,
this is an empty string.
Now it's a empty string
instead of a number like zero
because actually I will bind this,
queue the text input
and even if you have "number-pad" here,
what you will get as a value
will always be a string.
It will always be of type string
even if the text is a number,
even if the text contains a number
and that's the same as in the web.
So what we get from TextInput
will always be a string.
We can of course convert it thereafter.
But since I plan on binding this state
to the TextInput,
I also wanna manage a string here.
Now with bind this to the TextInput,
I mean that I wanna set the value prop
on TextInput
and set this equal to enteredNumber.
I do this so
that we can change the state
from anywhere in this app.
For example, when the Reset button is clicked
to reset it to an empty string
and such state changes are then reflected
in TextInput.
That's why I'm setting the value prop
to the state.
But of course, we also wanna update
this enteredNumber state
whenever the user types
into the TextInput field.
And for this, we can add a function,
the numberInputHandler, for example,
which should be executed upon every keystroke
which can be achieved
by adding the onChangeText prop here
to this TextInput.
And then we point at this numberInputHandler
and this will in the end execute this function
on every keystroke that is done
on this TextInput.
And conveniently,
we automatically get the inputText
or the enteredText passed into this function
by React Native.
So we automatically get a value
for this parameter because React Native
will invoke this function for us
for every keystroke on the TextInput.
And in here I'll then set my enteredNumber
to the enteredText.
So I'll update my state with the text entered
into this input field.
Now that is all nice.
That's a good first step.
The second step of course is
to connect this Confirm button.
For this, I'll add another function here
which I'll name confirmInputHandler.
And the idea here is
that we then check the current state
that we have, we check if it's a number
and if it's greater or equal than one
and smaller or equal than 99
because I only wanna allow numbers in that range.
And then we proceed to the next screen
if it's valid and we show an alert, otherwise.
Now let's first connect this
to the Button though.
And for this, our PrimaryButton
should expose a prop that does allow us
to pass in a function.
And if we have a look at the PrimaryButton,
then at the moment we don't use any props
in here that would take a function.
Instead here, our Pressable does have the onPress prop
and we point at the the pressHandler
but there, we just log to the console.
Now I want to make this button reusable.
I want to make this custom component reusable.
And I wanna add a prop that allows components
that use this Button component to pass
in a function that will be executed upon a press.
And therefore here I'll also pull out another prop
from that incoming props object,
which I'll name onPress.
Now, this name is up to you
because this is your component and your props,
but it makes sense to use onPress I'd say
because we know that we want a function
that should be invoked
when that button is pressed.
So that is a name that makes sense to me
but it's not a must use
because it is your component.
In pressHandler, we can then execute onPress
or we get rid of pressHandler
and we just forward that value
which we receive on the onPress prop
to the onPress prop provided by Pressable.
Now this name here on the left is not up to you.
That's a prop provided by Pressable.
But this here is up to you
because this is your prop.
And now we simply forward the value we receive
on the onPress prop
to the onPress prop of Pressable.
Yeah, it's a lot of presses
but it's hopefully clear how that works.
Again, this is standard React,
nothing React Native specific here.
With that we can go back
to the start game screen,
and now we can add the onPress prop here
on the PrimaryButton.
And if you chose a different name here
and here,
you have to use that different name here now.
But I'm using onPress so I will use this name
and here I point at the confirmInputHandler.
So a pointer at this function is now passed
to the PrimaryButton or to be precise
to this instance of the PrimaryButton.
And there it's forwarded as a value
to the onPress prop on Pressable.
And therefore, whenever we press this button,
this confirmInputHandler function
will be executed.
And in that function,
we can now add all our validation logic
and show an alert
if an invalid value is provided.