So let's now add
this input validation logic here.
For this I'll first of all,
create a chosenNumber constant,
where I wanna convert the enteredNumber of state,
that I have here, which is a string to a number.
And this conversion can be performed
by using the built in parseInt function.
This function is globally available in JavaScript,
in React Native apps,
just as it is globally available in the browser.
So you can't just call it like this,
and to parseInt, you pass the entered number.
This will convert this string to a number,
or at least it will try to convert it.
This would fail if something is entered
that is not convertible to a number,
like non-digit characters.
Therefore, I next wanna add a if statement here,
where I check if this is maybe not a number,
if the conversion failed.
This can be done
with the built in isNot a number function,
which is also globally available,
and to which I passed chosenNumber.
This will return true,
if chosenNumber is not a number,
so if the conversion failed.
Now, I also wanna add a couple of other checks,
because if this check fails,
or one of the other checks which I am about to add,
in that case, I wanna show an alert.
Show alert, that's what we'll do soon.
So the other checks I wanna perform,
are separated by an or,
because I wanna show the alert if this is not a number,
or if chosenNumber is a number,
but it's smaller or equal than zero.
So if it's zero or smaller than that,
that would also be invalid,
and I wanna show an alert in that case as well.
Or I wanna show an alert,
if chosenNumber is greater than 99.
If it's too big, I also wanna show an alert.
Now I also wanna return thereafter
to make sure that this function,
does not continue its execution,
if we make it into if statement.
So that we cancel this function's execution.
But how can we now show such an alert?
That would also be interesting.
And here React Native got us covered.
React Native exposes and alert API.
Now, this is now not a component which we display,
but instead alert is an object
that holds a method that we can call to show an alert.
To be precise, the alert method.
It also has the prompt method,
which would display a dialogue,
where we can enter a value.
But here I'm interested in the alert method,
which shows a Dialog which we can only confirm
by pressing a button.
Now this alert method here,
wants a couple of arguments.
The first one is the title,
the second one will be the message,
and the third one allows us to configure the buttons
that will be part of that alert.
And this alert method by the way,
will create a Native Alert Dialog,
as you will see in a couple of minutes.
So it will use the Native Alert API,
built into the IOS and Android platforms.
So here I'll say "Invalid Number" as a title,
and then as a message I'll say,
Number has to be a number, between one and 99.
And then as a last step,
we can pass an array,
where we configure the buttons that should be shown.
And you can actually add multiple buttons to the alert,
but here I will only add one.
And the button is defined,
by adding an object to this array.
And in this object,
every button then has a text,
which is the caption of this button.
In this case 'Okay'
And it has a style.
And this style can be default, destructive, or cancel,
and this will basically influence
which text color is used,
if the text is bold, things like this.
And here I will use destructive,
but feel free to play around with these different styles,
to see how the look changes as you change the style.
Last but not least,
you also can add onPress property,
which allows you to point at a function
that should be executed,
when that button is clicked.
So when that button on this alert is clicked.
And I do wanna do that,
because I wanna reset the input
once this button is clicked.
So that if an invalid value was provided,
we show the alert,
and once the alert is confirmed and handled by the user,
I wanna reset the input,
to get rid of the invalid input value.
For this we can add a new function,
Maybe here, the exact position doesn't matter,
which is the resetInputHandler.
And here I will set my entered number to an empty string.
To set this back to an empty string,
which also was our initial state.
And since we bind enteredNumber,
to the value of text input,
if we change enteredNumber,
if we change this state as we do it here,
the value in the input will be changed.
So therefore, now we can point at resetInputHandler,
like this, and now the input will be reset,
whenever this Dialog is confirmed.
Now last but not least,
I will also connect this reset button,
to this newly added resetInputHandler function,
by adding the onPress prop,
and pointing at resetInputHandler here as well.
This is not related to the alert,
but it's also something we need to do.
So now we should show an alert,
if the value is invalid,
otherwise, I'll just log valid number for the moment.
In the future,
we will of course make sure that in this case,
we move on to the next game screen.
But now with all these changes applied,
if we save this,
and we maybe reload all our apps to make sure
that all the changes are applied to these simulators.
If I try to submit an empty input,
I get this alert.
And you see I have this red text here
because I used a destructive style,
and I get this alert
which has to default iOS alert look and feel,
because it is default iOS alert.
On Android, I get an alert
that has to default Android Dialog look.
Now, if I enter minus one here,
I also get such an alert.
If I enter a valid number,
nothing happens though.
Instead then, we see valid number locked in the console.
If I click reset, this is reset.
And if I entered something invalid,
and I click okay on this Dialog,
it's also cleared as you can see.
So this all works as expected,
now we're fetching this user input.
Now we can make sure,
that we then move on to a new screen.
Because at the moment we only have one screen,
and that's this screen here.
Which is also not entirely finished,
but good enough for now.