So now that we can enter
and confirm a number,
let's make sure that we are able to switch to a game screen
once we get a number.
And for this, we already have this game screen JS file
but at the moment it's empty.
Therefore it makes sense to also add a functional component
in there because of course this new screen
will also be component in the end.
So we export this component here,
and then here for a start I will add some text
where I just say Game screen.
And we have to import this text component
from react-native of course, otherwise it's not available.
Now this screen here should be displayed
as soon as the user picked a number.
How can we do that?
Well, later in the course in the navigation section,
we will learn about a third party package
that helps with navigating between different screens.
But we can also navigate without that package
and to keep things simpler for the moment,
I will show you how you can do this
without any external dependencies.
Because in the end you just have to keep in mind
that we can use standard react tools like state
to change what's visible on the screen.
And we just wanna swap this StartGameScreen here
in the app component with the GameScreen
as even as we have a number.
So all we have to do for that
is manage some extra state in this app component
that basically keeps track of the fact
whether we have a number or not.
So, we can import useState
from react here in the app component,
and then we wanna register some state here With useState,
and that state that I do wanna register here
in the end is simply the number picked by the user.
So the userNumber for example
which we can set with this state updating function.
And initially this is null.
We could also set it to zero but I will send it to null
so undefined to be precise
to make it clear that we have no number initially.
Now we can add a function.
Let's say the startGameHandler or the pickedNumberHandler,
whatever name you wanna use.
And here I expect to get the pickedNumber.
So the number picked by the user,
and once the number was picked and confirmed
we know that the game should start.
So here we get the picked number once it is confirmed,
or at least that's the plan.
And then here we can set the user number
to that picked number.
Now, why is this helpful?
Because now we can use this userNumber state here
to either render the StartGameScreen
if we have no user number yet,
or render the game screen if we do have a user number.
So for this we can import the GameScreen here
from ./screens/GameScreen.
And then here I'll add a helper variable
called screen which is the StartGameScreen by default.
But I'll then add a if check here
directly in my component function,
and therefore this if check will be re-executed
whenever this component function is re-executed
which will be the case whenever state changes.
And in here I'll check if userNumber if this is truthy,
which will not be the case if it's null or undefined,
which it is initially.
But if it's truthy so not null and not zero
which can't be the case because we validate for this
in the StartGameScreen.
So if it is a valid number,
then we'll make it into this if block
and in that case I'll set the screen variable here
to the GameScreen.
And then we just have to render this screen variable here
in the JSX code instead of the hard-coded StartGameScreen.
So now we either display StartGameScreen or GameScreen.
Of course at the moment though pickedNumberHandler
will never execute which is a problem.
Now we do wanna execute whenever a number
is confirmed inside of StartGameScreen.
And again we can use props for that
and we can pass a pointer to this function
to StartGameScreen with help of props
so that this function can be executed
from inside the StartGameScreen component.
And this is a standard pattern in react
which we used before with the primary button
and the onPress prop we accepted there
and which we will now use again with StartGameScreen.
So here we could have a onPickNumber,
or onConfirmNumber, whatever you want.
I'll go with onPickNumber.
It's your component, so the prop name is up to you.
And here I will point at pickedNumberHandler.
Now we just have to accept
and use this prop inside of StartGameScreen
and therefore in this component
we can use props here or object destructuring
to automatically pull out this prop
from the incoming props object.
And then here we wanna execute that
whenever a number is picked and confirmed.
And that is case in the confirmInputHandler
after this if Check where we currently log to the console.
Instead of logging to the console
I now wanna execute onPickNumber
and very important I wanna forward the number
that has been picked.
Because in AppJS I expect to get this pickedNumber.
So in StartGameScreen
when we call the function received on this prop
which will be the pickedNumberHandler function,
there we now wanna pass the picked number
as a argument to that function.
So we wanna pass the chosen number which is our converted
and validated number to this function.
Well, and with that, if we save everything.
If I enter something invalid
we still get the same behavior as before,
but if I enter something valid here,
this disappears and I'm on the game screen
as you can see here in the top left corner.
Of course the game screen has absolutely no layout
and therefore it looks horrible
but we successfully switched the screen.
And now we can build up on this
and start working on that game screen.