So let's start working
on this game screen now.
And we got a couple of things that should be added there.
For example, the main thing that's happening
on this screen is that our phone,
so the program in the end, the app, is guessing a number
and then we have controls to tell the program
if the number is too high or too low.
Therefore, we definitely need to output the guessed number
and we need to derive the guessed number as a first step.
Then we need to output the controls
that allow us to provide feedback to the program
and then we need to recalculate a new number
based on that feedback.
In addition, I wanna log all the rounds we had in the game,
so I wanna log the different guesses that have been made.
Therefore, here in the game screen,
we will definitely need a view to group
all these different UI elements that we need.
So we'll have this main view
and then in there, I wanna have a text where I say
opponent's guess, this is just a title,
but I want to have this kind of title here,
then below that, I want to have the actual guess
being output and yes, we can't add text like this in a view
but this is just a placeholder.
We'll add a nice component
that shows the guess by the opponent here.
And then below that I wanna have another view
which holds the controls that we have to tell the opponent,
the program, whether the guess was too high or too low.
So here we could have another text
where we say higher or lower
and then below that we have our two buttons,
where we basically show a plus or minus
to indicate whether it's too low or to high.
These are all the chess placeholders
we'll add real buttons instead soon.
And then below all of that,
we'll have another view where we log our rounds.
So that's the general structure
with plenty of placeholders that we have here
and we'll have to fill those placeholders step by step
and we'll have to style this overall screen step by step.
And I'll start by styling this view that wraps everything.
I wanna make sure that we don't have the content
crammed up to the edges here,
instead, it should be centered,
it should be clearly visible on the screen.
And of course for that, we can use good old Flexbox.
So we'll add a style sheet here
in this game screen component, as well
and create the styles constant
which then will hold a style sheet
that is created with the create method
and then here in this style sheet object,
I'll add a property named screen.
Name as always, is up to you though,
which gets flex one to make sure it takes up
all the available space,
instead of just the space needed
by the content of the element that receives this property.
We wanna take all the available space instead.
And I'll already add some padding, let's say, 12 pixels,
to make sure that we add some distance in all directions,
so that we have some distance to the device edges.
Now for the moment, that's it.
For a start, that's good enough.
And then I'll add this style to this view,
as we did it many times before, like this.
If we save this, I get an error, of course,
because I have these texts here which must go into texts
and I'll just comment those placeholders out
because they are just meant to be used as placeholders,
not as actual text.
I also have this text, of course.
Let's count this out, as well.
Now with that finally, if I go to this screen
we have this extra content,
but it's actually still in the top left corner.
Now actually, there is some padding here,
as you can tell if I ramp up the padding to 40,
now it's moved in further, but 12 pixels wasn't enough.
Now we didn't have the problem here
on the start game screen
because on this screen, we do add
quite a lot of margin to the top.
We could add this here, as well on this game screen,
but actually I want to introduce a new component
that is very useful when it comes to adding some distance
to the device edges, especially to the top of the device,
to the notch as we have it here.
And that's the safe area view.