Modern smartphones
often have notches like this.
Here it's the typical iPhone notch,
other devices have a smaller notch,
but often we do have notches like this.
And therefore we wanna add some distance
to make sure that our content isn't too close
or even under that notch.
But, of course, not all smartphones have such a notch,
and it's not the same size for all smartphones.
Therefore it would be nice if there would be some component
that would automatically detect
on which device we're running
and add an appropriate amount of spacing
around our content to allow for that notch
and for that status bar.
And it turns out that such a component, thankfully, exists
and it's even built into React Native.
It's the safe area view.
And actually I wanna wrap this view around all my screens,
not just around the game screen.
Therefore I will not import it in the game screen,
but instead in app JS
because there I wanna wrap it around
my entire screen content.
So here we can import the safe area view from React Native.
And then we use this view by simply wrapping it
around our main content.
Now I'll go inside of the linear gradient
and the image background,
because I do want that background to be under the notch.
I don't want my image to end here in front of the notch.
It should be below the notch instead.
So that's fine, but I do want to make sure
that my main content, my screen content,
is not going under that notch.
Therefore I'll add my safe area view here
and wrap it around this screen.
Now we just need to make sure that we also add style here
to the safe area view,
and we apply our root screen style to that as well,
so that we still make sure that all the available space,
minus the area that is reserved for the notch,
which will be taken care of automatically,
is made available for this inner content.
With that, if we save this
not much changes on the starting screen.
If I reload everything,
we can see this doesn't look too different, that's fine.
But on this other page,
we see that now this is pushed down further
and we do have this nice distance to the top.
If we have a look at this on, on Android.
We see that it's way further to the top
because there is no notch on this emulator.
So this is now looking better.
Some extra distance would still be nice.
So on the game screen,
I'm still going to ramp up the padding a little bit,
maybe to 24 pixels,
but we do use this in conjunction with the safe area view,
to make that we don't go under that notch.
And this is a super important technique and view,
which you will use a lot
because, of course, typically you wanna make sure
that your content is not hidden by not just like this.