[Maximilian Schwarzmüller] Great.
So, now we added this save area view.
Let's now continue with styling
and laying out the rest of this game screen.
And this opponents guest text, for example,
should be a title.
Not a small little text as we have it here.
And to make it a title we can add some extra styling.
For this, I'll add a title property here.
And then we could say that a title
should have a font size of 18 maybe,
maybe it should have a font weight of bold,
that might make sense for a title
and we can give it a certain color.
The color is up to you
but here I want to use a yellowish color
and I'll use the yellow color
I have here in the start game screen.
So I will assign that here.
Now with that assigned, we can go back
and add our style here, like this.
If we do this, this is looking better
but I'd also like to center it.
So I'm also going to add text align center,
and maybe we ramp up the font size even more to 24 pixels.
And this looks better.
Now, what I want to add in addition,
is I want to add a little border around this title,
and I also wanna add some padding therefore
so that we have some distance
between the border and the actual text.
So I'll add a border width of two here
and a border color, of that same yellow as I had it before.
And last but not least I want to add some padding here
in all directions of let's say 12.
And with this I have this kind of title.
Now, of course you can adjust the title
to look however you want it to look,
but I'm quite happy with this result.
By the way, the layout is not final.
We will make sure that this is all pushed down
a little bit more in the future.
But now we have this title and it's probably fair to assume
that we might be using a title like this quite frequently,
in our application, maybe on different screens
but typically with the same styling
or maybe minor styling differences
and therefore it would make sense to outsource this text
into a separate reusable component
because that is what we typically do in React
when we do have elements that are used
in different places of our app.
So in the components folder I'll add a new file,
which I'll name, Title.js.
And in there, I'll add a component function
which I'll also name, Title.
Which I'll of course export as always
and the job of this component is to display
such a configurable title.
So we can grab this text here
from the game screen and cut it from there
and add it here as a returned JSX code.
Of course for this to work, we need to import text
from React Native here in this Title.js file
and the text here, should of course not be set in stone.
Instead I'll remove it
and I'll use object destructuring here
to pull the children property out of my incoming props
and use that here, so that the actual content
that is displayed by the title,
can be set by adding it between the opening
and closing text of my custom title component.
And now in GameScreen.js we can use
this custom title component.
Of course, for this you must make sure
that it's being imported.
And then here we can output opponents guests like this.
Now for this all to work we also must migrate our styling
and we can therefore cut the title style
from the game screen and move it into the title component.
There of course we must import style sheet
and create our styles via style sheet create,
like this, adding the title property.
With all of that, if we save everything
we got the same title as before and nothing changed here
but we have this reusable component
which we could use in different parts of our application.