Now in the previous lecture
we added this title component.
And by doing so we made sure that
we had this reusable title.
But speaking of reusability
and repeating certain things and settings,
you might have noticed that these colors
which I'm using are used in different places of the app.
I'm using colors in the Start GameScreen,
in the primary button component,
in the title component.
And having all these colors in all these places
is not ideal.
It's just as in web development with CSS.
If you're using the same colors in different places
which you typically are, repeating them manually is annoying
because you always have to copy the exact same hex codes,
and if you would change to color at some point
and even if it's just a slight change, a small change,
you would have to apply that in different files
of your project, which of course is not great.
Now in CSS, you could solve this problem
by using CSS variables, CSS custom properties.
But this feature doesn't exist with React Native
because we're not using CSS here.
Therefore what is commonly done in React Native,
is that you create a helper file
that exposes certain constant values
like the colors you're using.
And for this I'll add a new folder,
which you could name Util for utility
or constants or whatever you want.
And I'll go for constants
because I'll manage some constant reused values in there,
and then I'll add a colors JS file in there.
And in this file, I'll create a colors constant
which is just a regular Javascript object.
But in this object, I'm now going to set up
various properties which I'll reuse over and over again
throughout this app.
For example, a primary color.
And since I plan on managing multiple shades
of the primary color, I'll name this primary500.
It doesn't have to be 500,
it could be primary 1 and 2 and so on,
but I will indicate how saturated or dark a shade is
by higher or lower numbers after the main property name.
Now my primary500 number could be this primary plum color
which I have here in my by button for example.
So in colors, I'll set this here as my primary500 color.
Now we can export this colors constant here as a default,
and import it in all the places where this color is needed
like in the primary button
There, we also have a different shade by the way,
because of the ripple effect.
It's a slightly darker shade,
so I'll go to my colors constant and also add primary600
to store this shade here as well.
And then in primary button as mentioned,
we can import colors from going up one level,
diving into the constant folder,
and then into the colors file,
and now here we wanna use the darker shade,
so I access colors.primary600 to use that constant value.
And down here in the style sheet,
we can use this constant array as well,
and I can access colors primary500.
And if we would change the colors here in this colors file,
those changes would be applied to all the components
where we import this constant.
That's the advantage of using this approach.
Because now we can manage the colors in one global place,
and then use these colors in multiple components
and changes therefore only have to be made in one place,
instead of many places.
So I'll go to all the other places
where I'm using these colors as well.
To start GameScreen,
though there I'm not using this plum color as it seems
so no change needs to be made there.
(gasps) I am using it here and even darker shade.
So let's cut this from Start GameScreen,
and add this darker shade maybe as primary800,
to leave an extra space for in between shade
if we should need it and add this here,
and then in Start GameScreen,
we also wanna import colors from going up, constants,
colors like this...
We can then use this down here and use colors.primary800
which was this super dark shade we added.
And we cannot also add the yellow color here.
This is our accent color, so the alternative color.
So I'll name this accent500
and store the yellow color here.
And then again in the GameScreen,
in the places where we need that...
Sorry, in the Start GameScreen,
we can replace this hard coded text code
with colors accent500.
So do that here and here.
And we're using that same yellow color
in the title component,
so therefore here we cannot also import colors
from going up, constants colors,
and use that instead of the hard coded yellow values here.
So that we have colors accent500 here for the text color
and then also for the border color.
And that's how we can use these color constants
in those various components.
Now we don't use any colors in App.js...
Oh yes we do, here.
So let's also import it there.
Import, colors from./constant/colors.
And then here, this should be...
It's an extra shade actually as I can see,
so we might want to add that.
And this looks like a shade between primary600 and 800.
So it's good that we left some space here.
Yeah, I think it fits in there,
and now we can use that.
We can use this newly added color,
add this primary700 shade here in this App file,
and then this is our default yellow,
so here we can use our accent500 color.
With that if we save this, this should work again
and we should have the same look can feel as before.
Also if I reload and end up on the starting screen,
this looks good, but now we're managing this
in a global place with all the advantages I outlined.