So now that we added this title
as a reusable component
and we added our reusable colors,
it's time to work on the other features
that should be implemented into this game screen.
And for this, we need to output a guess made by the phone,
by the device, because we're playing against the device.
And the device should guess,
the phone should guess our chosen number.
Now to generate this guess
we need to calculate a random number.
And for this attached, you find this utility function
which generates a random number
between a min and a max number defined as imports here.
And we can also pass in an exclude number
which allows us to exclude a certain number
from being generated
which will be important for making sure
that we can't immediately guess
the number chosen by the user,
because here I wanna make sure that the phone is not able
to guess the correct number right at the start.
And therefore I add this exclude parameter
which allows me to exclude that single number
so that the phone can't win automatically
in the first round.
It's a little extra difficulty
that's added here for the phone,
hence these three parameter values.
And then inside of this function here,
I generate a random number with this calculation
where I use math random which creates a random number
between zero and one with one excluded.
And I then multiply this with the difference
between max and min to translate this random number
between zero and one, to a random number
between our max and min
and I use math.floor to then round this down.
Since this would give us a decimal number
with decimal places, and we don't want that.
We want integer and we round down with math floor.
And since we're rounding down,
we actually add our minimum boundary again
so that the lowest number we can get is not zero
which would be the lowest number otherwise
because math.random can produce zero as a result,
but that instead our lowest possible boundary
is the minimum defined here.
That's what we do here.
And then here, I just check if that random number happens
to be that number that we excluded
in which case we call generateRandomBetween
again recursively to simply calculate a new random number.
And we keep on doing this until we derived a random number
that's not equal to the excluded number.
And if we did not hit the excluded number,
we just returned a random number.
So this generates random numbers
and now wanna generate a random number
when that game screen is loaded.
The first guest made by the device
should be generated whenever this game screen
is rendered for the first time.
And this generated random number will change over time
and will be reflected in the user interface
because I wanna output it here.
And therefore we should useState
because we got some data that changes over time
and where every change should then be reflected
on the user interface.
Therefore in order to manage state here,
we import useState from React of course, as we always do.
And in the game screen
we can then initialize our state slice.
And here I have the currentGuess
of the phone and a state updating function.
And the initial value for this state
should be an initial guess
which we make by simply calling generateRandomBetween.
And I wanna generate a random number
between one and 100
because the upper boundary will be excluded
because with Math.random, the upper boundary
which would be one is excluded.
So we have to go one value,
one number above our actual highest number here as well.
And then I also wanna exclude a number
and that excluded number should be the number chosen
by the user on this starting screen.
So therefore, we need to make sure
that we have access to this chosen number in this component.
And how do we get access to values
that are derived in different components?
Typically through props.
We could also use React Context
but here I'll just use props.
And I'll use object destructuring here right away.
Alternatively, we could of course,
also accept the props object and use the dot notation here,
but I will use object destructuring instead.
And I expect to get the userNumber as our input here
as a property on my props object.
And I then can exclude this here.
So a phone can't guess this userNumber
when that state is initialized.
And then this initialGuess
is set as our initial value for this state.
Okay, so now we have that.
Now we have this guess that's being made,
and now we can output this guess here in our user interface.
And for outputting this guess
I wanna build a nice looking text here,
a nice looking text element
which I actually will outsource into a separate component.
Not because we have to,
but because I wanna keep this component a bit leaner,
especially the JSX code a bit leaner.
Therefore in the components folder, I will add a game folder
to add the game related components into that folder.
And I'll move primary button and title into a UI folder
to store genera UI related elements in that folder.
This is not required, but helps me organize my files.
So I'll move these files
and I do want to update my imports automatically
so I will choose always automatically update imports
to make sure that all the imports are updated,
such that moving these files doesn't break the app.
And in that components game folder,
we can now add a Number Container,
the name is up to you.
Which will be a simple container
that is responsible for outputting
the number that was guessed.
For this here, I'll add a function Number Container.
So a default component function here, which is exported.
And I wanna return a view that contains a text.
I add this extra view as a rapper
so that I can nicely position and style this text.
Of course, as you learned,
we need to import these two core components
from React Native, otherwise we can't use them.
So that's something we have to do.
And then I expect to get the number
that should be output as a prop here.
And I expect to get it as the prop that is used
or as the value that is used
between the putting in closing text of this custom component
when that component is used in a different file.
So hence we can use this special children prop
to output that content.
Now, this container is mostly about the styling, of course,
and therefore I will add my styles here
by using StyleSheet create as we did it many times before.
And now the styles that I do want to have here
are one style for the container, so for the view.
And then one style set or one set of properties
for the text, for the actual numberText, you could say.
These names, as always, are up to you.
Now for the contain, it's totally up to you.
And as always, I encourage you to play around with that
and come up with any styles you want.
I will set a borderWidth,
which we already did many times at this point.
I will give this a borderColor
And here I want to use my global colors
so that I take advantage
of this global definition of colors.
So I will go up to constants
and then to the colors file with this import.
And then I wanna use color accent 500.
So this yellow color here as a color.
I'll add a lot of padding with 24 pixels
And I'll add a border radius
of eight, maybe, to have rounded corners.
That's why we also need a view because border radius
is not supported on the text element.
So if I would've used just a text without a wrapping view,
I could have added things like the border and padding,
but adding a border radius
would not have been possible on iOS.
Hence we needed the extra view as a rapper.
Now I also wanna have some margin around this box.
So actually here, I'll also add a margin of 24 pixels.
And since all these views are flex boxes by default,
I will add alignItems center
and justify content center to make sure
that the actual text in that container is nicely centered.
And then on the number text,
which is the style that will be applied
to this text component here,
I will set the color to colors accent 500.
So to the same yellow and the font size to 36,
so that we have a really big number.
And I'll set the font weight to bold here.
And now we can apply these styles to these element and here.
So the container style is applied to the view,
and the Number text style is applied to the text.
And that's now the number container component
that should be used in the game screen
to output the guessed number.
So for this here, below this title,
I'll output the Number Container
Which therefore of course must be imported
from components game Number Container.
And with that import added,
we can use that here in our JSX code
And between the opening and closing text,
I will pass in the current guess that was made by the phone.
Now, if we saved it and reload everything,
it looks like there is an error with this import
Looks like this import path was not updated by VS code.
The title component is now in the UI sub folder.
So we must look for it there.
And in addition, yeah, looks like a couple of other imports,
although were not adjusted
like here inside the title component.
We need to go up one step further.
We need to go up to a higher level folder
because we moved title into a lower level folder,
into this new UI folder.
So that was also missing.
And now it looks like things are working again.
So let's force a reload on all these devices.
And now if I start this game, here is my guess.
And actually, if I look at this
I think it will look a bit nicer
if the title is not also yellow,
but if it is maybe white.
So here in Title.js,
instead of using colors accent 500, I'll use white.
By the way, we could store this white color
in our colors constant as well.
But since this is already a clear predefined identifier
I'll just use it like this.
Yeah, this looks a bit nicer.
Now we have our guess here
and this initial guess of course will be different
every time we start a new game.
So here on Android, it's different
than what we see on iOS, for example.
And if we would restart the game on iOS,
we would also very likely get
a different number the next time.
But of course, that's just the first step.
Deriving an initial random number is nice
but now we need to make sure that we have buttons
that allow us to give the computer some feedback
on whether that number is too big or too small
so that a new number can be derived.