So let's work on that feedback area now.
And for this, below this higher or lower text,
which I have here,
I wanna output two PrimaryButtons
using my own custom-built button.
One button that shows a plus
and one button that shows a minus.
Now, for this, of course,
you must make sure that PrimaryButton is being imported
in this file.
So this import must be added.
And then we can add a plus and a minus button.
We will later replace plus
and minus with better looking icons
but for the moment, these default characters will do.
Now, I actually wanna make sure
that these two buttons are next to each other in a row
below this text here
and therefore, I'll wrap them in a extra view,
just as we did it a little bit earlier
so that I can then ensure that this view,
which holds the buttons,
positions its children in a row
whereas this view, which holds the text
and then the view with the buttons positions these elements
in a column below each other.
And I will add the styling code
for creating that layout later
but that's the general structure I'd like to have.
Well, and now we can add the onPress prop to both buttons.
And then make sure that we have some function we can call
that will derive a new random number.
And for this, I will add a new function here,
the nextGuessHandler function
and the job of this function
is to derive such a new number.
For this, we need to know
if that new number that should be guessed
should be higher or lower.
Now, we could write two separate functions
where then one function is bound
to this first button
and the other function is bound to the second button
but here I will simply use one function,
which takes a parameters,
which could be called direction,
which then could be a string
that is either lower
if the new number should be lower
than the previous number
or greater if it should be greater.
So that is what direction should hold actually
and since I will be the one calling that function,
it's my responsibility
to pass in either lower or greater as values.
And then inside of nextGuessHandler,
we can check if direction is lower,
which means we wanna now generate a lower number
or well, if it's higher.
Now, for that, to derive that number,
we, of course, wanna call
our random number generation function again.
So generateRandomBetween.
We wanna call that again.
But now we need new boundaries.
And if we know that the new number should be lower
than the previous number,
we know that our minimum boundary was okay
but the max boundary needs to be adjusted
because it was too high.
Otherwise the new number wouldn't have to be lower.
So my min should stay the previous minimum number
but how do we know what the previous minimum was?
Initially, it's one but, of course,
that could change over time.
If we had to guess a higher number at some point,
the minimum is no longer one.
So both the min and the max boundaries
are actually dynamic
and they're only 1 and 100 initially.
Now, what we can do for this
is we can add extra variables,
which we manage outside of the component function
so that the variables won't change
just because the component is reevaluated.
And here I'll have my minBoundary,
which initially is one,
and I have my maxBoundary, which initially is 100.
And then we could use the minBoundary here
and the maxBoundary as initial values
but we also change these variables
as soon as we have to.
So here, for example, when we know
that we need to guess lower,
we know that our new maxBoundary
actually should be the currentGuess
because we know the currentGuess was too high,
so it makes no sense
to guess a number even bigger
because if we have to guess lower,
we know that the currentGuess was too big,
otherwise we wouldn't have to guess lower.
And therefore, we know that the currentGuess
is definitely the upper boundary.
Actually, it's the currentGuess minus one even
because if the currentGuess
would have been the right number, we would have won.
So it has to be the currentGuess minus one.
That's our new maxBoundary.
On the other hand, since the maxBoundary is excluded here
when calling generateRandomBetween,
we should not deduct minus one
because if we do so, we actually exclude a number
that could be the valid guess.
So setting maxBoundary to currentGuess is fine.
It will be our currentGuess,
which then will automatically
be excluded by generateRandomBetween
because of how this function works.
Now the minBoundary has not changed here
when we need to guess lower.
So now we generate a random number between the minBoundary,
the maxBoundary, which we did update,
and when it comes to excluding a number here,
we actually wanna exclude the currentGuess.
It makes no sense to guess the same number again,
though it would be excluded anyways here
since it is our new maxBoundary,
which as mentioned before is excluded anyways
because of how this function is written.
Nonetheless, we exclude the currentGuess here
and with that, we should guess a new lower number.
So here we have the new random number that's being guessed,
which should be lower than the previous one.
Now, else if the direction is not lower,
we know that we need to guess a higher number.
So we need to generate our random number as before
but now we need to adjust the minBoundary
instead of the maxBoundary.
And the new minBoundary here in this case
should, of course, also be our currentGuess
but the currentGuess plus one.
The minBoundary, unlike the maxBoundary,
is included in the set of possible results
and therefore, we have to add plus one
so that we don't guess the same minBoundary again.
We would exclude it also because currentGuess
is excluded but still,
this is an adjustment we can make here.
This exclude parameter mostly exists
for the initial guess.
For the other guesses, we don't really need it,
so therefore here, setting this
to the currentGuess each time is perfectly fine.
And of course, you will notice
that this random number calculation,
this line of code is exactly the same
so we can move this out of the if-else statement
and remove it in the other branch here
and just have it once
and just adjust the boundaries
inside this if-else statement.
So now we have this new random number here
and this is now the new random number we wanna use
as a new state for the guess.
So now we can call the setCurrentGuess
state updating function
and set this equal to the new random number.
Now, with that, this should be updated
and we just need to bind this function
to these buttons now.
And for this, of course,
we wanna point at the nextGuessHandler function
on both buttons
but we need to pre-configure this function
because this function wants a parameter, the direction.
And you learned that you can pre-configure
a function like this
that will be called by someone else,
like in this case the button
and therefore, React Native in the end,
by using the bind method on that function.
This allows you to pre-configure the parameter value
that will be used in a future function execution.
Now, the first value of bind actually sets the this value,
so it sets the value to which the this keyword
would refer in this function.
And since we're not using this keyword here,
this does not matter at all,
so we'll just set it to this.
But the second value is then the first parameter received
by that function.
And here that should be a string
with the content lower
because that's one of the two string values we want
because that's one of the values we're checking for.
We're actually not checking for the other value
in any place at this time
but still here I will set this to greater nonetheless.
And actually now it's wrong.
This should be the minus button.
This should be the plus button.
So I'll update these characters
so that they fit the way we call this function.
Okay, with all of that, we added those buttons,
we added this functionality.
Let's see whether it works.
We got the buttons here.
And if I click a plus, indeed, we get a higher number.
If I click a plus again, we get a even higher number
and if I click the minus, we get lower numbers.
However, only up to this point
and now the app froze here.
Let's try this again.
Yeah, at some point, it freezes
with a maximum call stack size exceeded error.
So it looks like we're somehow entering
an infinite loop in some place.
And that causes the app to crash.
Now, where does this happen?
Now, to understand why this happens,
let's actually add a console.log statement
to this nextGuessHandler
and let's log the min and maxBoundaries
because there is a reason why this is happening.
If we add this and we force a reload,
let's say I have the number 31.
Now I tell the computer
that the number should be smaller than 71,
smaller than 63.
And if we have a look at the log,
we see that indeed,
we're logging the minBoundary, which never changed
and we have our maxBoundary, which makes sense.
And we have no problem right now.
Now, if I now give the computer a wrong hint, for example,
like this, then we see
that the minBoundary is now 46
and the maxBoundary is 63.
At this point, the computer has no chance
of guessing the right number, which was 31,
but that's not even the main problem.
The main problem is that if I now say lower again
and lower, and now higher,
at some point, we narrow down this area
to an area where no guesses can be made anymore.
At the moment, it's still possible
but if I decrease this again
and I decrease this again,
now we get to a range where if I press this again,
we actually have a range that is no range anymore.
Now a random number between 48 and 48
would have to be guessed
and that number can never be found
and therefore, we enter an infinite loop
because this is then also always equal
to our latest guess,
which was 48
and therefore, we always make it
into this recursive function here,
guessing more numbers, never getting out of that.
So actually, the problem
is that we can make contradicting indications
to the computer
and besides entering this infinite loop,
this would be a problem anyways
because we should play fair.
We should let the phone know
if the guess was too high or too low
and we should not be able to say you need
to guess higher if actually you need to guess lower.
Therefore, we should add another check here
at the beginning of nextGuessHandler
and there, we should check if the direction is lower
and at the same time,
the currentGuess that was made
is smaller than the choice made by the user,
than the userNumber, which we get through props.
Because if the currentGuess is smaller
and we're saying that you need to guess lower,
then we are lying
because you already guessed lower than the userNumber,
so telling you that you need
to guess even lower is a lie.
The same would be true
for the opposite, if I copy this
and combine it with a or statement
because that would also be a problem.
If we say the direction is greater
but the current guess
is actually greater than the userNumber,
then we're also misleading the phone
into a wrong direction.
And this is what causes the infinite loop in the end.
So now I'll group this together in parentheses
and now with this extra if check added,
if we return here,
and not calculate a new number, in this case,
we won't have this infinite loop anymore.
Of course, I don't just wanna return silently,
instead, I wanna let the user know
that he or she lied.
And we could do this by throwing an alert.
So by using this built-in Alert API again,
which we already used before,
we can use this to now show a short alert message here
by calling alert
and saying don't lie,
you know that this is wrong.
And then we can add a button here
with a text of sorry, for example,
and the style of this button could be cancel.
You can, of course, configure this however you want.
We don't need to add a onPress handler here
because I don't wanna do anything
when this button is clicked.
Instead, I just want to close the dialog,
which will happen automatically and then return.
I'm just warning the user
that a incorrect indication was given.
Now, one thing that's missing here though
and that was already missing before to be honest
is the userNumber.
The userNumber is received as a prop
and we're using it to calculate the initial random number
but actually, I forgot to pass this number
into this component.
So all the time, we didn't take it into account.
Therefore, what we should do here
is we should go back to App.js
where we manage this number with state
and we should, of course, pass it into this GameScreen
as soon as the game started.
So here I'll set the userNumber prop
and set this equal to the userNumber state
that we're managing here in the app component
so that this picked number
is exposed to the GameScreen.
We should have done this before.
I did it now to make sure
that this number really ends up there.
Now, with that done, if we reload everything,
what we'll have now is that if I enter a number,
and now I have a guess that's too high,
the number is too big,
if I tell the phone that it needs to guess even higher,
a bigger number, I get this alert.
So now actually this would have been the right number.
We just don't have any exit condition yet
but now I get this warning.
And now with that, we get this alert
whenever we mislead the computer.
So that's another huge step forward
and we're getting closer
to implementing this final game logic that we need.