[Maximilian Schwarzmuller] Now with this logic added
we're able to give instructions to the phone
on whether it should guess lower or greater.
Now, the kind of logic that is still missing, though,
Is some logic that checks if the game is over.
And the game is over once the device guessed the number
we chose on this starting screen.
So once the device guessed 31 in this case,
then the game should end.
And at the moment, this is not happening.
It just crashes when we reach that number
because we then again, enter some infinite loop
because of how our code is configured.
Now, how could we check whether the game is over or not?
Well, there might be different ways of implementing this
but I would say that we need
to check the current random number
and compare it to this number defined by the user.
We need to make this comparison
between current guess and userNumber.
And if these numbers are equal,
we wanna let the app component know
because in that component, we then wanna switch
from the game screen to the game over screen,
which we have yet to add.
So therefore there are a couple of things we wanna do.
In the game screen, we wanna check and we wanna compare
the guess to the userNumber
and this should be done whenever the current guest changes.
Now, how do you do this with React?
Well, typically you use useEffect
because this allows you to run logic
whenever some dependencies some state, for example, change.
And therefore we can import the useEffect hook from React
and use that in this game screen component.
Maybe here.
We can use useEffect and add a function here,
maybe an arrow function.
And in this function here,
we wanna check if the current guess, which is this state
which we change with the next guess handler,
if that is equal to the userNumber.
And if that is the case, then we wanna call a function
that is defined in app JS, in the app component
that changes the state there to basically tell React
that the game is over and that a different screen
should be rendered.
And for this, in this app component,
we also wanna find a way of changing that state.
And we could do this by registering a new state here
in this app component which is our game is over state,
setGameIsOver, like this.
And initially, this is actually true
because actually the game hasn't started yet,
so it's kind of over.
And we wanna check if game is over is true.
If this is truthy, and in that case
we wanna set the screen variable to the game over screen
JSX element to this component.
Of course, for this, we first of all,
need to add some logic in the game over screen JS file.
So here I'll add a game over screen component
by exporting this here as a default.
And then here for the moment
I'll just output some text, where it will say game is over.
And of course we're going to tweak this component later.
For the moment I'm just going to import this text
from React native like this.
And then, in the game screen, sorry, in the app component,
I mean, we now can render game over screen.
We just also need to import it, of course,
we need to import the game over screen
from screens, game over screen.
And now we need to change this game over state,
whenever the game is over.
And for this, we should add a function here
in this app, component
the gameOverHandler function, for example.
And there I wanna set game is over to true.
And this function should now be passed
to the game screen component here,
so that from inside that game screen component,
from inside that useEffect call
we can trigger this function.
Now, to achieve this, I will actually define this function
before I render this JSX code here.
And then we can add a prop to the game screen component
like onGameOver, for example,
where we point at the gameOverHandler, like this.
Now, inside the game screen
we can use this onGameOver prop.
So here in game screen, we now don't just get userNumber,
we also get the onGameOver prop
which holds a pointer to this function.
And then there in useEffect,
if we know that the game is over
because the guess is equal to the number we chose,
we can simply execute onGameOver.
This function, which we receive here.
And that will therefore trigger
this gameOverHandler function in the app component.
So that's that.
Now we need to add some dependencies
to this useEffect hook to control
when this effect function should be executed.
And here, the simple rule is that all the variables,
all the values that you use in this function
should added as dependencies.
So therefore here our dependencies
are the current guess, of course,
but also the userNumber and the onGameOver function.
So now with that, whenever the current guess,
or the entered number, or this onGameOver function changes,
this effect will be re-executed
and we will check if the game is over.
In which case onGameOver will be called.
So therefore now with that, if we save everything
and we force a reload, I start on this game is over screen.
And I start on this screen because this is set to true,
and yeah, of course, I show this screen if the game is over.
What we will wanna do is we wanna check
if a number has been chosen and that the game is over.
So if the game has been played or if it just hasn't started.
If it just hasn't started, we don't wanna show this screen.
So we will check if the game is over,
and if userNumber is truthy.
So if a userNumber has been chosen,
which will not be the case initially.
So now with this, we start on the starting screen again.
And now we instantly go to this screen,
if I start a game though.
This, however, makes sense
because as soon as we set a userNumber,
we have game is over, which is true.
And we have a userNumber which is truthy.
And therefor, we show the over screen.
To avoid this, we must make sure
that we also set game is over to false once we start a game.
So here, when we pick a number, we also wanna set
game is over to false to indicate that the game started now
and that it's, therefore, not over.
This is important.
And these two state updates will be batched
together by React, so that the component
is not rerendered twice, but only once.
That's just a side note and that's just React specific,
has nothing to do with React native, but is nice to know.
So now finally with that,
we should be able to enter a number.
Now the game is starting.
And now we can and try to guess this number,
or let the phone guess this number.
And we still get this
maximum call stack size exceeded error,
as soon as we reach the final number.
So let's see why this is happening now.
This error is occurring because of this code here
in the game screen component
where we generate our initial guess.
What's important to understand about this code snippet
is that this function will be executed
whenever the game screen component is executed.
So whenever it is reevaluated, which will be the case
whenever a new guess is set.
So therefore regenerate it a new random number
whenever that happens
and we take our current min and max boundaries
into account here.
The problem with that just is that if we do it like this,
we execute this function, even at the point of time
where min boundary and max boundary are the same
because we derived our final result.
Now we don't do this in the next guess handler
because this handler can't be executed anymore
as soon as we have the final result
because the buttons won't be shown anymore
because we move to that game over screen.
But the problem is that this component function
is rerendered one time where the current guess
is equal to the userNumber.
Now useEffect runs after this rerendered cycle.
Hence we only trigger this function
that moves to the game over screen
after this component has been executed once.
Now, this is early enough to avoid
that the user is able to press these buttons again
because the latest buttons won't have rendered yet.
The buttons with the updated state won't have rendered yet.
But this function here,
this will execute before useEffect is evaluated,
so before we can move on to the game over state.
The work around is to hard code
our default min and max values here.
Because we only need this once, anyways,
we only need this initially, anyways,
and thereafter, we don't care about this.
An alternative solution could be to use the useMemo hook
provided by React to avoid that this gets executed again.
This might be a great alternative,
but this is a quick and simple workaround
that also does the trick.
And with that changed, if we now reload,
we are able to play this game again, but now you will notice
that we move to the game over screen
as soon as we reach that number, 31 in this case.
So now we got rid of this problem
by hard coding these values.
And it's really important to understand
that we had this problem because useEffect technically
runs after the component function has been executed.
And, therefore, this executed with the equal min and max
boundaries at a point of time
where it shouldn't have executed again.
Now this works, and now we can come back to styling
and work on this game over screen.
But also, of course, optimize is all these other screens.
And as always, definitely feel free to do this on your own.
Come up with your own layout and your own styling.
And then see what I will do in the next lectures.