So, let's now finalize these screens,
and for this I wanna start on that StartGameScreen again.
I wanna improve this screen a little bit
and I, for example, wanna add my title
above this input area.
And for that, if we go to the StartGameScreen,
we have to actually add another view
because at the moment everything on this screen
is only this input area.
This entire view here is this entire input area container.
So, I will add another view on this screen,
in the StartGameScreen Component here,
and then in there above this container
that holds the TextInput (indistinct) on,
I wanna add my Title Component that I created before,
which is imported from components/ui/Title.
And in that Title Component
we could say something like guess my number
because that is the title of the game, let's say.
With that we got this title here,
but of course this is not looking good.
Having this sit on the top edge
is not looking good at all.
To change this positioning
I will add another property here in my StyleSheet,
and name it screenContainer or rootContainer,
maybe that is a fitting name.
And here I wanna set up flex one,
so that whatever receives this style
takes up as much space as possible.
And here I also wanna add marginTop 100,
and actually reduce marginTop in the inputContainer
now to, let's say, 36.
And then we can add this rootContainer style
to this view here,
so we add the style prop and point at styles rootContainer.
With that this looks nicer
but I also don't want that title
to stretch from left to right.
Now, there certainly would be different ways of fixing this
but the way I will choose here
is that on that rootContainer
I simply change alignItems,
which aligns items across the cross axis,
which in this case is left to right,
from stretch, which is the default
which leads to this title being stretched, to center.
And with that it's not stretched anymore
but instead centered like this.
So that's an enhancement, I would say.
What I also wanna change
is that I wanna have a little instruction here
inside of that inputContainer box,
a little instruction that tells me
that I should enter a number that then has to be guessed.
So, for this, above this TextInput we can add a text,
a regular text,
which we of course have to import from React Native,
like this.
And in this text here we can then say enter a number,
Now, of course, this is totally not readable
so we need to add some styling here.
And for the styling I will add another style property here,
the instructionText property maybe.
And we can give the text a color of Colors.
lets try primary500, though that might be too dark.
And lets increase the font size to 24.
With that we can now add this to this text
by adding the style prop
and pointing at styles.instructionText,
and with this done we now got this instruction.
And I think it's not too easy to read
so as a workaround we could add a lighter shade,
but I think the better workaround is to make this yellow
since the number input field
also has yellow text, and so on.
And therefore I'll actually switch this
from primary500 to accent500,
to this yellow color which we stored.
And with this, yeah, that doesn't look too bad.
Now you could add more,
you could add an image to this screen,
enhance it in any way you want,
but I think this looks okay, this is decent.
I therefore would now wanna continue on this screen
where we actually play the game.
And on this screen, of course,
the buttons currently aren't that good looking.
I'm also not entirely happy with that number container
so I will work on this as well,
but I will start with the buttons.
I wanna group those buttons and the instruction text
that belongs to them in a box,
as we have it here on the StartGameScreen.
And actually I like the style of that box,
so I would like to use exactly the same box.
Now, since I plan on using exactly the same box
as I have it here on the StartGameScreen,
it makes sense to create a dedicated Component
that renders this box.
So, in the so in the components ui folder
I'll add a Card.js file
because this kind of Component
that provides such a container with this kind of look
is typically called a card.
So, therefore here we have our Card function
and we export this as a default here,
and then we crab the Card related code from StartGameScreen.
And for this I'm not going to grab all that code
because, of course, the specific content
that we have in this box on the StartGameScreen
should stay in that screen,
that's not what we wanna outsource into a generic component.
It's just the background, just the container itself.
And therefore it's actually this view here which I'll grab,
and return in here also with a closing tag.
And then in the Card component
I expect to get my children prop,
and I output this between the opening and closing view tags,
and that means that I can now use my Card Component
as a wrapper around any kind of content
to wrap this view with this style around that content.
Of course, for this to work
we also need to bring over the style, though,
and therefore I'll import the StyleSheet from React Native,
and create this styles constant here with StyleSheet create,
like this here.
And then in the StartGameScreen here,
we can grab this inputContainer style property,
which is responsible for styling this container,
this Card container, and cut that from StartGameScreen
and add it into this Card.js file
into the StyleSheet instead.
And I'll rename it to card
because this is now really the kind of style
we are applying here.
With that we can now use this Card Component
in the StartGameScreen,
and there we can import Card from components/ui/Card,
like that.
And now we just need to replace this view,
which is wrapped around our TextInput elements with Card,
and of course also replace the closing element
that belongs to that view.
And we can now also use this on GameScreen
to wrap this around our buttons there.
Here I wanna replace this view with Card,
also replace the closing view
and, of course, make sure that card is being imported
from the components/ui/Card file.
I also now wanna use my instruction text
that I defined here on StartGameScreen,
this text with that styling on the GameScreen
for this higher or lower text.
And, therefore, for the same reason,
we can create a Component.
The instructionText Component, or however you wanna name it.
The name, of course, is totally up to you.
But this also is a default React component, like this.
And in here we wanna return this text here,
which we have on the StartGameScreen
where we say enter a number,
and for this we then, of course, want to import Text
from React Native
and expect to get that children prop here as well,
so that we get this actual content
that should be rendered between the text tags
from the place where this instructionText Component
will be used.
And then, again, we wanna bring ove the styles
because that's the primary reason for creating
this reusable Component,
so that we have the styles to find once in one place,
and we can then use it in different parts
of the application.
And we therefore create such a styles object here
with StyleSheet create, like this,
and then we go back to StartGameScreen,
we grab the instruction text styling here and cut that,
and bring that over here into the StyleSheet
so that this works there.
And, of course, this should not be content
but children here.
So, now with that
we can use this instructionText here
in the StartGameScreen Component,
instead of the regular Text Component.
We now use the instructionText also for the closing tag
and we get rid of this style assignment,
we don't have that style in this file anymore
and we don't need it.
And, of course, you should add this instructionText import
and on the other hand
we can rid of the Text Component import
because we're not using raw Text Component
in this file anymore.
And now in the GameScreen we can also use this,
we can replace this Text Component
with the instructionText, like that,
and make sure that we import this Component,
and we can also get rid of the Text Component import here.
With all those changes made, let's see if this works.
It looks like we have an error,
can't find variable colors.
Okay, so in the Card Component
I'm referring to this colors constant
and I'm doing the same thing here in the instructionText,
and in both Component files I'm missing the colors import
so, of course we should import this from constants colors
and add this line of import to both the Card.js
as well as the instructionText.js files.
With that we're missing the variable view in Card,
and that makes sense I'm rendering a view
so of course we have to import this.
Now this should render successfully.
It crashed on Android as it seems
so let me restart it there.
And now we still have this box here
but we also have it on this GameScreen now.
There it's now just the positioning of the buttons
which I wanna change,
and then I got a couple of other things
I'd like to change as well.