So let's now continue on this game screen
with these buttons here.
Here in the game screen,
we already have this card as a container.
Then we have this view, which holds these two buttons.
And I'd like to position these buttons next to each other.
For this, we need to convert this view
from flex direction column,
which is the default to flex direction row.
Therefore that's what I'll do.
I'll add a buttons container here.
And as a side note, we have a similar container
on the start game screen.
And yes, we could outsource this
into a separate reusable component as well.
Here I'll not do it because it's just one line
of code, one line of styling anyways.
This line here.
But you could absolutely create a reusable component
for this button row as well,
if you wanted to.
You could even create a reusable component
that holds these two buttons,
if you wanted to do that.
That would absolutely be possible.
Here I will not do that though,
to keep things a bit simpler.
I will just add this view.
And again, wrap these individual buttons interviews
for the same reasons as before on the start game screen.
And then I can copy
over the button and buttons container style,
these two style objects, and add them here.
And then I'll add these styles to these views.
So this outer view receives the buttons container
and this interview receives the button container, like this.
And also this button.
With that done, if we save this, this looks better
just some spacing would maybe be nice.
And to achieve that,
I actually wanna add some spacing below the instruction text
or above this buttons container row.
Now we could easily add it to this buttons container row
but I'll add it to the instruction text
so that I can also show you
another key concept and technique
that you you will likely use quite a bit when working
with React Native, keep in mind that we're not using CSS,
so we have no cascading styles.
We have no inheritance.
But we can kind of replicate a similar behavior.
What if we want to add some extra styles
to this instruction text that should be applied in
addition to the styles applied already
inside of the instruction text component?
Well, we can use props in the instruction
text component.
Besides getting the children,
we could expect a style prop.
Though the name is up to you and doesn't have to be style,
but I will use style since that is the prop we used
on all these other components all the time for styling.
So now we get this style prop here on instruction text
and we can now merge the styles we get from this style prop
with the styles, we set up inside of this component,
which allows us to kind of build such a cascading structure
because we can now pass styles
from a parent component into this component
and merge it with the component specific styles.
Now this can easily be achieved
by wrapping our styles into an array here.
Because the style prop does not just take style objects,
it also takes an array of style objects.
If you do pass an array, by the way,
the items are parsed and evaluated from left to right.
So the right items, and the styles defined
in the right items, can overwrite the styles defined
in the earlier items.
So here I add the style that's coming in through props
and I add it as a last item
so that we could overwrite styles that are defined
in this default style set here.
So that we could override these default styles from outside,
and for example, assign a bigger font size if we wanted to.
So now we accepted this style prop.
We added to this array and we added such
that the default styles could be overwritten,
but we can of course now also add new styles
besides overriding default styles, by simply going
to the place where this component is used,
in this case the game screen,
and adding this new style prop
as a prop to instruction text.
And then here, I'll add a new style object.
The instruction text object, for example,
name is up to you,
and I'll add a margin to the bottom of 12.
So I'm not overriding any styles.
I'm just setting an additional margin to the bottom.
And now we can add this here like that
but this is an important technique,
which allows you to rebuild this cascading nature of CSS
in react native, by simply passing this style prop
into a component and then merging the incoming styles
with the existing styles, possibly as we're doing it here
such that you could override the default styles.
Though of course you could also add style
in front of the default styles if you want to ensure
that the default styles override the incoming styles,
if there are any clashes.
This is up to you
and depends on the exact use case you have.
Here I will add it such
that we could override the default styles.
And with this, we now have this margin to the bottom
and a bit more spacing between this text and the buttons.