So now we're making good progress here.
We worked on these buttons, but I'm not done yet.
There are two main things I wanna change
before we move on to the Game Over screen.
And the first thing which I'd like to change
is the icons in the buttons.
At the moment we have regular characters in there,
a minus and a plus, and I would like to use proper icons,
which are a bit prettier.
In addition, I also want to use custom fonts,
so that I'm not stuck with these default device fonts,
which are okay but which I don't wanna use here,
but that I instead can use my own custom fonts,
because of course, that is also a typical requirement
that you wanna bring your own fonts.
Now let's start with the icons though.
Thankfully, when working with Expo,
adding icons is super simple
because Expo and Expo-created projects
already come with a library, a package,
that allows us to use icons.
We just have to add a import here at the top
and we import something from @expo/vector-icons.
Now this should be available automatically
out of the box without you installing anything
because it is a peer dependency of Expo.
And from this package, you can import various icon sets.
Now, if you search for Expo vector icons,
you should find the official icons documentation.
And there, you can learn more about this library
and that it is installed by default
if you created your project with Expo in it,
and how you can use it
and which kind of icon sets you can use,
you can learn more here.
Now, one icon set that's built in which I like a lot
are the Ionicons.
Actually, there are more icon sets available
which provide different kinds of icons,
but Ionicons is one of them, which I like a lot.
Now on the official docs about Expo vector icons,
you can find a list of the built-in icons.
And for example, there if you search for minus,
you find various minuses,
belonging to different icon sets,
which are included with Expo vector icons.
And you do, for example,
also find the Ionicons minus in there.
For this, I'll add a little filter here
to filter only for Ionicons,
and actually search for remove.
And then here you find various icons
and I will use this md-remove icon, which is this minus.
But you can of course use any icon you want.
This name is important,
because you use these icons by grabbing this icon set
which is imported from Expo vector icons.
And then in the place where you wanna use an icon,
you render this as a component, as a self-closing component,
which gets a name prompt.
And now the name is that icon you want to use.
And we even get auto-completion here.
And we, for example, get help and learn that md-remove
is indeed a valid icon we can use here.
Now you can, in addition, also add a size prompt,
which sets the size in pixels.
And here I'll set this to 24 to have a nice big icon.
And you can set the color, and here I'll set this to white,
but you could also add a hex code or anything like this.
And with that, now we have this nice minus here.
And we can do the same thing for the plus.
We replace the plus character with Ionicons.
And now instead of md-remove, it's indeed md-add.
Same size, same color.
And with that added, we now also have this plus here.
And I'm using the same icons on both platforms.
You could even use different icons on different platforms,
but we will learn more about platform specific code
in the next course section.