So now, with the icons added,
let's talk about fonts
because we also sometimes wanna use custom fonts.
And again, thankfully Expo makes this pretty easy.
For this, we can go to the app component
because we wanna set up our own fonts
in the root component of the app
so that they are loaded when the app starts,
because custom fonts have to be loaded
and we wanna do this early on
when the app starts, typically.
Now custom fonts can be loaded
with help of a extra package.
This extra package must be installed
and we can do this with expo install,
and the package name is expo-font.
With that, this package gets installed into our project.
I still have the npm-start process running
in a different tab,
but I'm all installing this package.
And once this is installed in the app component,
we can import something from expo-font,
and that something is a hook,
a React Hook, exposed by this package,
the useFonts hook.
This hook can be called
and must be called in an app component.
In this case, in our root app component to load these fonts.
UseFont is executed,
and to useFonts,
you pass an object with instructions
about which fonts should be loaded.
Now, if you dive into the official
Expo Fonts documentation
you'll learn how you could easily include fonts from Google
because including Google Fonts is made extra simple
with help of a special Expo Google Fonts Package.
That might be worth a closer look as well.
Here, I wanna show you how to include any kind of fonts
where you might just have your local font files,
and therefore in the assets folder,
I'll add a fonts sub-folder,
and attached to this lecture,
you'll find two font files
which you should download and add to this fonts folder.
The OpenSans-Boldttf file,
and the OpenSans-Regularttf file.
These two files are attached,
and you should download them,
and add them to the fonts folder in the assets folder.
Now, once you added them,
they can be loaded with help of useFonts.
For this, in this useFonts object,
you must set up property names
that will later be used for identifying the fonts you loaded
and values for these property names,
that point to these files that should be loaded.
So for example, this font is called OpenSans
so I'll use open-sans as a property name,
between quotes, since this name includes a dash,
and it would be a invalid JavaScript property otherwise.
And then to load the font and assign it to this identifier,
we use this require function,
which we already know from images.
And here, just as for images,
we construct the path to this font
that should be loaded.
In this case, it's OpenSans-Regularttf.
And make sure you introduce no typo here
because otherwise loading that font will of course fail.
Now, we also have to bold version
for this I'll load open-sans-bold here,
and point at OpenSansttf like that.
This will load these fonts.
Now, what you should typically do
is that whilst these fonts are loaded
you wanna show a loading screen,
or you wanna show the splash screen of the app
which is the app loading screen
until the fonts have been initialized.
And to do this,
we can install another package with expo install,
and that would be the expo-app-loading package.
This gives us a utility component, which we can render
which will prolong the splash screen,
and will ensure that the splash screen is still shown
until some condition is met.
So now with this package installed,
we can import app-loading from expo-app loading,
and we wanna show this as long as we're loading fonts.
Now to find out if we are still loading,
useFunds, thankfully returns an array,
where the first element
which we can extract with array destructuring,
as we did it for useState,
where the first element is actually a boolean,
that indicates whether the fonts
have been loaded yet or not.
So we can now use this boolean
to render our app loading component,
which will then show the splash screen
until the fonts have been loaded.
So here I'll check if not fonts loaded,
so if we are still loading,
and in that case, I will return AppLaoding like this.
So in that case, I will show the splash screen,
and once the fonts have been loaded
the component will be re-executed,
and then we will not show the splash screen anymore.
But now with that,
we can use our custom fonts
because that is of course the main reason for loading them.
And it's up to you where you wanna use them,
but I, in the end,
wanna use my fonts in different places of the app.
For example, I wanna use my fonts here,
in the Title and Instruction text,
and NumberContainer elements.
And therefore, in Title.js to use my custom font,
we can, by the way, remove the colors import here
since we don't need it anymore.
But here to use the custom font
all we have to do
is go to our style object,
and add the fontFamily property,
as we would do it in CSS.
And now we can use these identifiers,
that we assigned in the app component.
So in my case, open-sans or open-sans-bold.
And here I wanna use open-sans-bold
since I wanna have some bold text.
We can now remove the fontWeight here
because this font which we load, is already bold.
Now in the InstructionText
I wanna use just open-sans,
so there I'll add fontFamily open-sans, like this.
And in the NumberContainer,
I wanna use the bold font again.
So here for number-text,
again we can comment out the fontWeight
but I'll add a fontFamily of open-sans-bold
or whatever you chose as your font identifiers.
With that, if we reload the entire apps,
the font is now a different one,
as you can tell,
because we're now using this custom font
that is getting imported.
The difference might not be huge
but it is a different font which we have here.
So that's how you can add custom fonts
to a React Native app.