So we worked on this start game screen.
We worked on this game screen and of course,
as mentioned before you can definitely fine tune this
to your likings.
Now, I wanna work on this game over screen
because of course this screen is not that pretty right now.
Now for this, let's switch to the game over screen.
What do we wanna do on this screen?
Well, I think it makes sense to show a game over title,
maybe a nice image and then below that image,
also a short summary of the game.
How many turns it took the computer, the phone
to guess our number and what our number actually was.
I think that could make a lot of sense.
And for this, to achieve this,
I will start by replacing this text here
in the game over screen with a View,
with a general container,
which we of course have to import
because as you learned by now
that is very often the first thing you do
since the View is this generic container component
that contains all your other elements
that make up a screen or a more complex component.
Now in here, I then wanna have my title
and I will reuse this existing title component
which I import from components UI title,
but of course you could also build a different title,
specifically for this page, if you wanted to.
I will reuse this existing title and say game over.
And then below this title, I'd like to have an image.
An image which I then also want to style.
For this we can use this image component
which we need to import from React Native as you learned,
and then for the image, I prepare the image for you.
Now, we already got the assets, images folder
and therefore you should simply download
and drag and drop that image into this images folder.
It's this success PNG file.
So now that's the image which I'd like to display here,
and for this, we can add a source here, as we always did
and require this from the assets folder like this,
and then there from images, it's success.png
that's the image I wanna add.
Now, on this image I then want to add some styling,
but for the moment let's just save this
and take a look at that.
So now we got the title and we got the image
and the image is way too big, as you can tell.
And it's way too big on purpose
because as mentioned I wanna show you how you can resize
and style the image and for example,
I also wanna create round image,
so a circle, and we can achieve this with style properties
which will dive into next.
For that, I will import Stylesheet
into this game over screen component
and create the styles object as we did it many times before.
Stylesheet create, and then create a style for our image.
And now when it comes to creating an image
with rounded corners, what works best is
that you create a View around your image,
and then on that View you add rounded corners,
and you add overflow hidden as we also did it earlier
for our custom button, if you remember this.
There we also worked with this kind of approach,
having a container with borderRadius and overflow hidden,
we'll do something similar for this image now.
And therefore here I'll add the imageContainer style,
where I add a borderRadius of let's say 200
and a width of 400 and a height of 400.
And the borderRadius should be half your width or height,
and width and height should be the same amount
so that we create a square and then by setting border radius
to half our width or height, we actually create a circle.
That is how we can create such a circle image.
And then we'll also add a border width of three here
to add a little border around that image
and the border color then can be any color you want.
I will use my colors constant, which is therefore imported
from constants colors, and on this colors constant,
I wanna choose a dark shade of my primary color,
like primary 800, which goes into the vlack color,
but isn't black
but still has some plum color elements to it.
Now, very important as mentioned,
we also wanna add overflow hidden, to make sure
that we hide the square or the rectangular nature
of the actual image and we use this container as an overlay,
as a mask for this image, you could say.
And I will also add a vertical margin or actually a margin
in all directions here on that image,
and here, let's say we wanna add a margin of,
let's say 36 pixels and we can of course tweak this later.
Now, this style will be applied to this view
which is the container for this image.
So hence I add it like this.
The image itself will now (indistinct) receive some styling
and for this I'll create an image style property
and all I do here is set the width to 100%
and the height to 100%.
And that 100% will refer to the container,
to the View in which the image is placed.
That's how percentage values always work in React Native.
They refer to the container of the element
on which you set up those percentage values.
So in this case, I will add this style,
this styles.image style to the image,
and therefore the percentage width and height
on that image will refer to the width
and height of the View that holds the image,
and that of course will be 400 each.
With that applied, if we save this,
now we got this circular image here.
Now it's a little bit too big,
and in the next core section.
We're going to learn how we can adapt this dynamically
to the available device size.
For the moment I'll find unit manually
and decrease this to 300 pixels height and width
and hence the border radius to 150,
so that it's still half the width.
With this, this looks better I'd say.
Now, in addition I also wanna have some general distance
to the top and some padding around the title and so on,
and therefore it makes sense to wrap this overall thing here
into a View, which we already did,
which receives some styling as well.
And for this, I'm going to add my good old screen
or rootContainer styling property,
my styling object to be precise and add flex one,
so that we take all the available space.
Then I'll add some padding, let's say 24 pixels,
and I wanna center the entire content in the middle
both horizontally and vertically and this can be achieved,
by using justifyContent center and alignItems center.
This will center it on both axis
and therefore it will be centered horizontally
and vertically.
And now this rootContainer style just needs to be applied
to this View, which wraps this entire content like this.
With that, we got this look
and this doesn't look too bad I'd say.
Now this is not everything I wanna do though,
instead as I said below the image,
I wanna output a short summary of the game.
And for this, we can go back to the JSX code
and then, below this imageContainer,
we can add another View,
simply to group together some text elements,
though we might actually not need that,
so let's just start with a text right away,
now that I think about this.
And for this of course text should be imported here
from React Native, and then in this text,
I wanna say your phone needed X rounds
to guess the number Y.
And of course X and Y are place holders
for the actual values.
Now we'll derive the values in a second
but what I wanna do is I wanna highlight X and Y,
and React Native makes that very easy as well.