Now to highlight X and Y we can wrap X and Y
in extra text elements, in extra text Components.
And this is something we haven't done
up to this point in this course
but it is something that is absolutely fine
and which you can do with React Native.
A text Component, actually can't hold
too many other kinds of Components.
For example, a text Component should not really wrap a view,
but a text Component can contain other text Components.
So having a text Component besides the plain text
in another text Component is allowed
and is absolutely something you can do.
And what this allows us to do is add different styling
to this text than to the rest of this text.
So therefore here I'll add another text wrapper
around the Y and then we can prepare some styles
for this text in general, and then for the X and Y texts.
Now let's start with the text in general.
For this, I'll add the summary text styling property,
and here I just wanna set the font family to open sense.
That's basically all I wanna do,
but then I also wanna add a highlight styling object here,
where I set the font family to open sense
bold so that we have some bold text
and where the color is set to colors primary 500
so that we assign a color to that text.
And now we can use these styling objects
to style the text and the texts inside the text.
The wrapping text receives the style prop
to assume the styles.
Summary text, styling
and the inner texts
that wrap X and Y receive style=styles.highlight
both these texts receive that.
And we could again create a reusable component for that
but here this is all the pretty reusable
since we assigned the same reusable style
to these two text Components.
With that we now got this summary text below this image.
Now, when I look at it, I'm not totally happy with that.
To make this a bit prettier
I actually wanna increase the text size.
So on the summary text, I'll ramp up the font size to 24
and now this is bigger.
And please note that the text that's nested
into another text element also is resized.
This is not inheritance at work,
but instead this is related
to how this is compiled to a Native Component internally.
If we have a view that contains a text
and we add a font size to the view
it would not affect any nested text elements in the view.
Nested text elements inside of other text elements
however, are affected by the text specific styles
you do set on the parent text Component though.
Though when we set a font size on the outer text
the nested texts are also affected.
That in the end works
as you would expect it to work, I guess
and it's definitely worth noting that it works like this.
So now we have this styling, centering the text
would also be nice still.
So I will also add text align center here
for the summary text,
so that this is centered like this.
Now last but not least below all of that,
I'd like to have a button that allows us
to start a new game.
So below of this text, I'll add the primary button
which therefore of course must be imported
from Components UI primary button.
And then on this primary button, I'll say start new game
and we will later add the on press prop
to trigger some function that does start a new game.
When we save this, we have this button here as well
and now maybe some spacing would be nice
so on that summary text
we can actually add a margin vertical
so margin top and bottom of 24 maybe.
With that there is some spacing
between the button and the text.
and actually, maybe we just want margin
to the bottom, now that I look at it
yeah, I think that looks nicer.
So now we have that, we have this game over screen finished
at least regarding the styling and the layout
but what's missing is of course that data
how many rounds we took?
and what the number was?
And this button is not working.
So that will be the next steps we will work on.