So let's work on outputting,
the actual number of rounds
the actual number that had to be guessed
and on starting a new game.
Now, here in the game over screen component
in this screen here
it's probably fair to assume that all that data
should be passed into this component from outside.
So from the app component
since that is the component
that is rendering the game over screen.
So therefore here in game, over screen
I just expect some props
and I use object destructuring here
to pull these props out of the incoming object immediately.
And the props I want here
are the rounds number,
the user number that was set up
and on restart or on start new game prop
which should hold a pointer at a function
that will reset all these game metrics
so that a new game is started.
So therefore now here
for X we can output the rounds number like that.
For Y we can output the user number like this.
And on the primary button here,
we add the on press prop and point at on start new game
With that this component is finished
but of course we at the moment get no data
for are these props.
We have to change this an app component.
So on the game over screen,
we wanna provide the user number.
We wanna provide the rounds number
and we wanna provide the on stat new game prop.
Now user number is pretty easy
because we're managing this as a state in the app component.
So we just wanna pass the user number into this component.
Now the rounds number is not available right now though
But that is something we can change.
Here in app JS,
we can manage a extra piece of state,
which is the guess rounds maybe
the set guess rounds,
state updating function.
And we do this with the use state.
And initially we have zero rounds
because the game hasn't started yet.
So now we could pass guess rounds to rounds number
but of course,
we will also need to make sure
that guess rounds actually changes at some point.
We'll take care about that in a second.
Now regarding on start new game,
we need a function that can be executed here
in the app component,
a function which I'll name start new game handler.
This sounds like a fitting name.
And then here,
I will point at this phone function
or to be precise I will pass a pointer
to this start new game handler function
to the on start new game prop.
So that this function here gets executed
when that new game button is clicked.
Now in this function,
we in the end wanna reset some data.
We wanna reset the state we're managing here
in the app component.
When we start a new game,
I want to set the user number back to null
because a new number must be picked.
I wanna set game is over to true because it is over
though we already set this to true here
so we don't need to set it again, actually.
But I also do want to set my guess rounds back zero
because a new game will start
and they offer the phone hasn't guessed any numbers yet.
So that's what I wanna do here.
And by setting user number back to null for example,
we ensure that this if check won't become active anymore
because user number
if it's null again is not truth anymore.
So we will automatically leave game over screen
and go back to the start game screen
just by setting user number to null
because both these if conditions won't be met anymore.
So that's already pretty good.
Now what we also need to do
when a new game is started though
is in the game screen.
Once a new game starts
we will need to reset the min and max boundary.
Now I'm managing these values as regular variables
outside of the component function
because they actually should be independent
from the component function.
When the component function is re-executed,
those variables
shouldn't be reset back to their initial values
all the time.
That's why I manage them outside of the component function.
But I do want to reset them
if a new game started
To achieve this,
we can again use use effect in the game screen component.
There I have an effect which I wanna execute
whenever this game screen component
is rendered for the first the time.
So whenever it was not part of the rendered user interface
and now became part of the interface.
And this can be achieved by
adding an empty array of dependencies to use effect.
Then this effect function will only execute
the first time this component is evaluated.
And then if it is removed from the UI and re added later,
this will execute again
but it will not execute
If this component was already on the UI
and now just updated
because for example a new guess was made.
So therefore this effect function
is now perfect for resetting min boundary to one
and max to 100
because with that,
we should ensure that this actually only happens
when this is rendered for the first time again.
Alternatively, we could also do this here
when we trigger on game over
because we know if the game is over
we wanna reset the min and max boundary
for the next time the game is played,
that should work as well
but here I'll try solving this with this
separate effect function.
So now we have all of that.
Let's now save this
and let's start a new game.
Now, if I solve this
and I start a new game again
I'm back here on this starting screen
and I can pick a new number
and then here I can still play the game as I did before
and it again ends.
So this looks good.
I can also see my number here on this game over screen
but of course the rounds number is currently not updated
and that's there for the next thing we wanna implement.
And we also should not forget
that the goal also is
to output a log of the play rounds here on this game screen.
So that's also something we'll have to do.