[Maximilian Schwarzmüller] So let's now work on logging
the number of rounds and on creating this log
that we can output on this game screen.
For this, we should add a new piece of state
to the GameScreen,
because these rounds are also just some state
which we can log.
So here I'll add my guessRounds
and setGuessRounds and initialize a new state
which initially should hold an array.
It will be an array
because of course we have multiple rounds
and we wanna log the number that was guessed
for every round.
So therefore also the initial value,
the initial first and only element
we wanna have in this array is the initialGuess.
That should be part of this array initially.
And now we can update this whenever we guess a new number.
So in the next guess handler,
besides setting the currentGuess to the newRndNumber,
we also wanna update the setGuessRounds state
or the guessRounds state
with the setGuessRounds updating function and update this
to include this new random number into this existing array.
Now, since we will update state
based on a previous version of that state,
we should use the function form of updating this state
by passing a function to the state updating function.
And here we get our prevGuessRounds.
So the previous state snapshot,
and we returned a new array
which is basically all our old array elements
which we can re-add into this new array
with the spread operator, plus this newRndNnumber.
This newRndNumber that was guessed in this round.
Now we can add this newRndNumber at the end of this array
or at the beginning which is what I will do,
so that when I do output the log
I can simply loop through these items
and the latest guess will always be on top.
This is not a must do, but something I wanna do here
for displaying this log.
So now we update these guessRounds
and we can now output them here.
So therefore, here we wanna output all these rounds.
We wanna output this log information.
We can do this by creating a view
and then mapping our array elements
into a list of other elements
that will be output on the screen.
So for this here we can use our guessRounds
and simply map through them and then we get our guessRound.
And for each round, we wanna output some text.
Let's say for this of course, you must make sure
that text is being imported from React Native,
otherwise this won't work.
And then here at the bottom
we output this text and we output this guessRound.
Now if we try this, we get an error here.
We get an error because we should have a unique key
for every element as you learned.
And indeed here we should add a key.
And the key can be the guessRound,
because we know that it will be unique,
because what's actually in this guessRounds array
are our guessed numbers.
And since we can never guess the same number again
due to how our logic is written here,
it's a perfect unique key,
because we know that every number
will only occur once in here.
So therefore now if we save this and we reload,
we can start a new game,
maybe on Android to mix things up.
And here 14 is the first number guess, we see it here.
And then you see this is being locked
but actually this is not looking right,
if we take a look at that.
What's the problem here?
The problem is that I added a tiny mistake here.
It should be the newRndNumber that's added as a new element
to this array.
So I mistyped and added the entire array again
which doesn't make any sense.
It should be the newRndNumber instead.
So if you save this and reload and try this again,
now this is looking better
and now we see that the correct numbers
are being locked here at the bottom.
So this is working
and this would be one way of solving this,
but of course you learned before
that outputting lists like this works
and can be okay, but if a list could get very long
then you might wanna use FlatList instead.
Now, arguably this list won't get very long
because it will very likely not take much more
than maybe eight, nine, or ten guesses at most
to derive the right number.
And outputting that amount of items with this approach
would be absolutely fine.
Still to learn it in the best possible way,
we can use FlatList here
instead of mapping a list manually.
But I wanna emphasize that in this situation
where we have a limited amount of list items,
it wouldn't be horrible to do it like this.
Still to move to FlatList
we can import FlatList from React Native
and use that instead to output all these items.
And of course, feel free to implement this on your own first
because you learned how FlatList works
and in the next lecture,
we're going to implement it together.
And there, we're then also going to create
nicely styled list items together.
But definitely feel free to do all these things
on your own first as a practice,
before we then do them together.