[Maximilian Schwarzmüller] So, did you succeed?
Let's build this FlatList together.
For this year, we render a FlatList.
And you learned that you need to provide the data prop,
which points at the array that holds the data
that should be output.
And in this case, that's our guessRounds state snapshot.
That's the array of data which we wanna output.
Now then we need to provide render item,
which receives a function that is responsible
for rendering the individual items.
So a function that will be called by FlatList
for every item in our data array.
Now, here we can provide an arrow function
and we wanna render, let's say a text element
for every item in this guessRounds array.
And you did learn
that you automatically receive the itemData here
as an argument,
automatically passed in by React Native, by FlatList.
And therefore between those text text,
we can then output itemData.item.value
if this would be a object with a value property,
but in this case, the item itself is already a number.
So we just output that item, that number.
Now, you also learned
that the key that uniquely identifies every item
is also needed when working with FlatList.
But you don't add the key by adding a key prop,
instead FlatList will add it for you.
It will look for a key property on your data objects.
But since our data are no objects,
but instead primitive numbers, it won't find that.
Hence we can add this keyExtractor prop,
where we tell FlatList how to derive a fitting key.
And for that here, we provide a function as well
which will also be executed by FlatList.
And in here we get our item, and we know that in this case,
the them itself is a perfect key
because the item itself is a number,
which is guaranteed to be unique
for every guessRounds element.
So we have a unique key here,
and we just tell FlatList to basically use our data itself
as a key, since every data item will be unique.
Okay, so now with that, we have a FlatList,
and if we save this and we give this a try,
this also is looking quite good.
And we now render these items here.
As a next step, we of course wanna improve
the styling of these items
because at the moment they are, well, ugly, to be honest.