Now for styling these items here,
We can create a new component,
maybe in the game folder, in the components folder.
And that could be the GuessLogItem.js file,
which holds the GuessLogItem component.
So we export this as a default GuessLogItem.
And then in here, it's up to you
how you wanna style this.
But I wanna make sure that for every LogItem
I show the number of the round,
and I also show the actual value
that was guessed in that guessing round.
Hence, I wanna add a view here
Which must be imported from react-native as you learned,
so we import this from react-native.
And I will also import Text here,
because inside that view,
I wanna have a text where I say hashtag,
and then roundNumber, let's say,
and roundNumber should be a prop which we receive.
And then another text where I output the opponent's guess,
which I also expect to guess as prop, as a prop,
and therefore that's the guess prop, like this.
So now these are the two pieces of information
which I wanna output in this GuessLogItem.
And I wanna render one instance of this component
for every round that's being played.
So for every item that's being output in the flat list.
Now, of course we wanna style this.
So I'll import the style sheet from react-native,
and then create my styles here
with StyleSheet.create, like this,
and then here, we can give this a name of ListItem,
and apply any styles of your choice.
In my case, I wanna style the border
by adding a border color here.
And for that, I'll choose my colors constant,
which is imported from that constants folder.
And I wanna use a dark primary shade.
The border should also receive a width
of let's say one pixel,
and the border radius of let's say 40 pixels,
to have some nice rounded corners.
I also wanna have some padding of let's say 12 pixels
so that we have some spacing inside of that container,
and the margin vertical of eight.
So that between the log items,
which are basically displayed on top of each other,
we have some spacing,
some vertical distance between the log items.
There also should be a nice background color
on every log item.
And I'll also get that from my colors constant,
and use the, let's say the accent 500 color,
so this yellow color.
I also wanna make sure that these two text items
sit next to each other in a row,
and therefore the flexDirection
must be changed to a row, as you learned.
JustifyContent can then be space-between
so that they are pushed to the edges of this container.
So the first item is on the left,
the second item is on the right,
and the empty space in between is left empty.
And I wanna add a width of 100%
to make sure that the log items take the full width
that is made available by the parent component,
which is the flat list.
Last but not least, we can add a little shadow,
and for Android, this can be done
with the elevation property, as you learned.
We could set this to a value of four.
And for iOS, we do this by adding a shadow color
which could be black,
and then a shadow offset
which is an object
with a width and a height, as you learned.
And the width can be zero, the height can be zero,
and then a shadow opacity of 0.25,
and a shadow radius, let's say, of three.
And you can play around with these values
to find a shadow that you like visually.
Now, with that, the styles have to be applied.
So on that view, I add styles.listItem.
And I also wanna make sure
that I use the right font for the text in there.
And therefore I'll add my itemText styling property,
where I set the font family to open-sans.
And then this itemText styling property here
can be added as a style to both these text elements,
these text components, like this.
Now we have the LogItem.
Now we can use it in the game screen.
Here, instead of outputting this boring text here,
I wanna output my GuessLogItem,
this newly added component.
Which therefore, of course, must be imported
from that file in which we created it.
And then here, we have to configure it.
We have to pass in the round number,
and we have to pass in the guess that was made.
Now the round number can be retrieved from itemData,
because on this itemData object, besides the item itself,
we also get the index of the item in the array.
And in the end, this index gives us an idea about the round.
The index itself is not the round number,
but we know that we just need
to take the overall length of the list,
so the number of items of the list,
minus the index, to get the round number.
We need to do this kind of calculation
because the latest round is added at the beginning.
So the latest round will always have an index of zero.
So if we take the overall length of the list
and we then deduct the index of the individual items
we get the round
in which this item was added to the overall list.
Now to get this listItem length,
we can add a regular constant
anywhere in this component function
before the JSX code is returned.
And here we get the guessRoundsListLength
by simply using guessRounds.length.
So this is recalculated
every time the component is reevaluated,
which will happen whenever a new round is added.
And then we can use this
to deduct itemData.index from it.
And the guess itself, of course, is itemData.item.
So the number value itself.
This is how we can deduct the round number,
and then the value for the round itself,
the number that was guessed.
If we give this a try,
you can see this is how it looks, and this looks quite good.
And you see now in the second round,
the guess was five, which is correct,
and this gets added, and added,
and we still get that warning if we give a wrong hint,
until we actually found the right number.
And this is scrollable
so that we can even view all the rounds
if we exceed the available space we have on the screen.
So we can still see that.
And eventually, of course,
we can then end the game
and start a new one if we want to.
By the way, we will also update this number soon.
So this generally works.
But if you paid close attention,
you might have seen that,
well, let me try again, reproduce this
so that we produce a list that's long enough.
You might see that actually here,
once we exceed this space,
yeah, we can scroll to see the bottommost value,
but actually it's not really scrolling into view.
We have a hard time really seeing that last guess.