Now to fix this scrolling issue
with the FlatList
where the content leaves our screen boundaries
a good solution is to wrap a container around the FlatList
which we already do with this View.
And to then add some styling to that container
that kind of controls how much space this FlatList
can take up.
Because by default, a FlatList works such
that it basically has an infinite height.
Now, if we restrict that height though
through a parent container that we add around it
then the FlatList will become scrollable
inside of that container.
But with that, we can avoid that it goes
beyond the boundaries of our device.
So we could then add, let's say, listContainer:
style object to the game screen, and add flex: 1,
on that and add a comma here.
To make sure that this container
takes up as much space as possible.
I'll also add a little bit of padding around it of 16 here.
And then this listContainer style property is assigned
to this View here, like this.
Once we do that, you will see that
if we start a new round and we keep on guessing here
and we hopefully don't guess the number too early.
Now I can still scroll here
but now I can scroll the items into View
and they don't go outside of my screen
which of course is better than what we had before.
So now this also works.
As a last step,
we can now count the number of rounds
so that we can also show it here on the Game Over screen.
Now counting the number of rounds to show it
on the game over screen
is at actually not too tricky.
In the game screen,
we are already logging all our rounds
and in the end the length of that list
is basically the number of rounds it took the phone,
the device to guess our number.
So therefore all we have to do,
is count the number of items in guess rounds.
Once the game is finished
and then report that to the app component
because the app component in the end needs that number
to pass it down to the Game Over screen
because there we need to pass in our rounds number.
Now for this, we already have the guess rounds state here
in the app component
which here is not an array, but a single number.
And we wanna update this number
as soon as the game is over.
For this, we got this gameOverHandler already
which is called by the game screen when the game is over.
And we now just need to make sure
that we report the numberOfRounds here,
that we get this as a parameter value.
So that in this function we can set guessRounds equal
to this numberOfRounds.
And now we just need to make sure
that this parameter is passed into gameOverHandler.
So into the onGameOver prop from inside GameScreen.
So in GameScreen, where we do call this onGameOver function
here, we wanna pass the guessRounds length as an argument
because that's the number of items
in this guess rounds array.
And that is the number of rounds
it took the device to guess our number
we're passing this into the function which we receive
through that onGameOver prop.
And that turns out to be that gameOverHandler function.
With that, if we save this and we start a new game.
If I enter a number here
and I then keep on guessing the game is over
and now see six rounds here.
So this works.
And let's actually also test this
on Android now and guess here.
So we have three rounds, four rounds
five rounds, six rounds, seven rounds, eight rounds.
And this is reported here as well.
So this works and last but not least
to also quickly show that
if I play this again up to the point
where we have a scrollable list
this scrolling all the works here on Android.
So that is all working and with that
the overall game is working as intended.