Now, that is it for this game.
You can absolutely fine tune this game
a bit more if you want to.
You can change the styling, the layout,
and you absolutely should play around
with those fundamentals.
Because in this section,
you learned a lot about these fundamentals.
You practiced a lot.
You practiced all these things you learned early
in the course, and you worked a lot
with all those built in core components with styling,
and you learned how you can build your own components
based on these core components,
how you can build general UI components
as well as app specific components.
You learned how you can switch
between multiple screens here simply
with help of State and if statements.
Later, we will also learn a different approach,
but this approach is perfect for simple apps
like this one here.
You learned in general how you can
use these core React features,
like State or useEffect in React Native apps,
and you learned how you can implement such a game
with React Native.
Now we did have a look at a lot of special cases.
You learned some tips and tricks
regarding styling and laying things out,
and for example, building custom buttons -
and that's what I mean.
I can only encourage you to build up on that
and practice all these things in your own demo apps.
Dive into the official docs
and get comfortable working with those core components
and with styling those components.
Now the final app we built here
could definitely be improved even more.
You could extract more components,
you could build more reusable components.
You could maybe use this style cascading effect
which we use here with the instruction text
where we merge an incoming style
with a built-in default style.
You could definitely use all these things
in different parts of this game.
I did not optimize all that code
in the best possible way,
because I A: Wanted to keep related concepts
and styles together to a certain extent,
and B: this already is a huge section and we wanna move on
and learn more exciting features React Native has to offer.
For example, in the next core section, we're going to build
up on this game and we're going to make sure
that it adapts to different screen sizes and platforms.
That we render slightly different styles
or layouts on different platforms,
that we can for example rotate the device,
and then also use this in landscape mode
instead of just portrait mode,
and a couple of other are interesting things.
That's what we will explore next, but for the moment
that's it for this section.