So let's dive into React Native
and let's of course start with the basics.
In this course section,
we are going to explore the core React Native concepts.
This means that we'll dive
into the core React Native Components,
and we will start building user interfaces
with those Components,
but we will of course also dive
into styling React Native apps.
We will learn how we can style those apps
and those Components,
such that we can really build the user interface
we wanna build.
And last but definitely not least,
we will explore how we can add interactivity to our app
and how we can manage state,
how we can make sure that there,
for example are buttons that can be clicked
and that something meaningful happens
when a button is clicked.
Now for this, in this course section,
we are going to build this demo app here.
It's a first simple React Native app
which allows you to track your goals.
For example, your goals for this course,
what you wanna achieve by taking this course
or as you are taking this course.
In this app, we got a list of goals
and we can open a model
and overly to add new goals.
And once a goal was added,
we can also tap the goal to remove it again.
This is maybe not the next billion dollar app
but it's a great first app
to learn about many core fundamentals you must know
about React Native.