So, let's dive into React Native.
For this, I'm back in this project
we created in the first course section.
In case you did not create it there
or you did remove it thereafter,
just make sure you got
the development environment set up mentioned there,
and then you can download
the attached starting project.
Once you did that, you will get the same code
as I have it here.
Just make sure that you open your terminal
or command prompt.
Here, I'm using the one integrated in this code
and that you install all the dependencies
this project needs, by running npm install.
And once that completed, you can run npm start
to this Expo process
that watches the code and builds the preview
and serves it on our emulators.
I'll then press a and i
to start and run this app
on my running Android and iPhone
emulators and simulators.
Here you go.
These are my two preview devices.
Now, and actually as we already got some code
on which we worked in the first course section already,
and what we have in here in the end
is a React component, a Functional React component.
And indeed, in this course,
we will only work with functional components
and React hooks.
We will not use class based components.
So this is a regular functional component.
We also got this Styles constant,
this SyleSheet object down there.
And I will come back to that in a couple of minutes.
At the top of this file, we got some imports
and we're importing one component
from an Expo related package.
And the other components, namely View and Text
as well as this SyleSheet object here,
from React Native.
And Text and View are two
of those built in components,
actually two of the most important
built in components,
React Native exposes to you,
to use in your JSX code.
Because in here, you can't use divs or h2 tags
or anything like this.
These are HTML elements, which work in the browser
when you have a DOM to work with,
but they won't work here on a Native device,
because Native devices are not browsers.
They don't have that DOM,
and they don't support those HTML elements.
Keep this slide from the first course section in mind,
that is how React Native translates different elements
into different Native elements
for Android and iOS.
And that's why these components are exposed
by React Native.
Now, if you visit the official React Native website,
then there, you will find various guides
which you can definitely take a look at
but you will also find the components tab
where you get a list of the components
provided by React Native.
And as you can tell,
we actually don't have that many components here
because it turns out
that with a couple of core components,
you can build any kind of user interface.
For example, we got a Button here
and Image and Text and View.
And especially View and Text and Text Input
are super important components
which you will use all the time.
And as you will learn from this course,
you can build very complex user interfaces
with those core components that you have here.
Now, React Native is all about working
with those core components that are built into it.
You build your overall app UI
and your custom components
that might make up that UI,
by simply combining those core components.
Because these core components, as you learned,
are translated into Native UI widgets,
Native UI elements for Android and iOS
by a React Native.
That's why we work with those core components
that are provided by React Native.
And we can combine them in our React Code,
in our JSX code, to build our own components
and ultimately our own user interface.
So in the end, we just compose our components
by combining those core opponents.
And if you think about it,
that's the same for React for the web.
HTML happens to have more elements.
There are h1, h2 elements, divs, article section,
there are many HTML elements.
But in the end, you also just combine
those HTML elements to build the web user interface.
It's the same here for Native apps.
So that's what we do with those components.
Of course, another important aspect
of building user interfaces in general
is that you wanna style those apps.
And when using React Native, there is no CSS.
You can't write CSS code,
because again, it's not a browser,
so the CSS language doesn't exist here.
Instead, you can, of course, still apply Styles,
but you do this either in line,
essentially by using props
on those core components that are provided
or with help of these SyleSheet objects
or this SyleSheet object
which you already saw in the code before.
You therefore. write your styling in JavaScript.
And hence, you have no extra styling language.
It's all JavaScript, but the React Native team
gives you a lot of JavaScript properties
which you can set and pass to those core elements,
which are similar to the CSS properties.
But it's only a subset
of the overall CSS property and feature set.
But in the end, as you will learn
throughout this Course,
you get all the important CSS properties
and features that you need
to build powerful and beautiful user interfaces.
But back here in our component code,
we can see how these core components
that are provided by React Native
are combined to build a new component,
in this case, the only component, the app component,
and how we then get this StyleSheet object,
which is used to set various styles
which if you take a look at those properties,
look similar to what you know from CSS.
And then actually this Styles object is provided
to this View component through a style prop.
But we will take a closer look at styling
and at building our own components in general
throughout the next minutes and hours, of course.
Now, just one final note about this app component:
At the moment, this is our only component here.
And indeed the app component in the app JS file
has a special purpose.
This is the root component
that is rendered in your app.
Expo will automatically take this component,
export it in this app JS file,
and render this as the root component.
So, any other user interface elements and components
must go into this app component
or into children or descendants of this app component.
But again, that is also something we'll explore
in greater details soon.