So let's explore how we can build
real layouts where we don't just have a bunch of
centered texts and buttons.
And for this, I will actually clean up my JSX content
and I will remove this style prop here
on the outer view for the moment
and remove all the styling here in this style sheet object
but I will keep the style sheet object.
And now here in my view,
I actually wanna add a neverview
and below that a neverview.
Now I'm doing this because
I wanna start building a basic interface here
that allows us to manage goals.
And the first view,
the first nested view here I should say,
should actually hold the input area
where users can enter the text for their goal
and click a button to add that goal.
And the second view should later hold the list of goals
that are rendered.
And I'm using two views as rappers
to have a clear separation between these two areas,
and because data will help me with styling.
So for this, I'll then therefore start
by adding a text input component here in the first view.
This is a component that allows users to enter text
and like all components, all core components,
we need to import it from react-native.
Now text input is a self-closing component.
And here we can, for example, add some placeholder text
as you could add it to a input element in the web
and say, your course goal.
Then, next to it I want to add a button
with the title of add goal.
And then here in this view, I will add a text element
where I say, list of goals
and later this will become a real list.
Now, if we save all of that,
we see that everything is crunched here at the top.
We also see that it goes beneath the status bar
and there would be different ways of fixing this.
For the moment, I'll fix it
by giving this outer view a style prop
and defining a style, which I'll name, app container.
And in there I'll add a padding of, let's say, 50 pixels.
And then here we can refer to styles.appContainer
to add to this padding to the overall outer view.
Now, if you save this,
we can see that there's more space around our UI.
Again, later, we will learn about different ways
of making sure that we don't interfere
with those native status bars and so on.
Now, still, this is not the layout I want.
For example, I want the button to be next to this input,
not beneath it.
I also want to have more space between the list of goals
and maybe this area where we add a goal
should take up a quarter of the overall height
and the list should take up the rest.
And that's where we need new styling features.
Styling properties about which we haven't learned before.
Specifically, we need flex box.