When it comes to building layouts
in React Native apps, Flexbox is super important.
And you might know Flexbox from the web and CSS.
And then the next lecture, will have a little deep dive
into Flexbox and how to use it.
But Flexbox is a key approach, a key concept
which is basically a collection of CSS properties
that you use to control how things look like.
And the Flexbox implemented here in React Native,
which can be set with all those React Native properties,
is very similar to what you know from CSS Flexbox.
In the end Flexbox is all about a couple of CSS properties,
or a couple of styling properties to be precise here,
that are about positioning elements inside of containers.
You can control how much space certain elements take up,
and if they are to the left or right,
or bottom or top of other elements.
And the positioning is then controlled
with the style settings that you apply to the container
that holds other elements, as you will see in a second.
Now Flexbox is all about Q-axis
which you have on a container.
For example, the styles which you see here at the top,
flex one, flex-direction: column, and so on,
would be applied to the container
that holds the three boxes inside of it.
Now the flex one instruction here, for example,
would tell the container that it should expand
to occupy all available space, though as you will see soon,
this is seen in relation to other containers
that might also take up space.
And then flex-direction controls whether the elements
are laid out in a column as you see it here,
or in a row as you see it here.
So that all works.
Basically, flex-direction controls if the main axis,
as it's called, is top to bottom or left to right.
With column, it's top to bottom,
with row, it's left to right.
And then you also got other properties like justify-content
or align items that allow you to control
how the elements are laid out in their axis.
So if there is some space between them,
if there are crunched together and so on.