In this lecture,
I wanna dive a bit deeper into Flexbox especially regarding
how you use it in React Native apps.
If you know all about that already,
you can of course skip this lecture.
So for this, I prepared a simple dummy application
and of course, you find data attached.
It's a normal React Native app built with Expo.
And in the App.js file here,
what I have in the end, is just a view with three views
in there where each view then has a text
with text one, two, three.
This simply creates some boxes
with different colors, red, blue, and green.
And now we'll use Flexbox to move these boxes around
so that you can get a feeling for how Flexbox works,
because it's so important.
Now, first things first, by default,
every view in React Native,
even if you assign no special styles, uses Flexbox.
And that's different to the web, for example.
There, if you have a div, which would be your equivalent
to a view kind of,
it doesn't use Flexbox by default.
In React Native, it does.
Every view by default organizes its children
with the help of this Flexbox thing.
Flexbox simply is, is a term,
It's simply a concept from CSS
that is all about organizing child elements
in a one dimensional space.
So here, for example, in a column.
That's also in every default,
not only does every view by default you use Flexbox,
it also by default organizes children in a column,
so from top to bottom.
That's all the difference to the web
and I don't wanna emphasize these differences too much
because of course you don't need to be a web developer
to build React Native apps.
But I think a lot of people do know web development,
do know a CSS Flexbox, and therefore it makes sense
to all the talk about the differences.
So in the web, when you use Flexbox
not only is it not turned on by default,
in addition if you do turn it on,
the default is to organize all child elements in a row.
And here, the default is to organize them in a column.
You can change that default though.
So in this case, on the view, which holds my boxes
by adding flexDirection here,
and setting this to row, for example.
Now, you will see that these three boxes are organized
in a row from left to right.
Now besides row and column,
you also have row reverse and column reverse.
And this simply also, well does what the name implies,
now we still have a row,
but the first element, the red box, actually is on the right
and not on the left anymore.
So that's also something you can do.
Let me go back to row view.
So that's the first thing you can do.
Another important thing about Flexbox
is how child elements are sized.
Here, I gave every child element
a width and a height of 100.
Now, if we would remove that width and height thing
on every child element, then you will see
that now we have a very, very small row here
because every box now is only as wide
as its child requires it to be.
And only as tall as its child requires it to be.
So every box here which holds a number
is only as wide and tall as the number it's containing.
Now, you can change that
with the surrounding Flexbox container 2.
Let's give that width of let's say 300 pixels
or of 80% of the parent width.
So in this case,
since it's the root element of the device width,
and let's give it a height of, let's say 300.
If we do that, and now really important,
I'm doing this on the view, which holds all these boxes.
I'm not doing it on the boxes themselves.
So if we assign this width and height
on the surrounding box, you see something interesting.
The height is assumed for all the elements.
Now, all the views
in the Flexbox take the height of the parent.
The width has no impact here.
That's also a default behavior you got here,
obviously since we haven't changed anything.
The default behavior here indeed, is that the child elements
in a Flexbox, so in this outer view here,
are organized such that they align themselves
along the cross axis by stretching.
Okay, that were a lot of terms,
what does this mean?
Now, when working with Flexbox,
we have two important axis.
The main axis depends on your flex direction.
For row, which we have here, flex direction row.
the main axis is from left to right.
For a row reverse, it would be right to left.
For column, it would be top to bottom
and for column reverse it would be bottom to top.
So that's the main axis.
And then you also have a cross axis
and that's simply the opposite of the main axis.
So for a row where the main axis is from left to right
the cross axis would be from top to bottom.
If the main axis is from right to left
which would be the case for row reverse
then the cross axis would be from bottom to top.
Okay, so that's the main axis and cross axis concept.
Now, you can organize your child elements.
So in this view where we have the free boxes
as child elements,
you can organize these child elements along these axis.
You use justifyContent to organize elements
along the main axis.
And you have alignItems to organize elements
around the cross axis.
Now you see the values you got for justifyContent here.
If you add these quotes
or if you place your cursor in there
and you hit control+space.
You see you can center elements, you can position them
at the end or at the start of that container
or you can add some space in between.
For example, if we use space between here
and we use alignItems center, then things will change.
Now, you will see they're taking the width
of the surrounding container,
every box itself still is pretty small
but they're split or they're distributed
across the width of the parent container.
And they're no longer taking the height
because along the cross axis,
we're aligning them with align items.
And there I set this to center.
The default here is stretch.
And if I set it back to stretch,
then unsurprisingly they do stretch for the entire height.
Now, if you want to make sure
that they take the available width,
you can set stretch here on justify content
which is your main axis positioning vehicle.
So you can set stretch here.
So what can you do regarding that then?
Well, that is something you now configure
on every child item itself.
You can tell a child item how much space it should take
off the space it's potentially getting.
Stretch here is kind of a special case,
there you set this up on the parent item.
Normally, you set this up on the child item.
So for example, if I set this to center now
so that the parent doesn't tell the child
how much space it should take.
then we can fully control the space a child takes
by going to the child style.
And there you can add flex, the flex property.
The flex property is applied
to items that are inside of a Flexbox,
so that are inside of a view in this case here.
And that can be a view itself
but that could also be another component
like a text, for example.
So now here you can add flex
and you can set this to a value of one, for example.
So flex needs to be a number.
If you set this to one,
what you will see is that now the red container
where I did set flex to one,
takes all the available width it can get
just so much that it leaves enough space
for the blue and the green container
so that they can squeeze their content
into the surrounding Flexbox.
Now, we can't see the boundaries
of the surrounding container
but the boundaries would essentially be where
the red item starts
and the green item ends on the horizontal axis here.
So now flex 1 makes sure
that the red item gets as big as it can get,
So it takes as much space as it can get.
but default views only take as much space
as their child elements require.
So as this one character required,
but with flex one you change this
and they now take as much space along the main axis.
So along the width here, as they can get.
For the cross axis, again, that's a special case,
You have to do this on the parent.
For the main axis, and since we have row here,
the main axis is a horizontal axis from left to right,
you do this with the flex property on a child.
Now, of course you can add flex
to other child elements as well.
Like to the second, to the blue container,
with the two in there.
You can add flex 1 there as well.
So now I have flex 1 on the red container
and flex 1 on the blue container.
And what now happens is that both of them
take the available free space, and amongst these two boxes,
the space is distributed evenly.
And that's what this number here indicates.
This number is a relative number.
All items in the same Flexbox
with the flex property distribute the available space
by considering the number you assign here.
And these numbers are relative to each other,
so if I give the blue container flex 2 here,
then this means that of the available space you have
in that surrounding container.
After deducting the space,
every element needs to squeeze its content in there.
The blue container will take twice as much space
as this one, because here we have flex 1,
here we have flex 2.
If we had flex 3 here,
then this would take three fifths
of the available free space,
because we have three plus two,
so we have five available segments, so to say.
And here the red container would take three segments,
blue container would take two segments.
If we have one and two,
then we have three available segments,
and the blue container takes two of them,
red takes one.
So you always add up these flex numbers
and then distribute or that's automatically done, of course
but then the available space is distributed accordingly.
So now here we'll see
that the blue container is twice as big as the red one
or it takes twice as much free space as the red one.
So this is how you can work with flex.
You can organize how items are positioned
with flex-direction, with justify content
and with align items.
And you can also make your items grow
and shrink the help of flex.
So now that's our brief introduction to Flexbox
in React Native.
As I said, inspired by Flexbox for CSS.
So if you knew that,
all of what I explained here is probably not new to you.
We'll work with Flexbox throughout this course,
so there're things also will become clearer
and we'll work a lot with it.
And you'll see you how you can create beautiful
user interfaces with Flexbox.
Flexbox in the end is the tool
in React Native to structure your content
on a page, to organize your content.
And you would typically work with a lot of views
which you also nest into each other
so that you can position elements the way you want.
Because of course, and that's also important,
you don't just have to have one view in your app
which uses Flexbox.
You could have another view
in there which also uses Flexbox.
And actually, as I mentioned
every view by default uses Flexbox
and you can then nest these views into each other
so that you position everything the way you want.
And you'll also see this in this module already.
And actually I'm already doing it here in my views here
which are in the surrounding view.
So my boxes here, there I also use justifyContent
and alignItems to center my numbers in these boxes.
So that one, two and three are centered there
horizontally and vertically.
And that works because we have Flexbox turned
on by default and we can't turn it off by the way.
And therefore, I just use these two properties here
to align my content of this view
along the main and the cross axis.
And here, since I have set no special flex direction
for this view, the main axis is top to bottom
because the default flex direction is column
and the cross axis is left to right.
That's just a side note.