So we did add some styling
and a basic layout.
This is nice,
but of course, not all we wanna do.
In most apps,
no matter if we're talking about web apps
or native mobile apps,
we also want to allow the user to interact with the app.
And we got a text input here
and we also got a button that could be pressed,
but at the moment, of course,
nothing happens if you type here
or if you press this button,
this is ignored.
And this is ignored
because we're not handling these events.
And just as with a web app that you're building with React,
you, of course, need to handle them
if you want something to happen.
The good news is that you do handle events in the same way
you would do it in web apps though.
You can add event listeners
and connect them to event handler functions
and you can manage state in your components
with the useState Hook,
just as you would do it in any other React app.
Because this is just a React app,
the only difference,
as you learned
in the first course section,
compared to a React app that targets the web
is that we use a different platform
with React Native instead of React DOM.
But when it comes to React's core features
like handling events or managing state,
that all works in exactly the same way
as you know it from React for the web.
And here I got two events that I wanna handle.
The first one would be a click on this button
but before we handle that
I also wanna handle keystrokes on that TextInput element
so that I can grab the value the user entered
and so that we can then use this value
to finally add a new goal
in this list of goals as a next step.
And therefore,
these are the first two things I wanna do.
I will add a function
that could be called goalInputHandler
that is responsible for fetching that user input
as the user types.
Then I'll another function addGoalHandler
which should be fired when this button here is clicked.
Now to connect those functions,
we use special event listening props
that are provided by React Native on its components.
For example,
to connect goalInputHandler to TextInput,
we can add the special onChangeText prop.
This is a prop exposed by React Native
which wants a function as a value,
a pointer at a function.
In my case, I'll point at this goalInputHandler function.
So I'll pass that as a value here
and I'll press the auto format shortcut
to make this a bit easier to read.
Now, please note that I don't execute this function here.
I don't add parentheses.
If you would add parentheses
this function would be executed
as soon as this code is parsed and evaluated.
And this would be too soon,
because that would be the case
when this user interface is rendered.
I don't wanna do that.
Instead, I wanna point at this function
so that React can execute it for me
whenever this text changes in this input
and that's what will happen
if we set it up like this.
Now in this goalInputHandler function here,
we then receive the entered value automatically
because keep in mind,
it will be React that calls this function
because it's React Native that exposes this prop.
And therefore, React,
or to be precise React Native,
will also provide us a value as a input
as a parameter to this function
and that will be the enteredText.
So we get the enteredText automatically.
And then we could, for example,
console.log this here.
Like this.
If we save this code
and we have the npm-start process up and running,
we can go back here.
And for example,
enter Test.
And as I type this here,
you see the log update here in my terminal
with every keystroke until we have the word Test.
So that's how this works
and this works totally on its own.
So that's how we can get the entered value.
Of course, we don't want to get the value
because we need it in this function though.
Instead, we need it in this function.
So we need it when the button is clicked.
And for this,
we need to connect this function
to a button click as a first step.
Now, if you would be building a web app
and you had a HTML button here,
you would add the onClick prop
but with React Native,
this prop doesn't exist on a button.
But we have a similar prop,
it's called onPress.
It's called onPress instead of onClick
because technically we don't have clicks
in native mobile apps.
Instead, we have taps or presses.
So here we have onPress.
And just as with onChangeText,
here I point at my function that should be executed.
In this case, addGoalHandler.
So now this function will be triggered
whenever the button is clicked or tapped.
Now we want the value entered
in this TextInput
in this function.
So what we need to do
is we need to store it as state.
We need to store it as state
which is updated with every keystroke in this function
so that we can then use it
in this second function.
And state management
works just as it works
in any other React app.
We can import the useState Hook from React.
So not from React Native,
but from React:
the core React library itself.
And then we can register a new state here
in our App component function
just as we do it in any other React app.
So here I'll call useState
and set this to an empty string initially,
because this will be my user input state
or my enteredGoalText state,
which can be updated with the setEnteredGoalText function.
And then in case this syntax doesn't tell you anything,
definitely have a look at some dedicated React resources
like my React complete guide course
because this is standard React
and you should know syntax like this.
So now we got this enteredGoalText state,
which initially is an empty string,
but with every keystroke in my TextInput,
I will update it
and set my enteredGoalText
to the enteredText I'm receiving here as a parameter.
And therefore, now,
in addGoalHandler,
we can access this state
and do something with it.
And for the moment,
I will simply console.log my enteredGoalText state here.
But of course, soon,
we will update a list of goals
which we then output down there.
So let's save this.
And now here,
if I enter Test
and click Add Goal,
we got this Test log here.
Or if we enter Some other text!
to see that this is really coming from our updated code.
Now we see Some other text!, here.
So this is working as intended.
The next step now
is to make sure that we can manage a list of goals,
which we then can also output.