So let's now manage that list of goals.
For this I will again add some state here
because my list of goals
is also some data that changes dynamically
and as it changes, the UI should be updated.
And that's a typical case for using state.
And this state will be initialized with an empty array
because I wanna manage a list of goals
and initially I have no goal.
Now I'll give this state a name of course, goals,
because these are my goals for this course, let's say.
And to set course goals, updating function.
And now in add goal handler,
instead of logging our entered text to the console,
we can call set course goal and update our goals.
And in the end I wanna take my existing goals
and append a new one.
Now, there are various ways of doing that.
One way would be to create a new array
and use the spread operator, these three dots,
which is standard JavaScript code,
modern JavaScript code,
to spread existing course goals into this new array,
so that I keep all the existing course goals.
And then I add my new goal,
by adding the entered goal text,
let's say, as a new goal.
In this case, a goal is simply a string.
We could do this, but if you followed a good React resource,
like my course or the official docs, then you know
that this is not the best way of updating state
if your new state depends on the previous state.
Which this state here does.
If your new state depends on the previous state,
a better way of updating
is to pass a function to this state updating function,
a function which will be called automatically by React
Q then derive the new state.
And this function will automatically
receive the existing state by React.
So here we could turn this into an arrow function
that gets the current course goals as a input, let's say.
So as a parameter.
And again, the value for this parameter
will be provided automatically by React
when it calls this updating function
or this function that's passed to the updating function,
to be precise.
And now this value, current core goals,
can be used inside this arrow function body.
And now we do derive this new state in a better way.
The other approach would've worked as well
but this is a recommended way,
a best practice way of updating your state.
So now we're updating this course goal state
based on the old course goals by appending a new goal.
The next step of course
is to now output the list of goals here.
And how does this work?
Well, it works basically
as it does in React for the web as well.
We have an array of values which we wanna output
and in React for the web we would use the map method,
typically, to map our array of data, of strings, or objects,
into an array of JSX elements which can then be output
in the JSX code returned by this component.
And we can do the same thing here.
Instead of outputting this dummy text down there,
I want to output something dynamic,
which we do by adding curly braces, opening and closing.
We can now refer to the course goals array,
and call the map method on it.
A standard JavaScript method
because we are writing standard JavaScript code here.
As you learned.
Now, this map method receives a function, as it always does,
and here I'll pass in an arrow function,
which as an argument, as a parameter,
gets the individual values stored in course goals,
so my goals here,
the single goals I have in this array of goals,
this function is called for every item in the array.
So every function called receives a single goal.
And then as a return value in this arrow function,
we returned a JSX element
that should be rendered for the individual goal.
And in this case, I wanna output the goal text.
So here I will render a text JSX element,
and then between the opening and closing text
I output goal.
Since my goals are just strings here in this array
because I just add my entered goal text,
which is just the text that was provided,
and therefore just a string,
I can simply output the goal between those text like this
because goal will just be a string.
And with that, if we save this
and we give this a try here.
Learn React Native.
If I click add goal, this is added
but we also get a warning here.
The same will be true on the iPhone here.
If I learn React Native, it works.
If I learn it with multiple exclamation marks
I still see that it works.
I add another goal now as expected
but we get a warning here.
We get a warning that each child in a list
should have a unique key prop.
And this is actually a warning you might know
from React for the web as well,
because this is a warning
that has nothing to do with React Native.
Instead with React in general,
when outputting a list of data, as we're doing it here,
every item in that list should receive a key prop
which uniquely identifies the individual list item.
Under the hood this helps React
update the list in an efficient way, so to say.
I do explain this in greater detail in my React course,
but you should always add this key prop
to the individual items
that you're outputting as part of a list.
Now, the value you pass to key can be anything
but it should be something unique
that uniquely identifies the concrete value
that you're outputting here.
In this case, I'm just outputting goals,
which are just strings,
so I'll take the goal string itself.
This is actually not necessarily unique
because I could enter the exact same goal text twice
but it's good enough for now, we'll improve this soon.
Now with this key prop added here though.
Now, if I add another goal, I don't get the warning again.
And of course here,
we don't have to enter the same text all the time.
We can also learn different pieces of text,
like learn all the details,
and as you see, our list keeps on growing here.
So with that, we're now able to handle the user input,
store it and React to a tap on this button.
And then we do something which you certainly did
many times with React for the web.
We're outputting that data here in a list,
but that's of course not all we want to do.