Outputting the data in a list
as we're doing it here is nice
but it would also be nice to have some styling
on those list items.
And therefore, that's what I wanna do next,
of course feel free to also pause the video here
and practice this on your own.
Apply some styling, any styling of your choice
to these individual list items,
and then compare your solution
to mine to see how I style this.
Now, here's what I will do.
I will create a new object that keeps
or that holds the styles for those list items.
And I'll name it, goal item.
The name is up to you though,
here in this style sheet object, and then in this object
which defines the styles for this identifier, you can set up
any styles you want, and I'll give every goal item
a little bit of margin, for example
so that we have some spacing around it, maybe eight pixels.
I also wanna add a border radius here
so that we have rounded corners
and this also wants a value, that's defined as a number.
And here I'll set this to six pixels.
Now to make sure that we can see this radius,
I will give this a background color
so that this item has an overall background color
of a specific hex code that I prepared ahead of time
which is five E zero A C C, which is a nice purple color.
I also wanna have some padding in here
so I'll actually add it next to the margin
not because it's required
but to keep those related values together.
And I'll add a padding of, let's say eight pixels as well.
So that we have some inner spacing as well.
And last but not least, I also want to add a color here
and I'll set this to white and this will be the text color.
So again, you see the property names are pretty similar
to what you know from CSS.
We of course have this camel casing instead of using dashes
because dashes are not supported in JavaScript
but besides that, the names should look familiar.
Now we can assign this goal item style
to our text items here.
So here we can add the style prop
and set this equal to styles.goalItem.
And I'll reformat this to make it a bit easier to read.
With that, if we save this,
this updates and we see our items here.
What you will see is that we got this changed styling
but actually on iOS, the rounded corners are missing.
We only have them on Android.
Now, why are they missing here?
And what can we do to fix the styling there as well?
This is a good time to talk
about the differences between the two platforms.
The idea behind React Native is that you can write code
with React that will actually give you native mobile apps
for multiple target platforms.
So you don't need to write different code
to target different platforms,
but one of the same code base can get you there.
Now this is generally true,
but as you will also learn later in the course,
sometimes there are differences
and sometimes you need to make tiny code adjustments
to target all platforms in the right way.
And for example, here, we got a difference.
The rounded corners are missing
on iOS because we added our styling here
that applies the rounded corners directly
on this text component.
Now it turns out
that this text component is translated by React Native
to a fitting native widget, a native UI element.
And the element to which it is translated
in case of Android seems to be an element
where corners can be rounded.
But in case of iOS,
it looks like the underlying native text output element
does not support rounded corners.
And that's why border radius has no effect
on the text elements on iOS.
Now to work around that,
we can wrap our text here in a view.
So in this more generic container element,
this is also translated to a fitting underlying element.
And it turns out that the underlying element
to which view is compiled by React Native is an element
that supports surrounded corners on both platforms.
How do I know that?
From the official docs and experience
and I'm explaining it to you in this course
so that you don't have to find it out the hard way.
So what we can do now is
we can grab our style assignment here
and add this on this view
and also add the key here on this view,
because now the view is the main element
that's output here in the list.
The text now is a nested element.
We still need the text
because we still have some text to output.
And as you learned before, text must go between text text
but the styling is now applied
to the more versatile view element.
If we do that and we save everything
we now see the rounded corners on iOS as well.
What we also see though
is that the text is no longer white.
Now we still have the color white setting here
but this is part of the goal item, which now
is actually assigned to this view here, not to the text
and unlike in CSS for the web, the styles don't cascade.
That's another important learning here.
We do have this CSS like property language here
if you wanna call it like that,
these CSS like property names, but it's not CSS.
It never was.
So therefore core CSS characteristics
like the cascading nature of CSS, where child elements
and descendant elements, inherit styles from parent
and ancestor elements is not part
of React Native's styling approach.
We don't have style inheritance here.
So if we assign a text color to the view,
this does not affect this text
or the text inside this text text to be precise
because that's a totally standalone element.
It is not related to this view.
It does not inherit any styles from that view.
So setting the text color on this view does nothing
to the text inside that text element.
Therefore, what we need to do
is add another style object here,
the goal text, that sounds like a fitting name.
And we set our text color on that
and remove it from goal item on the view.
We could leave it there,
but it doesn't have any effect, anyways.
With that, we now set our text color here
and now we can add this goal text style to this text here.
So we add the style prop
and set this equal to styles.goalText.
And with this, if we save this now,
we now have the white text back
and we have the rounded corners.
And this is really important.
This is something you must understand
about styling and about targeting different platforms.
The general idea is that you have one code base
that targets both platforms
but still there are differences under the hood.
And some differences can simply be solved like this
by adding an extra wrapper.
Later in the course,
you will also learn that sometimes you need
to write totally different code for different platforms
and you will learn how that works as well.
And you also learned
that styling is a bit different than in the browser.
It looks like CSS, at least a bit
but there is no inheritance and no cascading going on.
That's why you really have to set the styles
on the elements where they are supported instead
of some global parent element,
just as the rounded corners couldn't be applied to the text,
the text color applied to this view didn't have any effect
to the internal text here.
We need to set that on the appropriate text element.
And these are these tiny details, which you will see over
and over again throughout this course
and which are super important when you are working
with React Native.
But with this, we now got the look we want here
and hence, we can now move on and dive a bit deeper
into how we can and should output lists like this.