So we got our list here.
Now, one thing you will notice about this list
is that if I add more and more items here
and I just add exclamation marks to make them unique,
at some point we will go beyond the available space.
Now you would expect that you simply scroll now,
but it turns out you can't scroll.
No matter how you try, this is not scrollable.
Because by default the view generated here,
this view that holds everything in our app component
is not scrollable.
That's also a difference compared to the browser.
On a website, if you exceed the available space
by default scrolling bars will appear,
and you can scroll the website.
This is not the case here in mobile apps.
If you want to scroll,
you have to explicitly tell React Native
and the native platforms.
Now, of course,
this is a common problem and scenario though,
and, therefore, making lists,
or content in general, scrollable, is very easy.
There is a dedicated component provided by React Native
that helps you.
And that's the ScrollView.
We import ScrollView from React Native just
as we imported text input button and so on.
And ScrollView does what the name implies,
It gives you a view so such a container element,
which will be scrollable.
And therefore we can now use this ScrollView
around our goals here.
So let's try replacing this view here
with our ScrollView, simply.
We add ScrollView here instead of view
around our list of goals.
And I leave my style on this ScrollView.
Keep in mind this style here controls
that this container takes up a lot of space.
If we save this, this doesn't look too good.
This now is indeed scrollable, as you see,
but the space is different than it was before,
we have way more space for the input
and way less space for the list.
The reason for that is that the ScrollView has the job
of making something scrollable, but the area
that's scrollable is in the end determined by the current,
the container that holds the ScrollView.
So what you should do here is add another normal view,
which restricts the available height,
to which you then apply the style
that sets the height that will be taken up by that view.
So that is the setup we had before, but now we
have a ScrollView inside of that view.
So the outer view, controls how much space this area
of the screen should take up.
And the inner ScrollView then makes sure that this
space, and the items in that space, to be precise,
will be scrollable inside that overall space.
That's how we set up such a ScrollView,
and how we let it interact with the surrounding container.
If we set it up like this and we save everything,
we get the same proportions as before,
but now, indeed, as you see, this list is scrollable here.
And that's, of course, what we want,
because now we have a list
where we can add more and more items
and it stays scrollable as we exceed the available space.
Of course, if I force a reload,
by pressing R here in the terminal.
And I then go back, all the data is lost,
and now you see, nothing seems to be scrollable here.
If I add a single goal here,
we do see, though,
that this is indeed scrollable,
but of course it's not really scrollable,
It always jumps back to the top because
we don't exceed the available height.
So, ScrollView is super useful because it does allow you
to make lists, or content in general, scrollable.
Now you can learn more about ScrollView
and the props it supports in the official docs.
I wanna draw your attention to those props here,
because there is a lot you can configure,
about the ScrollView.
You can, for example, configure how it bounces,
and you'll also see that some props are specific to iOS.
And others specific to Android,
whilst yet others are available for both platforms.
And again, these are some of these platform differences,
which we will encounter here
and then throughout this course.
For example, you will notice
that in our app here, I can scroll
and I have this bouncing effect.
If I would want to disable this,
I could set always bounce vertical,
which is true by default, to false.
So if I go to ScrollView,
and I set always bounce vertical to false,
and I then save this, you will notice that here in iOS,
if I now try to scroll,
this bouncing effect, which we had before, is gone.
Now, if I add more and more goals to make sure
that I exceed the available space here, at some point,
it still is scrollable,
and now it also bounces, but it didn't bounce,
if there was not enough content to fill the available space,
the available height here.
If you do want to set this or not as totally up to you and
which look and feel you want, but it is important to
be aware of the vast configuration options you have here.
And therefore taking a look at those props here,
and understanding what you can set
and how you can use this view is definitely
something I would encourage you to do
because every app you're building will be different
and every app needs slightly different configuration.
And therefore the official docs are always
a great place where you can find all kinds
of supported configuration settings.