So we got our scrollable list here,
and this is implemented with this ScrollView.
Now, this solution has one downside,
one disadvantage though.
ScrollView is great,
if you wanna add scrolling around some content.
For example, if you had an article,
which would be too long to fit on a screen
or you simply don't know
which device sizes your users will be using
and you wanna make sure that an article for example,
is scrollable.
In such situations, ScrollView is perfect.
For lists as we have it here, it's not perfect though.
The reason for that is,
that lists like this could become very long.
Sure, you might only have like 10 or 20 items on there.
And especially for such a goal list,
it's very likely that you have around that size
or around that amount of items.
But you could also have lists
with hundreds or thousands of items.
Now, what ScrollView does is,
it always renders all the items that are inside of it
whenever the overall UI is rendered.
So even if an item is not currently on the screen
like this last list item here,
this item is still rendered behind the scenes
even though it's not visible yet.
Because ScrollView renders all its child items,
no matter if we're talking about 10, 20, or 10,000 items.
And for very long list, this can become a performance issue.
If you have a long list
with dozens or hundreds or thousands of items,
rendering them all at the beginning
even though vast majority is not even visible to the user,
will slow down the app.
And of course, that's not something we want.
Therefore ScrollView is great for limited amounts of content
like an article which has a fixed end at some point.
But for dynamic lists, which could become super long.
We typical don't wanna use ScrollView.
We can, but we typically don't want to,
to avoid possible performance issues.
A better solution for such scenarios
is another built-in component that ships with React Native,
the FlatList component,
this is another component that will help scrolling.
But as the name suggests,
it's specifically built for scrollable lists.
And internally, it will only render the items
that are actually visible.
And all the items that are off screen
will only be loaded and rendered lazily
as they are needed because the user is scrolling.
Now, internally, FlatList will have a small threshold
to make sure it already starts loading and rendering items
before they are visible.
But it will only render them as the user gets closer to them
as he or she is scrolling the list.
If you have 1000 items in your list
the vast majority of items will not be loaded
and will not be rendered when using FlatList.
So how do we with FlatList then?
Well, you do use it by replacing ScrollView with it.
So we replace ScrollView with FlatList.
Now, regarding this alwaysBounceVertical prop here,
this is still supported.
So you can leave it there because FlatList actually supports
pretty much all of the props ScrollView supports.
Because internally it kind of has a similar implementation
but with this optimization
of only loading data when it's needed.
So this is a first step, but we're not finished yet.
We replace ScrollView with FlatList.
The next step is that we get rid of our custom
mapping code here, we remove that,
we no longer map our data manually.
Instead, we now have to pass this task to FlatList
so that it can render this list efficiently
by only rendering what's needed.
FlatList is now in charge of this
hence we need to let FlatList do that.
And this is done by giving FlatList two important props.
The first one is the data prop, which is a required prop.
This is a prop that points at the data
that should be output in this list.
In our example here, that would be the courseGoals array.
That's the data that should be output as a list
so we pass this as a value to data.
But that doesn't tell FlatList
how the data should be rendered.
You don't tell FlatList by passing content like this,
between the opening and closing text,
that's not how we use FlatList.
Instead, we should cut this
and we can turn FlatList into a self-closing component.
And we add another key prop now,
and that's another required prop, the renderItem prop.
This is a prop that wants a function as a value,
a function that will tell FlatList
how to render the individual data items.
Therefore it is a function
that will receive the individual item
as a parameter, automatically.
FlatList will pass in this item
whenever it calls this function,
and it will call this function
whenever it determines that a new item must be rendered
because the user is scrolling
and a new item should be made visible.
And therefore, in this function,
in this array function which I defined here,
you then return to JSX code that should be rendered
for a given item.
Now, of course, we wanna output our item data
and we received this item parameter value
automatically by FlatList.
But this item which we get here
is actually an object generated by FlatList internally.
An object that is wrapped around the individual data items
we have in our data array.
And therefore I will actually name this itemData
because it's actually an object
that does not just contain our values,
but also some metadata.
Now, itemData does for example,
also give us access to a index property.
Again, this object with this property
is generated by FlatList.
And this holds the index
of the different items that are rendered.
First item here has an index of zero,
the second item has an index of one and so on.
But itemData also holds another property
that's very important for us
and that's the property I will output here,
the item property.
This will hold the actual data items,
one, for each list item that's being rendered.
So with itemData.item,
we get access to the different data items we have here.
Now, with that, we can get rid of this key prop
because we're no longer mapping this list manually
and hence keys are no longer managed like this.
We will come back to keys in a second
but for the moment we'll remove it.
And now I will reload the apps by pressing R here,
in the terminal with the terminal selected.
And if I now add another new item here,
you will see it shows up and I can add multiple items here.
And if I add enough items to exceed this screen height.
So if I add more and more items here,
you will see that this list also is scrollable,
I can scroll here.
But you also see of course that I'm getting a warning,
I did get it right from the start actually.
And the warning is the end, that I'm missing some keys here.
Because it's still a list
and therefore we still should add keys,
but we don't add them as we added them before.
Instead when using FlatList,
there are two main ways of adding keys to these list items.
The first approach is to turn your data values
from primitive values like strings as we have it here,
into objects that have a key property.
And that's what I'll do here.
When I add a new courseGoal,
instead of just adding the entered text like this as a goal
so as a plain string, I will wrap this into a object.
Where I, for example have a text property
that the actual goal text,
but where I actually also add a key property
which I set to a unique key.
Now, to generate a unique key here,
I will actually use Math.random toString like this.
Which is not really a unique key.
I could generate the same number twice
but it's good enough for this demo here.
And now with that every item in my course goals array
is actually an object,
an object with a text property and with a key property.
And the special thing is that FlatList
will automatically look for such a key property.
So FlatList does work with primitive values
in the data array as well
as you saw a couple of minutes ago.
But it works even better,
if your data in this data array is a list of objects.
So if you have a list of objects as data
and every object has a key property,
because then this key property
will automatically be used as a key
for the items that are rendered.
Now, that we turned our items into objects here though,
we have to make sure that when we access the data
that belongs to a single item,
we dive into the text property here on the item.
Because every item is now an object
with a text property, that's what we set up here.
Hence we have to access this text property down here.
And then with that,
if we save this and again reload this
and I now start adding items here,
you will see that now I can add items as many as I want
and I don't get this warning anymore.
And I got this strollable list.
And under the hood,
only the items that are needed are being rendered
and the other items will be loaded lazily
as we scroll closer to them.
That's how this FlatList works now.
Now, if you don't have a property named key
because you're maybe getting data from an API
and you can't influence its shape,
and you don't wanna transform it
just because flat list needs that key property.
You also got an alternative
to setting up such a key property in the input data.
Let's say this would be named ID,
this would be a reasonable property name
because this could be a unique ID.
But it would be the wrong name
because this list is not looking for an ID property
but for a key property.
Now, of course we could transform it
but if you don't wanna do that, you can go to your FlatList
and you can add another prop to the FlatList component.
And that would be the keyExtractor prop.
The keyExtractor prop wants a function as a value,
for example, an inline arrow function.
But you could also define a function somewhere else
and pass up a point or edit here.
And this is a function
which will automatically receive two parameter values,
item and index.
These two values will be provided by FlatList
when it calls this function for you.
And it will call this function for you,
for every list item that's being rendered.
Now, the renderItem function
is also called for every list item that's rendered.
But the renderItem function
is responsible for generating in the JSX code
that should be rendered for every item.
KeyExtractor on the other hand,
this function is simply called to get a key
out of every item,
which then under the hood will be attached
to the item by the FlatList.
And therefore here you should return the key.
And since you get the item as the first parameter value,
and since I know that every item for me is an object
with an ID property.
And since I know that the ID property makes for a great key
since it will be unique, I can return item.id here.
And with that, I simply tell FlatList
how it gets to a unique key for every item it outputs.
So with that, if I save this
and I then again, reload everything here.
If I again, learn React Native here, this works as before.
And I don't get any warnings.
This off course, all the works here on Android
if you wanna see it there.
I can add multiple goals there as well
and there it's also scrollable.
So that's FlatList and action, and you should use FlatList
whenever you have lists with dynamic data
that should be scrollable.
And especially if you have lists that could be super long.
Then, for performance reasons
FlatList is better than ScrollView.