So by now, we already learned
a lot about important React Native components
and concepts in general.
Our app JS file is getting bigger and bigger.
And this is something that happens in most React apps,
no matter if you're building for React Native,
or if you're building for the web.
Your components get bigger as you add more functionality.
Now, what do in such cases is you break up your components
and you split them into smaller components.
That is a common approach and a common best practice
for keeping your code maintainable.
And it's no difference here for React Native.
Thus far we're working with one component only
but this of course is the exception.
The norm is that you do work with multiple components.
And we wanna do that here as well.
For this, I'll add a new folder in my project
which I'll name "components"
because I wanna store my components in there.
You don't have to use this name
but it is a common convention
since we will be building and storing components in there.
And then I want to add two components files in there.
Goal input JS,
because there I plan to store
the data input related JSX code and functionality.
And goal item JS,
here I plan to store the actual JSX code
and functionality that is related
without putting single goal items.
And of course you could split this into more components,
if you wanted to.
Now I'll start working on this goal item component.
In there I'll add a function goal item
because I'll create a functional component
and I will export this as a default.
So I will build a standard React component in there.
Now you don't need to import React from React here.
You did need to do that in the past
but with the modern versions of React Native and React
you don't need to do that anymore
and therefore a functional component
can be created just like this.
Now in this goal item component,
I wanna return some JSX code
and I actually wanna return the code
that is responsible for outputting a single goal item.
So not the list of items, but a single item.
And that means I wanna use this code here.
Hence, I will cut this code from app JS
and return it here in goal item JS.
Now, of course, here, I'm referring to some styles though
and those styles therefore also should be brought over.
For this I have to create a new style sheet object
that belongs to this component.
So to this component file also
and hence I will import from React Native
and I will import the style sheet object here.
Which allows me to call the create method,
which creates a new React Native managed styling object,
which helps with auto completion and so on.
I'll store this in a constant named styles,
though the name is up to you,
but since I'm already referring to this kind of constant
here in my code,
I will keep the name here.
Now as a side note, we could have also passed our styles
from app component to goal item component via props.
We don't have to define the styles here
but it is a good practice to keep your styles
close to your JSX code.
And therefore I wanna move my styles
that belong to the goal item
from the app component into the goal item component as well.
And that would be these two objects
with their style properties.
I will cut them in app JS and move them over
to goal item JS.
And here in this object which we pass to the create method,
I'll paste in these two properties.
And with that, I can reference those properties
in my JSX code.
So with that, we are creating this component.
We still need to take care about this text,
but we get our first component
and then app JS we can now import this component.
We can now also get rid of some imports
which we don't need anymore because I'm, for example,
not displaying a text component in there
and I'm not using scroll view anymore
But I will now import goal item from components goal item.
And this works just as it works in our regular React app,
we import our components from other files like this,
we have a capital starting character
because we plan on using this in JSX
and we wanna make it clear to React
that this is a custom component.
Hence we start with a capital character.
Now down here in our JSX code,
where I return some markup inside of render item.
I now return my goal item component, so my own component.
And this is how we define and use a custom component.
And of course in the end it's totally the same
as we do it in a React for web project.
There isn't really any difference here.