Now of course we will need to pass some data
to goal item though, because we got the item data here
in the app component and we need it here.
And this is a problem solved With props.
Again, just as we do it in any react app
because we are building a regular react app here,
we have a regular react component
and we can use props therefore.
And we can expect and use any props we want,
because it's our component.
So here for example, we could expect
that on this props object, we get a text property,
or a value property whatever you want.
I will go with text here.
And now we just have to make sure that in the place where
we use this component, so in the app component here,
We pass this prop so that we set a text prop here,
on goal item in the app component.
And then here we have to pass in
item data dot item dot text.
Because again, text is the property that holds
the actual text and I wanna pass this text as a value
to the text prop in my goal item.
And with that if we save this and I reload everything,
if I go back and I learn React Native here, this crashes.
Because of this error, can't find variable view.
What's wrong here?
Well, what's wrong is that in the goal item component,
I'm using the view and the text components
but I'm not importing them.
And I showed this on purpose,
because this is important to understand.
If you are working with a react for the WAP,
you can use DVs and h2 elements just like this.
You don't need to import them.
That's different in React Native.
There, all these components are provided by react native,
and you have to import them in order to use them.
So besides importing the style sheet here,
we also have to import view and text,
because we are using these two components in this JSX code.
And once we import them, if we now reload our apps again,
you will see that now of course if I do learn React Native,
this works again.
And now it's looking the same way as before,
Because in the end we get the same UI as before,
but we're achieving this with help
of another custom component.