So now we got this custom component.
But we got another custom component, which I wanna build.
And this component should hold the input
related markup and logic.
Now, definitely feel free to extract the appropriate code
from App.js into GoalInput.js on your own
and build your own GoalInput component,
which you use in App.js.
In a couple of seconds, which I give you to pause the video.
We will do this together.
So, did you succeed?
Let's try this together.
Now here, I want to extract some markup into GoalInput.
For this, I'll First of all,
create a GoalInput component here,
in the GoalInput.js file and export this.
and then we wanna return some JSX code in here.
The JSX code that should be returned is the TextInput
and the Button, but I will also grab the View
that holds these elements as the container,
Because that View holds
the input related container styling.
And I wanna outsource this well.
So here, I will add this container with the TextInput
and the Button to my GoalInput.js file.
Now, just as before, we need to do a couple of things.
We need to import View, TextInput, and Button
and we need to bring over our style sheet objects.
Now, I'll start by importing,
and I will import View, TextInput, and Button
from react-native, so that we can use these components here.
And it will also import StyleSheet,
because, of course, I will create a style sheet.
I will create such a styles object here
with StyleSheet.create, so that we can set up the styles
that belong to this component in this component file.
And in our case,
that would be the inputContainer and TextInput styles.
So in App.js here, I will grab the inputContainer
and TextInput style objects,
and cut them, so that our style definitions
in App.js are now much leaner.
And it will move them over
into the GoalInput component file.
So here in this object, I'll now paste them in,
and that makes sure our styles are there.
But now we're not done.
We also are handling some state here.
We're getting the user input and we're interacting
with the main courseGoals state with help of this Button.
But now the problem, of course,
is that the courseGoals state
is managed in the App component,
whereas, the inputs are in a different component.
But that's a common problem in react apps
and not specific to react-native,
and we can solve it as we solve it in all react apps.
We can also talk to the parent component
by passing event handler functions via props.
So here, for example, we can accept props on GoalInput
and expect a special prop which could be named, onAddGoal,
to be provided by the parent component,
which actually holds a function as a value
that will be executed upon a press.
So now in the App component,
we can use the GoalInput component We just added,
we can import GoalInput from ./components/GoalInput.
And we can use this component here in that place,
where we had all the input related markup before.
And set this onAddGoal prop,
which we expect to get here in our GoalInput component.
And now, since we set this prop's value
as a value for the onPress prop,
and that prop wants a function to be executed,
we should pass a function to onAddGoal in the App component.
And we still pass our addGoalHandler here, just like this.
Now what does change though
is how we handle the user input.
How we fetch the user input?
Because this GoalInputHandler and the state
that manages the entered input is in the wrong place now.
We don't do this in the App component anymore.
Because the TextInput element is in the GoalInput component.
What we should do therefore is grab that state,
and cut it from the App component,
and move it into the GoalInput component, like this.
For this, of course, we must make sure that we import
useState from react, in this GoalInput component.
So that we can use this function here.
Now we got this state.
We also need this GoalInputHandler function,
which updates the state though.
So that in the App component, only the courseGoals state
and the addGoalHandler function is left.
We will treat this function as second as well though.
In GoalInput.js, we can now paste in
that GoalInputHandler function.
And therefore this is now,
again, connected to onChangeText,
where we point at this function.
So this enteredGoalText is still being handled here.
Now, the only problem is that this enteredGoalText
is eventually needed in the App component,
when we add a new goal.
and therefore we also need to make sure
that this data arrives here in addGoalHandler.
The easiest way of ensuring this would be
to expect the enteredGoalText as a parameter.
So that whenever addGoalHandler is called,
we get this text and we can use it in here.
Now, this function is fine.
But right now this text wouldn't be provided.
addGoalHandler is passed as a value
to onAddGoal on the GoalInput,
and onAddGoal is forwarded to onPress,
and onPress which ultimately calls this function
does not provide this enteredGoalText.
To make sure that it does,
we have to change something in our code here.
For example, we can add another function here
in our GoalInput component file
and name this function addGoalHandler, again.
So now we have this function or a function with this name
in both GoalInput and App, but that's no problem
because we're in different components here.
Hence, we have no name clash.
Now in this function,
I actually want to execute props onAddGoal.
So I want to call this onAddGoal function,
which we receive here manually
And then, onPress is connected
to this addGoalHandler function which I just added.
By calling this function manually,
I can now make sure that I forward my enteredGoalText.
So this state, I passed this as a value to the function
I receive on this onAddGoal prop.
And therefore, since function is the addGoalHandler
in the App component.
That addGoalHandler function
will receive the enteredGoalText
because I'm passing it manually here.
And again, this is nothing react-native specific.
This is standard react.
Now as extra bonus,
we could also set our enteredGoalText to an empty string
to clear it, whenever we added a new goal.
We didn't do that before but we can do it now.
And I think it is a change that makes sense.
But of course, it's up to you
whether you want to do that or not.
Here, I will do it
by setting the state back to an empty string.
With all of that, back in App component,
this should all work.
We can now get rid of some unused imports again,
which we don't need anymore.
And if we now save everything,
and reload the app on both devices,
if I now learn react-native, this goal still gets added.
Now what's not happening is that the input
would be reset though.
Actually internally it is.
If I click add goal, you see there was no text.
But it's not reflected here in the input element.
The reason for that is that I'm resetting
the state here in GoalInput,
but I'm not binding the state to TextInput.
We don't have any proper two way binding here.
We just have one way binding.
In the past, this didn't matter,
because as we never changed the text
besides typing into the TextInput field.
But now since we're also changing the state here,
like this by resetting it,
we should add a value prop to TextInput,
and bind this to the enteredGoalText.
So that whenever this goal text changes,
because we for example, reset it,
this is reflected in the TextInput.
If we now save this, and reload everything,
I can, again, learn, react-native.
Now it's reset.
And I can add my goals.
So this is now working.
And now, we split this into multiple components.
And in the end, as you see,
here we had absolutely nothing react-native specific.
Splitting our app and passing data and functions around,
that all works just as you know it from react.