We're making good progress.
We're now able to add items to our list here,
and we're managing this list in an efficient way.
Now, what we're not able to do yet though,
is remove items,
and it would be nice if you could simply tap those items
and they would be deleted.
Now to make them tappable, if this would be a web app,
all you have to do would be that you add an "onClick" prop
to the item.
That's how you would do it in the web.
But this is not how it works in React Native.
Instead here, if you wanna make an item pressable,
you have to let React Native know.
And you let React Native know by wrapping the item
that should be pressable into a specific component
provided by React Native.
And that would be the "Pressable" component.
React native also knows a component named "Touchable"
and various related components like "TouchableHighlight,"
and "TouchableNativeFeedback,"
and "TouchableOpacity,"
but those are components that are
not deprecated, but that should be replaced
by "Pressable" now.
So these "Touchable" components
are the old React Native way.
"Pressable" is the way forward.
So we use "Pressable" by simply wrapping the item
that should be pressable with it.
Like This.
In my "GoalItem," I wrap my view
with "Pressable," and with that,
this item becomes pressable.
And whenever we press any item inside of "Pressable,"
so in this case, this view with this text,
this "onPress" prop will trigger the function
that we provide to it.
So we should provide a function to "onPress"
and since I plan on deleting items in the future,
I will define this function in App.js,
because here, I'm managing my "courseGoals" state,
and here, I will have to delete items in the future.
So I will add a "deleteGoalHandler" function here in App.js.
And for the moment, I'll just "console.log('DELETE')" here
in this function.
We will of course replace this with proper code later.
Now, "deleteGoalHandler" should be provided
to the goal item,
In the infer, I'll add a prop here,
and since it's my component,
it's my choice how this prop should be named,
and I'll name it "onDeleteItem"
and pass my "deleteGoalHanlder" function to that.
A pointer to this "deleteGoalHandler" function
is passed as a value to "onDeleteItem"
on my "GoalItem" component.
And now this "onDeleteItem" prop can be used
in that component.
And here, I can for example,
simply forward it.
Like that.
We might tweak it later but for the moment,
we can just do it like this.
Now, if I save this,
If I tap on one of these items, I get no visual feedback,
but if I go back, you see the that "DELETE" was locked
to the terminal.
So indeed, this already works.
'Course, some visual feedback would be nice
and we will add it in a second,
but for the moment, it's great that this works.