As a next step,
we can now make sure that an item actually does get deleted.
And for this, in the app component,
in the deleteGoalHandler,
it would be convenient if in this handler function,
we would receive the ID of the to be deleted item.
Because that allows us to uniquely identify
and remove an item.
So here in this function,
we could then set our course goals again,
to update this course goals state.
And now the new state should be based on the old state
where we wanna take the old state, but remove a item,
and therefore we pass a function
to this state updating function.
'Cause that's how we should update state
in React if it's based on the previous state.
So here, I again, get my current course goals
as I did here, when we added a goal
and I return the updated state.
And the updated state which I return is current course goals
which is in Array, dot filter.
Filter is a built-in method in JavaScript,
just as map was built-in method,
which we can call on in Array.
And filter will return a new Array, which is the old Array
minus all the items we filtered out.
Now filter itself takes a function,
which has to return true or false
and if this inner function returns true, an item is kept,
if it returns false, our item is dropped.
Now this inner function is executed by JavaScript
for every item in this array and therefore,
it receives these items as inputs, as parameters.
In my case, these individual goals.
And I wanna return false, if my goal has this ID here.
So I will check if the goal ID,
so this ID property on my goal object
is not equal to the ID I'm receiving here.
This will return true if there is no match,
which is good because I want to keep items
where there is no match, but if there is a match,
if a item has the idea I'm looking to remove,
this will return false because then the IDs are equal
and then this item will be dropped and the new array
will no longer contain it.
That's how we can delete a course goal.
Of course, we have one problem though,
the ID which we expect to get here
is currently not provided.
In goal item, where I'm binding
on the lead item to onpress, onpress won't give me that ID.
Now to make sure that idea is provided,
we could, again, define a little helper function here
as we did it in goal input, where we added addGoalHandler,
where we then manually called the function
and passed our own parameter
and that would be absolutely fine.
But alternatively, we can also call the built in bind method
on the function which we get through that
onDeleteItem prop.
Bind is a standard JavaScript function
which basically allows you pre-configure a function
for future execution.
Now, the first value you pass to bind
sets the this keyword in the to be executed function
and we don't care about that here,
so I'll just set it to this, but it doesn't matter.
The second value, the second argument you pass to bind
will be the first parameter received
by the to be called function.
And in my case, that should be the ID of the goal item
that should be removed.
So here I'll set this to props.id,
so that the ID which I get through props
on this goal item component is sent as a parameter value,
queue the function that we receive
on this onDeleteItem prop
which is this delete goal handler function.
Of course, for this to work, we must make sure
that we do get an ID prop on the goal item component though.
And currently that's not the case
but we can update our code here
and make sure at an ID prop is set on goal item
and that would be itemdata.item.id.
Now there would be other ways of solving this as well,
but this will work and if we save this now
and we tap a item, it is removed.
So now I can add items, multiple items
and I can then tap them to remove them.
By the way, you could also add validation
to make sure that empty items can't be added
but here I will not do that to keep this app a bit simpler.
But with that, we can remove items.
Now what's missing though, is some styling,
some visual feedback.
At the moment, when I tap this item
I get no visual feedback other than its disappearance.
So let's focus on the styling next.