So let's now work on the styling
of this pressable component or of this component
if the item is currently pressed
because at the moment we got no visual feedback.
Now, adding some nice styling here
is fairly easy for Android
because there is a dedicated android_ripple prop
which you you can set to an object
where you can set the color of the ripple effect.
And for example here,
I could set this color to some dark gray
by adding six Ds here, this hex code.
And if I do that, if I set this value
for the android_ripple prop here on Android,
if I add a goal
and I press this,
there is a slight ripple effect.
Let me show this again.
Here,
if I then press this.
You see?
There is this ripple effect around this item.
Now, if you wanna have the ripple effect
inside of that item instead,
what we have to do is move pressable into our view here
like this so that it only surrounds the text
instead of the view box as well.
If we do that and we reload all apps
to make sure these changes get applied.
Now, if we do this again on Android here,
you will see there is a slight ripple effect on the item.
Now, that ripple effect is now only on the text.
Not on the overall container.
And to fix this, what we can do is move our padding
from the goal item which is the view, which is the container
to the text because then the padding is part of the text
and the ripple effect will take this padding
into account as well.
So now with that, if we set this up
we got this ripple effect here.
And of course, you can play around with the ripple color
to get the look you want.
You could, for example, also take this purple color here.
And maybe choose a very dark purple as a color,
and now we have this, which maybe looks a bit nicer.
So, this is pretty easy on Android.
Now on iOS, this doesn't have any effect though.
Here, if I press this and keep it pressed
so that we could see a potential effect,
we don't see any effect at all.
Now for iOS to add some styling,
we can add the style prop to pressable
which generally works like all your style props.
It takes such a styling object
but it also takes a function as an alternative.
And this function will be called automatically by pressable
whenever the press state changes.
You will get a argument here, a parameter,
with information about the current press state
and you can use object destructuring to get hold
of the pressed property that's part of this object you get.
You could also name the overall parameter pressData
and access pressData.pressed in that function.
It's up to you.
Here, I will use object destructuring
to directly get that pressed property.
So, that's provided by pressable.
And now we can return different style objects
based on the pressed state.
We can define them down here of course.
We could have our pressed item here.
And there, we could say
that we wanna set the opacity to 0.5, for example,
to make it slightly transparent.
With that up here, we can check pressed
and if it's true, we return styles.pressedItem.
Otherwise, we return no special styling.
If we save this
and I now do learn react native again,
you'll notice that if I press this
we also get some feedback here on iOS.
Now of course, you could go for all kinds of feedback.
You could also bring this view back
into the pressable component here
and add another surrounding view
so that you can influence the style in greater detail,
and you can, for example, also change the background color.
Whatever you want.
Here, I'll keep this simple feedback
but now we also do have some feedback with help
of this function form of this style property here.