[Maximilian Schwarzmüller] So again.
We made good progress here.
To conclude this section.
I wanna improve the overall look
and feel of this application a little bit though.
And I wanna start by actually outsourcing this input part
into a modal, modals are these overlays.
That typically slide up or pop up,
on mobile apps that overlay the main screen.
And allow you to take some action,
after which they disappear.
Adding such a modal, and adding the input logic here
into such a model,
is thankfully pretty easy in React Native.
Because it comes with a built in modal component.
So, all you have to do in the goal input component,
where I want to create that modal.
Is, you import modal from React Native.
And then you wrap that,
around the content that should go into the modal.
In my case here, that's the view
with the text input and the button.
If you do that, we have this look here.
So our list of goals seems to be gone
and the styling is a bit off.
And as I add goals, I don't see them.
The reason for that is,
that we actually see the modal here.
The overlay, which we have on the entire screen.
Now, of course the modal shouldn't always be there though.
Instead it would be nice to have a button
on the start screen,
that allows us to open the modal
when we want to add a new goal.
And then to have a button that allows us to
close this modal here on this modal screen.
Now let's start with that button
that opens the modal.
For this, I'll go back to App.js,
and I want to add that button there.
We still have the goal input component.
But above that component, I wanna add a button.
And for this I'll use the good old built in button.
Though, of course we could also import "pressable".
And build our own button,
as you learned it a couple of minutes ago.
Because the button here in the end, all it just
uses is the "pressable" component or those old "touchable"
components internally.
But here, to save some time,
I'll use the prebuilt button instead of building my own one.
And I'll give this button a title off, "add new goal".
I'll also give the button a color, through the color prop.
Because "button" doesn't take a style prop.
It doesn't support it.
Because it is already pre-styled.
That's why you can't influence it too much.
If you do want to style your own button, you have to
build your own button with the "pressable" component.
And then some text and views inside of it.
Here, with the pre-built button, we can change the
color through the color prop though.
And I will set color here to,
actually to a string.
And I will use the same purple,
as I used here in goal item.
For the background of my goals.
I'll use this purple color here.
And set this as a color of this button here.
Like this.
So now we have the button.
But of course, we don't see the button if
we save this.
Because we still have the modal everywhere.
Now this button should control the modal visibility.
And for this we need "state",
because the modal should either be visible or not.
And that's a typical case for using "state".
So, here in the app component,
we can add a new piece of "state".
And use, "use state" to initialize it and set it to
false initially,
because that will be my "modal is visible" state
And the "set modal is visible" updating function,
will allow me to change it.
And initially the modal should not be visible.
Now we wanna change this whenever the button is clicked.
So for this, I'll add a "function" here,
maybe here, the exact position doesn't matter.
Which I will name "start at goal handler".
And in this function I want to set,
"set modal is visible" to true.
Because I wanna show the modal.
Now, this "start at goal handler" function,
should now be connected to this button.
And this button,
being a built in component has this on press prop
Which we now use to connect it to "start at goal handler".
Now to show the modal only when this state is true.
We could now render goal input conditionally,
as we would do a it in most React Web Apps.
We can add curly braces around that.
And then check our "modal is visible" state.
And if it's true,
then we render goal input.
Which internally contains this modal.
If we do It like this and we save everything.
Indeed we see the button here.
And if I press the button,
the modal appears
But the model then is just there.
There is no animation and nothing.
And therefore that's typically not,
how you would do that.
Instead of just showing or hiding this component like this.
A better approach is to embrace some of the props, "modal".
This built-in modal component, offers to you.
To be precise, this "modal" component has a "visible" prop.
And if set to "true", the model is visible,
If set to "false", it's not.
Now, this is useful.
Because in addition, modal also has a animation type prop.
Where you can set how it will be animated.
That there maybe is no animation at all.
That it should fade.
Or that it should slide in.
And I will go for sliding.
And now I just expect to get the,
"should it be displayed or not" information, via props.
So here I'll access "props.visible",
though this prop name here is up to you.
It could also be "show modal".
But I'll choose "visible".
And now we have to set this prop on goal input,
in the app component.
So here, I'll now add this "visible" prop.
And set this equal to "modal is visible",
which is true or false.
And with that, if we now saved this.
And we force a reload,
by pressing R here in the terminal.
Now the modal slides up.
Of course we can't dismiss it at the moment.
And the styling in there also is a bit off.
So, therefore let's next focus on that styling.
And let's then make sure that,
we can also close this modal.