So to work on the styling here.
In the end we need to go into the GoalInput component.
There, we have this model
and in the model we have this View.
Which in the end is responsible for controlling how
the textInput and button are displayed.
Now I wanna change the overall look.
I now wanna have the button beneath the textInput
and I wanna have another button
in addition to add goal.
Because that other button should allow us
to close that model.
Now to achieve this I will restructure this a bit.
And I will actually add another View in here,
below the textInput, and move my button into this View.
And add another button here
with a title of Cancel.
So that I can add the goal or cancel adding.
And this should in the future close my model.
at the moment it won't do anything though.
Now with that, we got that View in a View.
But now I wanna change the styles of that outer View,
which is the main View inside the model.
Because it's the first element in the model.
The top most element in the model.
And on this input container, I wanna use flex 1.
So that it takes all the available space in the model.
But I wanna change the flexDirection back to column.
And therefore we can also remove it
because that is the default anyways.
With this, if I save this,
the buttons are now below the textInput.
But they are totally stretched out,
because we have space between for justifyContent.
This should instead be center
to make sure all the content is centered.
This now looks way better.
Now in addition these two buttons
should be next to each other
and therefore I added this View around the buttons.
and I will give this View some styling.
So here, maybe at the bottom,
I'll add my buttonContainer object.
And actually give this a flexDirection of row.
So that the two buttons are next to each other.
And then add this buttonContainer on this View.
So here I'll add a style
which is styles.buttonContainer.
And with that, the buttons do sit next to each other.
Now it would be nice if the buttons had
maybe a fixed width and some spacing between them.
And to achieve this, since I can't style these buttons,
since they're built in
and since I don't wanna build my own button
which we could do but which is some extra work.
I'll actually wrap each button into a View as well.
Because then I can style that View instead of the button.
And therefore still influence the look of the button a bit.
So here I'll assign a style property to those Views here.
And setup a dedicated styling object for those buttons.
I'll name style object button.
And for every button here I'll just make sure
that it takes, lets say, 40% of the available width.
And then we might want to add a marginHorizontal,
So margin left and right, of eight pixels.
So that we have some spacing between the buttons.
And it's now this button style here
which I wanna add to the Views that hold the buttons.
And that's a quick and easy way
of setting my own styles to the buttons
even though I can't change the button style itself.
But you can change the width or height with that,
you can add margins between them.
You wouldn't be able to change the color
or text color though, if that was your plan
you would have to build your own button.
And in general, if you need more adjustments,
you might wanna build your own button
by using the pressable component.
But this is good enough for now
and it gives me these equal sized buttons
below the textInput.
I also wanna have some spacing between
the textInputs and the buttons.
And maybe we can shrink them a little bit.
So to shrink them I'll change the width to 30% here
or we set this to a fixed pixel width of 100 for example,
like this.
And for the spacing between the textInput and the buttons.
On the buttonContainer I will add a marginTop
of let's say, 8 or maybe 16.
So now I save this there is some distance
between the buttons and the textInput above the buttons.
The textInput now also can become wider.
So I will set the width of the textInput to 100%.
And with that, I reloaded the app in between
so I will reopen this, this is now wider.
Now it would still be nice to have some area
around that which is not occupied.
And therefore on the overall container,
Which is that root View in that model,
I will add a little of padding in all directions
and let's say add 16 pixels of padding.
And now I'd say this doesn't look too bad.
Last but not least
we still have some extra spacing to the right
of the textInput,
because we had a margin to right
and I wanna get rid of that as well.
So now this does look quite good.
And of course you can adjust this a bit further
if you want to.
Now I wanna make sure the model closes
whenever we cancel or click add goal though.
Because at the moment that's not happening.