So to close the modal,
whenever we click add goal or cancel,
we have to react to taps on those buttons.
And then in the end,
we have to change the visibility state in the app component
because modal is visible in the end controls
whether the modal is shown or not.
Now we already got a 'StartAddGoalHandler'
which opens the modal.
Now we can add a 'EndAddGoalHandler'
which should set 'ModalIsVisible' to false.
And now we just need to make sure this function
gets called whenever a user taps
on the 'Add Goal' or 'Cancel' buttons.
Now, if a user taps on 'Add Goal',
the 'AddGoalHandler' is triggered
which triggers the function received on the 'onAddGoal' prop
which turns out to be this function.
So in order to close the modal if a goal was added,
we just have to set 'ModalIsVisible' to false here as well
or call the 'endAddGoalHandler' manually here.
Both would work.
Now to also close it,
If we tap the cancel button,
in goal input we have to add 'onPress'
to this button as well,
And then expect that we get a pointer
to this 'endAddGoalHandler'
passed into 'GoalInput' through props.
So here we could expect
that we get a function on a cancel prop.
It's our component, so the prop name is up to you.
Now we just have to make sure that this prop is provided
in app component.
Here we pass the 'onCancel' prop
to the 'GoalInput' component
and point at the end, 'addGoalHandler' function,
so that this function is executed
whenever the cancel button is clicked, or pressed.
With that, if we save this.
Indeed, if I click cancel the modal closes.
And if I add a goal here,
like this, and I click add goal,
it also closes, but the goal is there.
And of course it also works on Android.
Both adding and removing, and opening and closing.