Now to finally finish this app here.
I wanna improve the overall look and feel,
by changing some colors and by adding an image.
Which is something we haven't done yet.
But which is of course, something you will often do.
And you should therefore know how to do.
Now, adding an image, thankfully is easy.
Because React Native has a component for it.
There is an "image" component,
which you can import from React Native.
And just as you have,
the "image" element for the web, in HTML.
This is a component that helps with displaying an image.
This "image" component is used in your JSX Code.
And here I wanna display an image,
right above the text input.
So, I will add my image here.
On this image, you can then add some style.
Which we'll do in a second.
But most importantly, you can also add a "source" prop.
And this should point at the image you want to add.
Now, when it comes to that image,
you do find an example image attached.
And you should download that image
and move it into your "assets" folder.
Or to be precise create an "images" folder
in that "assets" folder.
Because that "assets" folder is generally,
the folder where static assets like images should be stored.
And then move that attached image,
into that "images" folder in the "assets" folder.
And it's this "goal image", which you got attached.
And now when it comes to linking to that image.
It works differently than what you're used to from the web.
We won't create some link here, which points to
"assets/images/goal.png"
at least not quite.
It's not too wrong, but it wouldn't work like this.
If I save this, you see, I get a warning.
I get an error, this doesn't work.
Instead, you have to import the image here
with a special import syntax.
You should use a "require" function.
Which you might know from Node.js,
if you worked with that.
And to that "require" function,
you pass the path to the image.
However, the path is a relative path from the file
in which you're using this "require" function.
So, seen relatively from that goal input file,
which is that file,
where this "required" function gets used.
We have to go up one level,
to leave the "components" folder.
And then dive into images and select the image.
Now to go up one level we type ../,
this means go to the parent folder.
And then we dive into assets, images, goal.png.
This is how we add an image.
Now let's also add some styling to it.
And for this, I'll add an "image styling" object
in my style sheet here.
And here we could set a width of let's say 100 pixels.
And a height of 100 pixels.
And give this a margin of 20 in all directions,
to have some spacing around the image.
As always, you can play around with
the styling, to find your favorite styles.
Now I wanna apply that style to my image.
And thankfully the "image" element,
the "image" Component, does support the style prop.
And we can set "styles.image",
as a value on that style prop.
And with that, if we reload the app by pressing R here
in the terminal.
You will see nothing.
As it seems.
The reason for that is that the image is white.
And we can't see that,
because the background is also white.
That's no problem because,
I wanted to changed the background as well.
And since we're in the modal here.
This background can be changed.
By setting a different background on this input container.
Because that is our root element in the modal.
And it defines the overall modal container look therefore.
The modal itself does support the style prop.
But for styling the overall modal background,
you should use a nested view, as we are doing it here.
And now here on this input container.
We can add a background color.
And I prepared a nice dark purple,
which I'd like to use here.
Which has to hex code 311b6b.
And whilst we're here,
I also wanna change some other styles.
For example, we don't need the border
at the bottom anymore.
Because there is nothing below that.
And that border here looks really strange.
So I will remove that border.
And I will also remove that margin to the bottom
which I have here.
So that these are the remaining styles that I have here.
And with this, now we can see the image.
Because now we got this nice purple background.
Only in the modal though.
We will work on the other background later.
But here in the model, we got that.
Of course, we now also might want to,
tweak the text color here.
When we enter something into this input field.
And we might wanna tweak the buttons here as well.
To make those look a bit prettier as well.
Because currently they don't fit the background.
But most importantly, we did now add the image.
Which was the main task for this lecture.
And as you saw, adding an image is super simple.
With that "image" Component and this way of adding a source.
So let's next improve the overall styling
of those modal elements.
The other elements, I mean.