So for improving the overall look and feel here,
I wanna start by changing the button colors.
For this, we can go to our JSX code
because you learned that for these built in buttons,
you change the colors with the color prop.
And again, I prepared some hex codes,
which I think look quite nice.
And for adding an item here,
I wanna use the code 5E0acc.
And for canceling, I prepared another code,
which is F31282.
If we save this, this is how the buttons look like.
And it looks good on Android, but on iOS,
it's a bit hard to read I would say.
This is a bit hard to read.
So actually, we might wanna tweak this
and pick a slightly lighter purple,
like B180f0,
which I think looks good on iOS as well.
It doesn't look as good on Android,
but for the moment I don't wanna dive
into writing different code for different platforms.
We will do that later in the course,
but for now let's stick to this uniform solution here,
where we have the same code for both platforms.
Of course, feel free to optimize the app
for one of the two platforms.
For example, if you're on windows and you can't test this
on iOS anyways, you can of course choose a prettier color
for this button there.
But we got these buttons now,
let's now work on the text input styling.
And for this, we got this text input styling object here.
In there, I wanna to change the border color a little bit
and choose E4d0ff.
And also give this a background color
which should be the same color.
So I'll just copy that as a background for the text input.
I will now also change the color of the text that's entered
to 120438,
which is another prepared hex code.
Since I added a border,
I also wanna change the border radius,
so that I have some rounded corners with border radius
and set this to six pixels.
And with that, that is how this input looks like.
And I think that doesn't look too bad.
Last but not least, I will ramp up the padding
a little bit though, and change it to 16,
so that we got this padding here.
So that's now how this model looks like.
And I would say it doesn't look too bad.
We can now learn React Native and this app looks quite nice.
I just wanna switch to button order
because I ended a bit more intuitive
if the add button is on the right,
but of course, this comes down to personal preference
and is totally up to you.
But now, this works.
Last but not least,
I also wanna improve the styling of this main screen though.
Because I think that white background color
isn't too pretty.
Here, I prepared a little color for us.
And it has the hex code 1e085a.
Now, if we set it like this, this works
and we got this as a background color.
And this works just fine here.
But if we had multiple screens in this app,
so not just the model, but also other screens,
which we will have later once we add navigation,
then manually setting the background color like this
all the time, can become annoying.
Therefore what you can do when using expo,
is you can go to the app.json file.
And in that file, you can actually also add
a special background color configuration item
and set this to a hex code.
And this will then automatically be applied
as a background color to all screens by expo.
So if I now reload after adding this to app.json
and saving that file, we also got this background color,
but now it's applied by expo to all the main screens,
not to the model, but to all the main screens
that are not overlays.
Here, we only have one screen, so it didn't matter.
But this can be the more convenient approach
if you do have multiple screens.
Of course, like this, I'm not totally happy
with the way this add new goal button looks.
I think it's a bit hard to see on iOS.
Therefore, what I will do is in App.js,
I will change the color of this button.
And we could go for a lighter purple like this.
And I think that looks a bit nicer.
So now with the styling changed,
there's one thing that might become obvious.
The status bar is really difficult to see
on both these devices.
The reason for that is that it's still black,
that it doesn't know that we have a dark background.
Now, thankfully, expo gives us a solution for that.
We can import a special component from expo.
And that component is the status bar.
We can import it from expo-status-bar,
which is a standalone package
which is already part of this project.
This package here.
This is a component which we can use to fine tune
the look of the status bar.
We simply use this status bar as a component,
here in our JSX code, in this root app component.
So here we can add StatusBar.
And since it's now next to another sibling component,
right at the top of the return to JSX code,
I will wrap it with such a fragment,
since you're not allowed to have sibling elements
at the root level of JSX code otherwise.
So we add this wrapping fragment
and add the StatusBar component
next to our root view component.
And on this StatusBar component,
you can now set a style prop, which one's a string though?
And you can now set the status bar to dark or light
or let it infer it automatically.
Now, auto doesn't work here.
So I will set it to light.
And if I do that, the status bar becomes white
and is now way easier to see again.
And that is definitely a tweak we also wanna apply
so that we do have an app that looks good
and that still allows the user to see
crucial phone information like the battery or the time.
But with that, this app is finished now.
Definitely feel free to dive deeper into it
and tweak it and play around with styles,
position things differently, add features,
but for now we're done.
We are of course, going to dive way deeper into React Native
in the next course sections though.