So, that's it for this course section.
We learned a lot about React Native.
We built the first basic application here,
where we can add our course goals,
and whilst building this application,
we learned a lot about building user interfaces
with React Native, in general.
You learned that you must use these
built-in core components, for example.
You are not allowed to use HTML elements
like div's or anything like that.
Instead, you build the entire user interface
and all your custom components
from those built-in components.
But then you can combine them
as you need to, to build your own elements and features.
You also learned how styling works,
that you create such style sheet objects
which hold nested objects,
which you can then assign
to different elements in your JSX code.
In those nested objects, we have CSS-like properties,
which allow us to set margins, paddings, colors,
and all these things.
Now even though it looks a bit like CSS,
or the names are similar, it isn't CSS.
We have no inheritance and in general,
it's just not CSS, it's JavaScript
and under the hood, React Native translates
our style settings to the Native style instructions
for the different platforms.
We, for example, saw that we had problems
assigning rounded corners to these elements on iOS,
whereas it worked without issues on Android
and therefore, its really important
to keep in mind that we have two different platforms
and React Native just does its best
to talk to both platforms
and transform our instructions for them.
Now, what we also of course learned,
is that besides the components and the styling,
we write regular React applications.
We can still use state, we can react to events,
those events are just not called onclick,
but instead onpress.
But then we can react to them, we can change state,
we can output state and we can do all these things
and this part, works exactly as you're used to.
There's nothing special about this.
React Native Plus React is exactly as React Web Plus React
when it comes to managing state and so on.
Now, we saw differences
when it came to outputting lists though.
We did this with a scroll view,
but then we switched to flat list for better performance.
Which is another built-in core component.
And you will see cases like this from time-to-time
throughout the course, where we have a special solution
for the Native platforms for better performance
or a Native look and feel.
But that's it for the basics for now.
In the end it's not too complex,
it's a React app, just with a different target platform,
but of course it is something you must get used to.
Working with those built-in components,
setting up styling like this.
It takes practice to get used to that.
And thankfully we'll have plenty of practice
throughout this course,
because this was just the first real section
and just the first app.
We're going to build way more
and we're going to learn way more
throughout the rest of this course.