- [Maximilian] Now, that's
it for React Native for now.
Before we now really start
diving into React Native
and all its basics,
let me briefly come back to this course
and give you an overview
of what you can expect
from that course.
Right now we're just getting started,
but we're pretty much done
with that and thereafter,
we're going to dive into
all the React Native essentials you need.
In the next course section,
we will dive into the basics,
into how you can build user interfaces
with React Native components,
how you can style your user interfaces,
how you can build powerful
layouts and of course,
we're also going to
practice all these things
by building real apps and thereafter,
we're also going to learn
how we can add navigation,
how we can make sure that users can switch
between different screens
with nice animations,
how you can add drawers or
tabs and things like that.
Now, this also has a
couple of prerequisites
to make sure that you get the
most out of all these concepts
out of all these sections,
and specifically,
you already need JavaScript
and React.js knowledge.
However, this course also comes
with two refresher course sections,
which you find at the end of this course
to which you can jump ahead
if you wanna go through
those refreshers again
before you start diving into
all the React Native sections.
These refreshers don't replace
full courses on these topics,
but they are great if it's been some time
since you last worked
with React for example,
and therefore it's my recommendation
that you take a look at
those refresher sections
if you need them.
Now, after all those React
Native essentials though,
we're also going to dive
into more advanced features
and specifically, we are going to learn
how we can connect
certain key React concepts
with React Native,
for example, how we
can use the context API
or Redux with React Native.
We're going to build
a complete example app
from the ground up to
practice all these things
we learned up to this point.
We will learn how to handle user input
and send HTTP requests and
all these things again,
by building multiple realistic apps.
Last but
not least,
we will dove into many advanced modules as well
where we will focus on user authentication
and learn how we can use
native device features like on device storage,
the camera, locations,
for example, locating the user or showing a map
and we will
also learn how we could add push notifications.
Last but
not least, we will also learn how you can publish
your React Native
apps, so how you can get them into the app stores.
Now, that's the course content.
I also wanna make sure
that you get the most
out of this course though
and the most obvious
recommendation of course,
is that you should watch the videos,
because this is a video on-demand course,
but of course, watching the videos means
that you should watch
them at your own pace.
You can use the video controls
to speed the videos up
or slow them down and you
should take advantage of that
to make sure that you
get the most out of them.
You can also pause videos to
practice something on your own,
even if I don't tell you
to practice something,
definitely do this on your own as well,
and feel free to go back
to the beginning of a video
to re-watch a video or
even an entire section
if something wasn't clear the
first time you watched it,
because that is the huge advantage
of a video on-demand course.
So embrace that advantage.
In addition of course, in this course,
we're going to build a lot of apps.
We're going to write a lot of code
and I recommend that you do code along,
that you don't just watch the videos,
though you can of course
also just do that,
but you will learn more if
you also pause the videos,
if you practice things on
your own, if you code along,
if you try to write the code on your own,
if you maybe even experiment
with the code a little bit
and you write slightly different apps,
you add extra features that I
might not add in the videos.
Do all these things,
because that will ensure
that you get even more out of this course.
Now, when following along
and when coding along,
you will sometimes also get stuck.
You might not be able to reproduce
a certain result I'm showing in the videos
and for those cases or if you wanna,
for example, get the course slides,
you should use the course attachments
that are also provided
as part of this course.
To be precise, in the next
lecture after this one,
you find a link to all
the course resources,
all the code snapshots and so on
and you should use these resources
to compare your code to mine,
to maybe even replace your code with mine
or parts of your code
with mine if you're stuck
to make sure that you can
find plus fix your errors
that you might be facing.
The next lecture also
contains instructions
on how you can use the
provided code resources,
how you can download them,
how you can use them to
compare or replace your code.
Now last but not least, this
also has a Q & A section
which you can use if you're
stuck, if you have questions,
but don't just use this
section to ask questions,
instead also try to help others,
because if you try to help
others, if you reply to others,
you will get way more out of this course,
because when you solve
someone else's problem,
you are challenged to
come up with a solution,
to articulate that solution and
that will actually make sure
that you really get the
most out of this course,
that you have to understand the things
that I teach in this course
and that you fully understand them
instead of just a little bit, for example.
So definitely also use this
Q & A section to help others
and not just to ask for help.
That's my recommendation for this course.
And with all these recommendations,
you will get a lot out of this course,
you will learn React
Native from the ground up
in great detail and therefore,
in the next course section,
it's now time to really dive
into React Native in detail.