So, what exactly is React Native?
Well, as the name applies, it is related to React.js.
And with React.js and React Native,
you can build real React Native based mobile apps
for iOS and Android,
which are real apps you can distribute
through the app stores and apps that can be used
by any user with an iOS or Android device.
Now React.js is a library that's independent
from React Native though.
React.js is a JavaScript library
for building user interfaces.
And it is typically used for web development.
That's also the environment for which it was first created.
But actually, if you worked with React.js,
you might know that there, it's actually another library
the React DOM library that adds the actual web support
because React itself, the library React itself,
without React DOM is platform-agnostic,
which means you can use React
in conjunction with React DOM to build web apps,
but React the library itself, actually does not care
about the underlying platform.
React just gives you tools for managing state,
for building virtual component trees,
and then you need an extra library like React DOM
for translating the result React produced
to an actual platform like the browser.
Now, React Native is basically
an alternative to React DOM, therefore.
React Native gives you a collection
of special react components,
which you can use in your JSX code.
So React Native ships with built-in components you can use.
And those components are then compiled to native UI elements
for the iOS and Android platforms,
and React Native will also take care
about this compilation step.
In addition, React Native
also exposes certain native platform APIs
like using the device camera
so that you can use such features in your JavaScript code
even though you need to tap
into native device APIs for that.
And therefore in the end, React Native is like React DOM.
It just does not target the web, the browser as a platform,
but instead iOS and Android.
And React Native gives you
all the components and the APIs you need to interact
with those platforms and to build apps for those platforms.
That is what React Native is all about.
And therefore, in order to work with React Native,
you also must know React.js
because you will write your code in React.js
and then just use these extra React Native components
and APIs in your React JavaScript code
to produce those native mobile apps
for iOS and Android.