Now, how does React Native work
Under The Hood though?
If you're building a React and React Native app,
then you are typically writing code like this
which should look very familiar,
if you worked with React.js before
maybe, or most likely
for building browser based apps.
This is a React Component
what you see here.
And it's just one way
of writing such a Component.
We could also use the function keyword instead
of defining an arrow function.
And we could also use a class based Component.
But it's code like this,
which you will write
for React Native
and it's code like this
that will be compiled to Real Native App code.
So which will be bundled
into a Real Native App in the end.
Now, if you take a closer look
at the code snippet on the left here,
you will see two Components
two JSX elements in there,
which you don't know
from web development,
the View and the Text element.
These are some of these special Components
that are exposed by React Native,
which will be compiled by React Native.
It is worth noting though,
that it's really just the Views.
Just this JSX code
that is compiled
not the JavaScript logic itself.
I will come back to that in a second.
So the Components,
the JSX elements you use are compiled
to native elements for the respective platforms.
And to make this a bit easier to understand,
take a look at this comparison table here,
here we got a bunch of elements,
as we would use them in the browser
if we would be using react-dom
and then the equivalence
for the native platforms,
and then the Components exposed
by React Native to target those equivalence.
So for example
if you want to display an input element
where users can enter some text,
then when building a web app
we would use the HTML input element
which is available in JSX
when we're using react-dom.
If we would be building a native Android app
with Java or Kotlin
then it would be the built in added text widget
that is provided by Android,
which we need to build.
For iOS
it would be the UITextField element
and with React Native
we would use the built in TextInput Component
which is provided by React Native
and which will then be compiled to added text
for Android or to UITextField for iOS.
So React Native maps and compiles reusable Components
like TextInput or View
or many other Components
about which you will learn throughout the course
to their respective platform equivalents.
That's one of the main jobs
React Native will take care of.
But what about the logic?
I mentioned that those Views
the JSX elements are compiled
to their native equivalence.
But what about the JavaScript code
you write outside of JSX?
What about all these functions?
If statements?
State management?
What about that?
Well, unlike the UI elements,
the logic is not compiled.
The UI elements
which are those Components
exposed by React Native
are compiled as you learned,
but the logic which you write
in JavaScript is actually not compiled
but instead it's running on a JavaScript thread
that's hosted by React Native
in the native app that was built.
So React Native basically
spins up a simple JavaScript process
as part of your native app
that's being built.
And it manages this process for you.
And it allows this process to talk
to the underlying native platform
and therefore your JavaScript code
will run as JavaScript
in the native app that's being built
but it will then talk to the underlying Android
or iOS platform,
through a basic translation bridge.
You could say that is provided
by React Native
as part of your native app.
That's how you can think about this.
And that is it for now.
That's how React Native works
Under The Hood and what it does for you.
You don't need to know more.
You can of course dive
into the official docs
if you do want to learn more
but that is what you should know
in order to work with React Native,
because I believe it's always important
to have a basic understanding of how a tool works.
And this is how React Native works.