- So, I'd say that's enough theory for now.
- Let's get started with React Native and
- let's create a new React Native project.
- And to get started, you can simply
- search for React Native and you should
- find the official web page
- reactnative.dev.
- And on that page, you can then of
- course learn more about React Native
- and it therefore is a great resource to use
- in addition to this course, also to dive
- deeper.
- But you can also use this site to get
- started and to create new React Native
- projects.
- And that is what we'll do here.
- So if you click on get started, you should
- be taken to this setting up the
- development environment page here.
- If you're not, you can visit it manually by
- navigating to it here on the sidebar on
- the left.
- And on this page, you'll find two main
- approaches you can use for creating
- new React Native projects.
- And the approach that is selected by
- default and that's therefore
- recommended also by me is to use a
- tool called Expo and to use its CLI, its
- command line interface to create new
- projects in the end and to manage these
- projects.
- Alternatively, you could also use a tool
- called the React Native CLI, which you
- could also use to create React Native
- projects.
- But as you'll also see in this course, this
- Expo tool simply makes the process of
- creating and managing and building
- React Native apps a lot easier.
- That's why we will also use this approach
- in this course, just as it's essentially
- recommended on the official page here.
- But what's the difference between these
- two approaches?
- Why do we have two approaches?
- We have the Expo CLI and the React
- Native CLI.
- CLI stands for command line interface
- and both tools are tools that exist in
- order to help you create React Native
- projects and run React Native apps on
- testing devices and simulators, as well as
- build React Native apps so that you can
- ship them to the app stores.
- So these are the tools you need to really
- build apps and to get those packages,
- those distributable packages, which you
- can upload to the app stores.
- These two tools are crucial, but you don't
- need to use them both.
- You can use either of the two and one
- tool is enough.
- But why do we have these two tools and
- what's the difference?
- Well, the Expo CLI, or just Expo, as I will
- also call it throughout the course, and
- the company behind this CLI is in the
- end a third-party service that you can
- use, a service that is entirely free.
- You don't have to sign up, you don't have
- to pay for it.
- You can sign up and you can pay.
- They do offer extra paid services, but to
- build React Native apps and to ship
- them, you don't need to pay.
- When using Expo, the CLI and a couple
- of other free tools, which they give you,
- you get a managed app development
- workflow, as I like to call it, which means
- creating projects is easy, writing code is
- a bit easier, tapping into native device
- functionalities like using the device
- camera and so on is easier.
- And in general, when using Expo, the
- Expo CLI and also a couple of other tools
- provided by Expo, writing native apps
- with React Native is more convenient
- than with just the React Native CLI and
- without Expo.
- There is less friction to this process.
- And the best thing is that you can still
- leave this Expo approach and ecosystem
- anytime if you need to.
- If you start by using Expo because it's
- easier to get started with that, and then
- at a later point, you find out that you
- want to switch to just using the React
- Native CLI workflow and not using Expo,
- you can do this anytime.
- That's why it's also the default selection
- to start with Expo because it's easier and
- you can still switch anytime you want to.
- Now why do we have the React Native
- CLI then?
- Well, because it existed before we had
- Expo, because this is the tool provided
- by the React Native team and the
- community around React Native.
- It gives you a bare bone React Native
- development setup, which means you
- will need to do more configuration and
- setup work on your own.
- There are less convenience features and
- if you need to tap into certain native
- device features like using the camera or
- other features, then it is often a bit more
- work when not having Expo around.
- Because as mentioned before, Expo is
- not just about the tool that creates
- projects.
- It will also give you helpful packages and
- tools that you can use when writing
- code that will make your life easier in
- that case as well.
- Now what the pure React Native
- workflow does have though, is that it is
- often a bit easier to integrate with native
- source code.
- So with source code written in Java or
- Objective-C or Swift or Kotlin.
- So if you must mix JavaScript code and
- native device source code, then using
- just the React Native CLI could be
- beneficial.
- But the idea behind React Native is that
- you don't have to do this too often and
- therefore this might not really be an
- advantage.
- And for all these reasons, and especially
- since you can switch anytime if you
- need to, we will use Expo in this course.
- As you will see, it's super easy to get
- started with that and it will make
- building React Native apps much easier.