- So, therefore, back on this official React
- Native website, we can now follow the
- steps described here in the Expo tab to
- create a new Expo-driven React Native
- project.
- But I'll actually not start by running this
- command here.
- Instead, as a first step, you must make
- sure that you have Node.js installed on
- your system.
- And you can visit nodejs.org to
- download the latest LTS version from
- there.
- Node.js is a JavaScript runtime that
- allows you to run JavaScript outside of
- the browser.
- And whilst we won't write any Node.js
- code in this course, this tool, this
- runtime, is in the end used under the
- hood by Expo and it's also required to
- unlock this npx command here, which
- you need to run to create new projects.
- That's why you must make sure that you
- got Node.js installed.
- With it installed, though, you can copy
- this npx create-expo command, which
- will be used to create new Expo-driven
- React Native projects.
- And you can and should then open your
- default system terminal or command
- prompt to run this command, though as
- a first step, you should make sure that
- there you navigate to a place on your
- machine where you want to create this
- new project.
- Once you did that, though, you can run
- npx create-expo to create a new
- Expo-driven React Native app, though I'll
- slightly tweak this command and add
- –template blank here as an option.
- This will ensure that we get a very basic
- project setup, which we can use to really
- start from scratch and learn about all
- these key features step by step.
- If you don't include this option, you'll get
- a more complex starting project, which
- also uses TypeScript by default and
- that's also something I don't wanna do
- here, because not everyone knows
- TypeScript, of course.
- So this option should be included and
- thereafter you specify your project
- name, like rnCourse for React Native
- Course, but this of course is up to you,
- this name.
- And this will then also be the name of a
- folder that will be created for you and it's
- in that folder where this project will be
- setup, once you hit enter.
- Now what's also worth mentioning at
- this point is that regarding Expo, you
- can also find a dedicated website
- provided by the team behind this Expo
- tool, expo.dev.
- And on that website you can of course
- learn more about Expo and also learn
- more about the Expo-related
- commands you can execute in the
- command line and about the features
- offered by Expo, though that is
- something we'll get back to throughout
- this course as we build React Native
- apps and as we also use Expo step by
- step.
- Now this command can take a while to
- finish, that's totally normal, because it
- will go ahead and setup that project and
- install all required dependencies, but at
- some point it will finish and once it is
- finished it typically will also show you
- some commands you could run to
- navigate into this newly created project
- folder and to then run this basic app
- that is created by default in that starting
- project on Android, on iOS or on the
- web, though in this course we'll ignore
- the web part.
- I do have a complete React course
- where I show you in detail how to work
- with React and how to use it to build
- web apps, in this course we'll focus on
- building Android and iOS apps with
- React Native.
- So therefore you could run these
- commands, but we'll not do that just yet.
- Instead as a next step let's open this
- newly created project and let's explore
- how it looks like and which kind of files
- we have in there.