So we created this project, this expert project
before we run it now,
I wanna open the created project
in an editor that allows me to edit the code
in a convenient way.
Now you can use any code editor you want,
My recommendation is Visuals Studio Code,
which is an amazing free code editor,
That's very extensible and fun to use.
You can download it for all platforms.
And I already do have installed it for Mac OS.
Now with vscode installed,
you can open it and you might see a welcome screen.
If you installed it for the first time,
you can simply close that screen.
And then you should see something like this,
where you can open a new folder.
Alternatively, you can always go to the menu file
and find open on Windows,
or open folder on Mac OS still.
And then if you click that,
it will open such a file picker,
where you can now select that project
folder you just created.
So here I'm selecting this RNCOURSE folder
which I created before, and I'll open this in vscode.
So here I got this expo react-native project opened up
and you can of course configure the visuals,
the way vscode looks, however you want.
by going to view appearance, you can hide
or show the sidebar, the status bar at the bottom,
and you can also go to preferences
and then choose a color theme,
that suits your needs.
I'm using the dark plus theme here.
so you can configure this editor however you want
but what was created for us here?
Well, we see actually not too much.
We got two folders, expo-shared and vscode
which we can ignore,
vscode just holds some settings
i configured for this workspace here,
And expo-shared simply just holds
some internally used information.
The assets folder will become important later,
because we can store images there.
For example, the icon of our app
but also images which be used inside our app.
And we got the node modules folder
which holds all the third party packages
that are used under the hood.
We got a package, Json file
which lists all the dependencies
of our project here.
And here For example, we see expo
because expo is not just the command line interface.
It's all so a JavaScript package which we can use,
and which we will use heavily as you see
because it gives us many utility functionalities
that make writing react-native code easier.
But you also see we're using react,
react-dom, react-native, and react-native-web,
though again, that's not the focus of this course.
You could build web apps with react-native
but support is a bit clunky.
And yeah, we're simply not focusing
on that because you could just use react itself.
If you want to do that together with react-dom.
React-dom of course therefore is also just here
because of react-native web.
So that's what we have here.
We also got a couple of script commands
which we could execute with NPM
but overall there's nothing fancy in here.
And you know, these kinds of files
if you worked with react before,
which you should have
because this course assumes
that you have react and JavaScript knowledge.
So that's the package, Json file .
Package-lock is related to that.
And the babbleconfigjs file just configures
how code is trans piled under the hood,
and unless you know what you're doing
you also shouldn't change this file therefore.
Now we do have the app Json file,
which will become important later
because here we can configure some settings
and behaviors of our react-native app.
And this is a file that will be picked up by expo.
When our app is built for preview
or for the actual app stores.
We can set the name here.
We can set some background colors here
and we will come back
to this file occasionally for configuration.
So this is a file, which we have because we're using expo.
And then we got App js.
This is the only real code file we have
in this starter project.
The exact content could change over time
to make sure that we're all on the same page.
I attached my App js file to this lecture
so that you can download it and replace yours with it
so that you have the same code as I have it.
Because we'll build up on this code in the next lectures.
This in here is a regular react component
which uses special components
special js x elements, exposed, bio-react-native.
That's what I mentioned before.
And then we got some styling which could look a bit weird
but I'll come back to how styling works
in react-native apps later.
So for the moment, this is our app code,
and now it would be nice to see this code in action.
For this, we need some device on which we can preview it.