So we got our code opened up here.
We created this project with Expo.
Now it would be nice to preview our app because of course,
whilst we're working on the React Native app,
we want to constantly preview it
so that we can see our changes
and tweak the app as required.
It would basically be nice to have the same kind of workflow
or a comparable workflow
as we have it with the browser and just React
when we're building React Web apps.
There, we can also create a React project
and preview it in the browser.
Now thankfully, since we're using Expo,
previewing our app on a real device is super easy.
You just need an Android device or an iPhone.
In my case, I have an iPhone here,
but the same is true for Android,
and you visit the app store there.
And in the app store, you can search for Expo.
Now, you should find a Expo Go app.
This is an app provided by the company behind the Expo CLI
and this Expo package, which is part of our project here.
So you can now download this app onto your device.
This app is available for the iPhone
and for Android devices.
And once downloaded, you can open it.
Now in here, you can preview your Expo apps
that are built on your local computer.
To do that, you should open up your terminal
or command prompt.
Here, I'm using the one integrated into VS Code.
You can open this by going to terminal here
and opening a new terminal.
And this is the default system terminal integrated here
into your VS Code.
And then in here you can run npm-start.
Now, what this will do,
(device chiming)
is it will actually start the Expo Development Server
which watches and builds our code
and which builds our code,
basically such that we can preview it.
And it also gives us a QR code here.
You can scan this QR code with your Expo app on Android,
not on iOS.
I'll come back to this in a second,
but on Android, you will have a barcode scanner,
a button that allows you to scan this barcode
in your Expo Go app which you downloaded.
In addition, you also should have a browser tab
that opened up where you also find this barcode,
and where you will find log messages printed by Expo
as your app is running.
Now on the iPhone, the scanner is not integrated
into the Expo app.
Instead, there you need to open your camera
and then scan this barcode here or the one in the terminal.
And then once you tap to open the link
that is sent by that barcode, you should click Open,
which opens the Expo Go app.
Then you should grant
any permissions the app might
(device chiming)
be asking for.
And now you see here that the JavaScript bundle
is being built.
So the Expo app is being built.
The React Native app based on Expo is built
and it opens up in this simulator on our real device here.
So in this Expo Go app here.
We can close this info screen.
And now here, we see our app which we're building
on our local machine running on a real device.
Now we can tell that this is our app by changing this text.
If I remove all the text here, and instead I say,
"Hello, World," good old "Hello, World" message,
and I then save this file,
you will see that it basically instantly updates
on your phone as well in this Expo Go app
which we use for previewing.
And this is how simple it is to build
and test those Expo based React Native apps
with the Expo Go app and why it's so recommended
to use this Expo workflow.
It simply makes building
and testing React Native apps much easier.
And this still is a React Native app here.
We're just using Expo to make our life a bit easier.