So, this is how easy it is to get started
with Expo and React Native.
You can easily create an app
and with help of the Expo Go App,
you can easily preview it.
And you might not need more for now.
You can now follow along
and preview your app changes on your real device.
But maybe you don't want use your real device only.
Maybe you also have an iPhone
and you wanna also preview the app on Android
but you don't have an Android device.
For those reasons,
you might want to install a simulator
which is an extra piece of software that runs
on your local machine that simulates an iOS device
or an Android device.
Now, for this, you can search for Android studio,
to download Android studio to get such a piece
of software that allows you to run Android emulators
on your local machine.
On developer.android.com/studio.
You will find a download link that allows you
to download Android studio for your operating system.
And this can be downloaded for Mac Os and Windows.
Now the download can take a while
but make sure you do download and install it in order
to be able to run emulators on your local device.
Now for iOS, it's different.
There you must open the app store on Mac Os
and search for Xcode and download this Xcode tool
which is Apple's developer environment
for building iOS apps.
Unfortunately, this is not available
for Windows or Linux devices.
So if you are on a Windows or a Linux machine,
you can't run iOS simulators through Xcode.
This is a limitation applied by Apple.
So unfortunately on Windows or Linux
you can only build and test for Android.
Actually, you will be able to build real iOS apps as well
through some Cloud build service
about which I'll talk a little bit later
but when it comes to previewing the app on an iPhone
if you don't own a real iPhone
on which you can use the Expo go app
or a Mac Os device on which you can install Xcode
you have to focus on Android instead.
It is what it is.
Now, once you did install Android studio,
you can open it and you should see a welcome screen
that looks something like this and that should have
some more actions button.
And in there you will find a Virtual Device Manager.
You can use this manager to build virtual devices
so to build emulators.
So here I already have an emulator
but you can click on create device to build a new one.
And here you can select from a broad variety of presets
like the pixel five, for example, here.
Click next, then choose an Android version
that will run on this emulator.
And here I'll choose the API 32 version
which is the latest version in my case, click next
keep all the default settings here and click finish.
And now this will create such a new emulator.
And then you can click the play button
to launch this emulator.
And this will now launch this emulator on your device.
So on your Windows or Mac OS or Linux device.
I'll just increase it a little bit here.
So that's now an Android phone
so to say running on our computer.
Of course just a dummy phone, an emulator,
but a real phone when it comes to testing Android apps.
Now I will show you how to run this app
on this emulator in just a second.
First, I wanna show you how it would work
for Xcode and Mac OS.
Which as mentioned only works on Mac OS.
Here in Xcode you wanna open this as well.
You don't have to open a project.
You just need to open Xcode,
and then you should go to the preferences there.
In the preferences make sure you go to locations
and here under command line tools
make sure you have a version selected here.
By default no version is selected
and you should do that then select a version here.
Once this is done, you can close it.
And then we can go back here to our Expo app in Vs Code.
Now I used the terminal to run this NPM start process.
And this process is still running.
You should by the way keep this process running
as long as you are working on your code.
If you quit this process, your code is not watched anymore.
Preview builds are not built anymore
and they are not pushed
to your connected real devices or simulators anymore.
You can always quit this process by pressing control + C
and you can then restart it by running MPM start again.
But as long as your writing code
you should keep it running.
Now in there, we have this QR code
which we could scan to use the Expo go app on a real device
but we can also press A to run it on Android
or I to run it on iOS and it will pick
those running simulators or start a simulator for you.
Nonetheless it doesn't hurt
to already start an Android simulator
as I did it here so that I can then press A.
And now this is opening this on Android.
So this app is now built and previewed
on this Android emulator.
Now, in case you're getting an error
like this that is most likely related
to the emulator you created.
You might wanna create a new emulator
and make sure that you create one
or that you pick a template that has this placed or icon.
Because Expo needs to be able to access this play store.
So the play store must be part
of the emulator in order to download this Expo go app
which is used for previewing onto this emulator.
So use an emulator template that has this icon
then still the latest version, all the defaults
and create this emulator and start that emulator.
So now I'm launching a new emulator based
on this new template here.
And once this finish starting,
we can again restart NPM-Start maybe,
and then press A again to find this emulator,
it will be found automatically by Expo
and then it will install this Expo go app
onto this emulator and open our app there as well.
We get this info screen, which we can close.
We get this debug screen here
which we can use to reload the app, for example
or turn on certain debugging tools.
But I will we'll come back to debugging later.
We can close this for now and see our app here.
So that's Android.
Now for iOS development you should go
to your applications and locate Xcode
and show the package contents off that.
Because in there in contents, developer, applications
you will find this simulator app.
And you can double click on this to start an iOS simulator.
Now, in this case, it's an iPhone 13 simulator.
You can change this by clicking on it and going
to the menu and then under file open simulator
you can choose all kinds of devices.
But I'll go with iPhone 13 here,
and we can all increase this in size
to make that a bit easier to view.
And now we can press I here.
You don't even need to restart NPM start.
You can serve the preview on Android and iOS simultaneously.
So I just served it on Android.
Now I will press I to also started on the iOS simulator
which also should be detected automatically.
And now Expo will also install the Expo go app
on that simulator and open this app
in that Expo go app on our simulator.
So here it's opening up and after a short while
and it only takes that long initially
when this is all first installed and set up,
of course, after a short while we will see
our app preview on this device as well.
Here we go, it's loading up now
and now we see Hello World here as well.
So now we can preview our little application
on a real device as I showed it to you a couple
of minutes ago, and on those simulators like this.
And this process here should always stay up
and running as long as your writing code.
So we'll just make it smaller.
And now we can change our code
add a couple of exclamation marks.
And if we save this file,
this is automatically picked up and reloaded
on those apps without us doing anything.
You can still manually reload it though by pressing R
in this running terminal here
this will then manually reload those apps.
And that's the development environment
we will use for Discourse.
This is now what we need to dive deeper into React Native.
And Discourse here.